Natsu
me
Yuu
jin
chou
Natsume Yuujinchou
Just why are you crying? I don't understand at all
kimi ga doushite naite iru no ka boku ni wa nani mo wakaranai
I can't just thoughtlessly tell you that I "do understand"
"wakaru yo" nante kotoba karugarushiku kuchi ni dekinai
So please tell me why you are in pain
dakara oshiete kimi ga kurushimu wake o
I want to try my best to do for you whatever I can
boku ni dekiru seiippai no koto kimi ni shite agetai kara
To you, living in this moment, I'll send my song
ima, toki o ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
To you, trying your hardest to live on, I'll send this song
seiippai ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
You've been through so much up to today,
kyou made konna ni kurushinda kara
but you'll definitely have a happy tomorrow
ashita kara wa tanoshiku sugoseru yo kitto
So please, don't keep suffering alone
dakara kimi yo hitori de kurushimanaide
See?
It's because you keep focusing on your rook.
That leaves you open diagonally, so...
Oh, I see.
The match is over now.
That's why you-
Natsume?
The Other Side Of The Glass
The  Other Side Of The Glass
Check.
Wait, that was...
You're the one who said "no take backs."
You're not as good at this as I thought you were, Kitamoto.
Shut up.
Don't be a brat.
This is the first time you've won.
Okay, now how about that grilled corn on the cob you promised?
Maybe I'll have a candy apple instead.
Why do I owe you anything?
Natsume, how'd it go?
Natsume's the one who won, right?
Oh, I won.
Thanks to you.
Natsume, do you mean Tanuma coached you?
Yeah. Just a little.
You should come with us.
Kitamoto's gonna treat us.
Who decided that?!
I didn't know they had a festival this time of year.
A tiny one.
They're celebrating something called Omibashira-sama, right?
No, Omibashira-sama's the one they do on the mountain.
Here you go. Two fresh ears.
Here's your coaching fee.
Thanks.
You buy your own.
You're so stingy!
He's revived.
Really?
Then we must hurry...
What are these voices?
And this presence...
Take this.
What is this?
Hey, what are you doing?
That's a human.
My mistake.
But it's rare for a human
to have such strong spiritual powers.
Excellent.
Let's take him back with us.
Wait, I'm...
Hey, Natsume!
Natsume!
Where are you?
Natsume, are you okay?
Natsume, what's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
Yeah, just a bit lightheaded.
Sorry, Kitamoto.
After you were nice enough to buy this for me.
Forget it.
If you're not feeling well, let's go home.
Natsume?
Tanuma.
Did you...
It's nothing.
Did something happen?
Oh, nah.
No, it's nothing.
Thank you.
Sorry.
Let's go.
Warm, fun days.
But that means that, lately,
I'm back.
the littlest thing
Welcome back.
makes it seem like it could all disappear.
I'm back.
Nyanko-sensei?
He's out again?
He left the window open, too.
I thought if I asked him about that flyer,
he might know something.
A bottle?
What?
Where'd that come from?
A youkai threw it?
I'm back!
That festival was great.
Natsume's still out?
He keeps wandering around...
Whatever.
I'll have a drink while I wait.
Sensei!
Did I imagine that?
Nyanko-sensei!
Is that you, Natsume?
Where are you?
Here! Right here!
Nyanko-sensei!
Here?
Natsume turned into Natsume sake!
No, here!
What happened here?
I was sucked into this.
Open it!
It looks like a youkai bottle.
It's stuck!
Just a second.
It's tougher than it looks.
Stop!
What about this?
Don't!
You'll crush me, too!
Well?
It's hot, Sensei.
Nothing's working!
No!
I like it. It keeps you from wandering around.
Well, I hate it!
At this rate, the humans are gonna call the police,
and it'll be a big deal!
This bottle can only be opened by its owner, it seems.
If I try to force it open,
it could put your life in danger.
Where's the owner, then?
Hell if I know!
We'll have to search for him.
Search for him?
But what do I do until then?
And Tohko-san knows I'm back!
At this rate...
Takashi-kun!
It's almost time for dinner.
Right.
I would guess that humans can't hear you right now.
Or see you.
No...
Then...
[ Pieces of paper: Run away, Kidnapping, Accident, Disappearance ]
They're having pork cutlets tonight.
You owe me big for this, Natsume.
This isn't normally something I'm good at,
but a powerful youkai like me can...
W-What are you going to do?
What do you think?
What do I think?
I've never made that pose before,
so I don't really know,
but it's kind of creepy.
Let me see...
Perfect!
Is that what I look like?
Takashi-kun!
Dinner's getting cold!
Right!
I'll be right there!
Don't get so excited over dinner, Sensei!
Here I am.
Oh, my.
Where did you get that bottle?
Don't worry your little head about it.
I mean, don't worry about it.
She really can't see me?
Will you get Shigeru-san a beer from the fridge?
Right away.
You don't need to talk like that!
You sound like a kid!
No, Sensei!
Absolutely not!
Oh, my. You must've been hungry.
He's still growing up.
Awesome!
I mean, this is good.
Stop gulping it down.
Sensei...
It's a shame that there's no sake to go with the meal,
but it's a hundred times better
than what I usually get.
Don't make things any worse!
Seconds.
No seconds!
Oh, my, that's rare.
Oh, and tomorrow we'll be a little late coming home.
Will ya?
Will you!
Will you?
We just got a call...
an old acquaintance of ours passed away,
and we'll be helping with the funeral.
Here you go.
Wait, Sensei!
Wait for them to finish talking!
I'll make some gratin for tomorrow night's dinner.
Warm it up and eat it.
Yes.
Okay.
That was delicious.
I guess we're lucky that they'll be home late tomorrow.
I've gotta get out of here before then.
When will that gratin be ready tomorrow?
Do something about me
before you worry about the gratin.
At this rate, I can't go to the bathroom or eat...
You hungry?
No, not particularly.
I thought so.
There's no air holes in that bottle either.
The inside of that bottle
is probably connected to the youkai world.
Youkai don't get hungry?
Some don't have to eat unless they realize they're hungry.
They're fundamentally different from humans.
It's late.
Sleep.
But...
Don't worry.
I've got a plan.
But still...
Can he really find the owner of the bottle?
We don't even know what kind of youkai it is.
What's that sound?
Oh, good.
It got him.
Let's take him back.
He's the youkai from the festival.
Sensei!
I knew it.
I thought somebody would come to take it.
What?
The one in the bottle is my prey.
Let him out now.
This is a present for Omibashira-sama.
Don't interfere, beast!
Omibashira?
Let him out now.
He's fast.
You saved me, Nyanko-sensei.
Didn't get you out of the bottle, though.
That youkai was talking about Omibashira-sama.
What about it?
Nishimura and the others were talking about it at the festival.
They said it had something to do with the mountain...
The mountain?
Which mountain?
And what does it have to do with it?
I didn't get that much information.
Why didn't you ask?!
If you ask them, they'd probably know.
Come to think of it, they gave you something
called a "boxed lunch" when you went to school.
I'll do it in exchange for that.
Is this really okay?
Natsume Yuujinchou
What do you think?
We'll be late, Sensei.
Fried chicken, huh?
Don't eat it until lunch.
We'll be leaving around noon, too.
When you come home, make sure you eat
and lock the doors.
Gotcha.
I mean, yes.
Okay, goodbye.
Lunch, lunch, I get a boxed lunch.
So many people all wearing the same outfits.
Forget that.
You just need to say hi.
Nothing more than that.
Just ask Nishimura what you need to,
and then we go home.
I get it.
Morning.
That's a big yawn.
Nishimura.
Come here for a sec.
Stop standing there.
Just get over here.
Okay...
Sensei!
Tone it down!
And smile!
Damn, you're annoying.
Natsume, are you mad...
Wait a second.
Okay!
There's something I want to ask you.
Come here.
Natsume, you wanna go to the nurse's office?
What a pain.
Sensei, politely!
Be polite!
Omibashira?
Yup.
Where is it?
The mountain.
Where on the mountain?
Tell me what you know about it.
Dunno.
I really don't know the details.
Is he an idiot?
I told you not to say anything you don't have to!
Kitamoto might know.
Year 2
Class 1
Omibashira?
Yeah.
Tell me what you know about it.
Dunno.
Sensei, calm down!
I really don't know the details.
But the girls were saying that there's something
called Omibashira on the mountain.
Which one of the girls might know?
Which among the girls would know?
Among?
Stop worrying about the details.
I'm very upset now.
Sorry.
I think Sasada might.
She likes things like that.
Sasada?
Sensei, you've met her a lot of times.
Oh, her.
Sensei, calm down.
Don't do anything that will stand out!
Sasada.
Is Sasada Jun here?
Jun-chan went to the library to return a book.
She returned the book
and went to the science room to get some papers.
She went to the teacher's office to hand in those papers.
We'll by using those papers in the third years' class,
so I had her take them there.
She went back to her class.
Natsume-kun!
They said you were looking for me?
Sensei, politely!
Gently!
What's wrong?
Oh yeah... I saw a cat almost as ugly as yours today!
It was so fat...
I need to talk to you.
Now?
Now.
Wait!
Um...
Everybody in the class was watching...
Sensei, stop!
Let go of her hand!
I need to know right now.
What is Omibashira?
What's wrong, Sensei?
Um... Natsume-kun?
You...
smell delicious.
Sensei!!
What does that mean?
Does "delicious" mean that...
That was yummy.
Even if I go back to normal,
how am I supposed to explain this?
More importantly, we need to talk about Omibashira.
You were just eating lunch!
Sasada said there's a legend
that somewhere on this mountain
there's a shrine sealing something called "Omibashira."
And people said that the shrine was a stone
that was destroyed during recent construction.
So then, a youkai that was sealed away has revived?
Probably.
That's...
"Omibashira-sama has revived.
Any who are weak
and seek his protection are to come bearing an offering."
If the youkai are all talking about it,
then, once his power returns, he must be fairly strong.
We should stay away from him.
Then what happens to me?
That bottle doesn't belong to Omibashira.
It's Onizaru.
If we can find him...
Oh, there you are.
Tanuma.
What's wrong with you?
Nishimura and Kitamoto said
you were like a totally different person.
Nothing.
What's that bottle?
I'm not feeling well today, so I'm going home.
Bye, Tanuma.
Natsume?
You should stay away from the mountain, too.
Wait, Natsume.
What's in that bottle?
I suppose...
there's something very interesting in it.
Interesting?
You might not be able to see it, though.
You're not Natsume, are you?
What are you talking about?
Something's wrong with you, Tanuma.
Who are you?
Natsume wouldn't say that.
Where's Natsume?
Tanuma...
Are you a youkai?
Who are you?
Jeez...
I was just giving you a warning.
The sharp ones are always trouble.
Do you really want to know who I am?
No, Sensei!
Ponta!
You middle-aged cat!
Why did you get Tanuma involved?!
I didn't get him involved!
He involved himself!
Because you led him on!
What?
This only got complicated because you
kept making a mess of things!
I'm going to roll you!
Roll, roll, roll!
It just looks like a cat playing with an empty bottle.
Is Natsume really in there?
Yeah.
It's no good. I can't see him.
I bet not.
By the way, he looks really pissed right now.
Is he mad?
I'm sure I don't need to tell you why.
Well, yeah.
But I can't hear what he's saying right now,
so it's up to me whether I help him or not.
Natsume'd do the same, if it happened to me.
No, Tanuma!
Don't!
If you want to complain,
you can do it when you get out of that bottle.
The more someone cares for me, the more scared I get.
Scared that someday. something terrible will happen.
Anyway, Nyannyan-sensei sure made a mess of things.
Sasada was passed out at her desk.
It didn't work because Natsume kept distracting me.
So what do we do?
We capture the bottle's owner, Onizaru.
We can just wait, and he'll-
Something's wrong here.
Is something here?
There you are!
Wait!
What? Is something here?
Tanuma, that's enough!
Stop!
Onizaru is after the bottle!
You need to leave it behind and go!
What is this presence?
Tanuma!
Tanuma, behind you!
What was that?
I got dizzy all of a sudden!
Natsume?
Natsume, where are you?
Natsume!
No way!
Can I feel anything?
I should be able to feel something...
This way!
Natsume!
This is...
What is this place?
There weren't any
stone steps like this behind the school.
I can see them.
The youkai?
Why?
As you stood smiling,
hohodenda ushirosugata ni
I, behind you, was holding back my tears
nakisou na kao wo kakushiteta
My chest was hurting from all the kindness,
yasashisa de mune ga itakute
and the days were so lovely and precious
konna ni hibi ga itooshikute
To the sound of the wind, to the night's darkness,
kaze no ne ni yuuyami ni
I nostalgically remember you
natsukashii kimi wo omoidasu
"We will always be together forever"
"itsumademo issho dayo" to
I kept repeating this impossible wish
kanawanu koto kurikaeshi
With warmth in my hands,
nukumori wa kono te ni
I am now living with bright colors
azayaka na mama ikite iru
I do not want to forget,
wasuretakunai mono
the love I received that changes the future
uketotta ai wo mirai ni kaenagara
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Gap Between
Humans and Youkai
Tanuma, don't do anything stupid!
If something happens to you...
I have to save Natsume.
I got Tanuma caught up in this.
The window won't open!
Am I locked in?
I sense a strange presence.
This might get bad!