Natsu
me
Yuu
jin
chou
Natsume Yuujinchou
Just why are you crying? I don't understand at all
kimi ga doushite naite iru no ka boku ni wa nani mo wakaranai
I can't just thoughtlessly tell you that I "do understand"
"wakaru yo" nante kotoba karugarushiku kuchi ni dekinai
So please tell me why you are in pain
dakara oshiete kimi ga kurushimu wake o
I want to try my best to do for you whatever I can
boku ni dekiru seiippai no koto kimi ni shite agetai kara
To you, living in this moment, I'll send my song
ima, toki o ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
To you, trying your hardest to live on, I'll send this song
seiippai ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
You've been through so much up to today,
kyou made konna ni kurushinda kara
but you'll definitely have a happy tomorrow
ashita kara wa tanoshiku sugoseru yo kitto
So please, don't keep suffering alone
dakara kimi yo hitori de kurushimanaide
Natsume!
Hey, Natsume!
I have to go home.
I have to go home...
He let a wimp like that get inside him...
If I do something stupid, it could destroy his mind.
Wake up!
Natsume!
I hear Sensei's voice.
I have to go home.
But to which home?
To where?
Why's he just wandering around?
Is Natsume lost?
Miyoko's family's taking him in, right?
He probably doesn't know the way home yet.
He must be dumb!
But I'm too scared to go home.
There are monsters everywhere I go.
I've been here a long time.
He's going back!
You going back to school?
Can no one else see them?
All these scary things...
Huh? Um...
I'm really lost.
A shrine?
Out here?
It's quiet.
This is great.
I can run here whenever the monsters chase me.
I can make it a secret base.
A quiet place, just for me,
where nobody else will come.
A Long Way Home
I'm done.
What's wrong, Miyoko?
You barely ate.
Clean your plate.
But...
I don't want to eat.
I'm leaving.
Hey, Miyoko!
Hey, Miyoko.
Make sure you go to school with Takashi-kun.
I'm going with Nao-chan!
That girl...
Takashi-kun, don't worry about it.
Eat up.
Okay.
I smell something good.
[ Signs: Udon ]
That looks great.
I want to try it someday.
Hey, it's Natsume.
What's he doing?
Hey, it's Miyoko.
Hey, Miyoko!
I heard you're living with Natsume!
That's naughty!
So naughty!
Hey, stop!
Naughty! Naughty!
I hate you!
Miyoko!
Scary!
I have to apologize.
She didn't do anything, and I...
It's my fault for coming to this house.
I'm done.
You're still not eating?
Miyoko, what's wrong? Really?
Um... I...
I'm done.
Miyoko!
Daddy!
Why did he come here?
Miyoko, wanna talk with Daddy until bedtime?
Then tomorrow you can go to school with Takashi-kun.
Miyoko's still upset, so we're letting her sleep in our room tonight.
Will you be okay, Takashi-kun?
Yeah.
Okay. Good night.
Can I take a look?
Just for today?
Dad... Mom...
No, I can't.
I can't look at this.
It just hurts.
I can't read it.
I'm all right.
I'm not lonely.
They're gone, but I'm sure they're...
Bye.
Walk farther behind me.
Hey, where's your house?
Your real house.
My real house?
The house where your parents lived!
Don't you remember your mom and dad?
I don't remember my mom.
And your dad?
My dad either... but...
He was really, really nice!
I'm sure he was.
You're weird.
How can you say that when you don't remember him?
How dare you talk like that?
My dad's much, much nicer!
My real home...
You're weird!
How can you say that when you don't remember him?
If I went to my real home,
I might be able to remember more about my dad.
But...
If I remembered a lot, and it hurt a lot...
Your house?
Oh, the Natsume place?
I think Tachibana-san gave us
a piece of paper with the address on it.
Here it is.
But why?
Umm... I wanted to keep it as a good luck charm.
This piece of paper?
Oh, it's not that far.
Shiromachi is just west down the Shirokawa River a ways.
Oh, another tiny monster.
What is that?
I'll eat it for you.
This is...
She didn't eat her food again.
She's a bad girl.
I'll eat her for you.
What are you talking about?
Don't do it!
Get lost!
Scary, scary...
Go someplace far away!
You can't cause trouble for people.
You can't!
Shiromachi.
Just west down the Shirokawa River a ways.
Natsume Yuujinchou
What do I do?
What time is it?
I have to go home.
I'll cause problems for them again.
I'm all right.
Thunder isn't scary.
I have to go.
I have to hurry!
Hello!
Hello?
There he is!
I'm so sorry.
We're sorry for the trouble.
No, I'm glad we found him.
Poor kid was terrified.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Takashi-kun.
You can go inside.
I'm going to apologize to everyone.
Go eat dinner with Miyoko.
I'm so sorry.
No, not at all.
I'm sorry... I'm sorry.
Why do my parents have to apologize?
Why do they have to have people get mad at them?
You're the one who's weird!
Get out of here!
Just leave!
Leave, please...
Shiromachi.
Just west down the Shirokawa river...
My home's there.
I'll go home.
I'll go home... to my real home.
That empty home...
Dad...
Dad... Dad... Dad...
I called his name again and again.
And I learned that each time, nothing called back.
I learned that no matter how much you want something,
how many times you scream for it, sometimes it's out of your reach.
I never did make it there.
I got lost, and ran out of energy.
I decided to stop calling out for someone
who would never call back.
Sad memories you want to forget.
I'll eat them for you.
Draw a mouth.
No.
They're a part of what makes me who I am.
No matter how much they hurt, they're important to me.
Let me eat them.
Your memories and your heart.
Let me eat them all.
Natsume!
I hear a voice.
Takashi-kun.
Tohko-san.
Natsume!
We'll be here when you get back, Takashi-kun.
That's right,
I'm going home!
You did it.
I destroyed his spiritual energy.
He's just a harmless bug now.
Thank you, Sensei.
Did you call me?
Did you see my memories?
I'm not interested in your memories.
I'm only staying with you until I get the Book of Friends.
Shiromachi...
Straight west down the Shirokawa River.
Natsume
I'm home.
Did I draw this?
I must've been a mischievous kid.
My Dad kept it, even though I drew it in a place like this.
So, well?
Remember anything about your life here?
No, I forgot most of it.
So many... so many important things I've forgotten.
Sensei, somewhere in this yard
my mom planted some flowers, my Dad said.
I wonder where they are.
It's too late to tell.
Takashi...
I hope they bloom this year.
I hope they bloom every year.
Takashi...
Bye, Dad.
Goodbye, my home.
Now let's go home.
After that, I felt really tired,
so I just went straight home.
We didn't get to eat that udon,
but for once, Sensei didn't get mad.
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Welcome home, Takashi.
I'm home.
Huh?
Again?
Which way is it?
I think we're almost there.
This is the third time!
Natsume-sama!
See you later!
Later! Later!
Soda water! Soda water!
Hey, I've got a feeling that it's this way.
Shuu Natori
Thanks for this!
How was it?
I loved it!
Sasada!
Taki-san!
You finally made it.
Took you a while.
How'd you get here ahead of us?
We looked it up!
Natsume said you were going today, so I waited!
Is this where the soda water spring is?
What?
It's red!
Of course it is.
It's rusted.
It's fine. You won't get sick unless you've got bad luck.
Then you drink first, Nishimura.
Rock paper scissors!
We can do rock paper scissors!
There were sad days, and painful ones,
and there may be more.
Even so...
Okay, ready? Here we go.
Come on, Takashi. Get closer.
Come on, smile! Takashi-kun!
Let's see how it turned out.
I can't wait!
Tonight it's the croquette blues...
Shigeru-san, Tohko-san,
can we take another?
Stay still, Nyangoro.
Treasured days,
that I'll never forget.
As you stood smiling,
hohodenda ushirosugata ni
I, behind you, was holding back my tears
nakisou na kao wo kakushiteta
My chest was hurting from all the kindness,
yasashisa de mune ga itakute
and the days were so lovely and precious
konna ni hibi ga itooshikute
To the sound of the wind, to the night's darkness,
kaze no ne ni yuuyami ni
I nostalgically remember you
natsukashii kimi wo omoidasu
"We will always be together forever"
"itsumademo issho dayo" to
I kept repeating this impossible wish
kanawanu koto kurikaeshi
With warmth in my hands,
nukumori wa kono te ni
I am now living with bright colors
azayaka na mama ikite iru
I do not want to forget,
wasuretakunai mono
the love I received that changes the future
uketotta ai wo mirai ni kaenagara