Natsu
me
Yuu
jin
chou
Natsume Yuujinchou
Just why are you crying? I don't understand at all
kimi ga doushite naite iru no ka boku ni wa nani mo wakaranai
I can't just thoughtlessly tell you that I "do understand"
"wakaru yo" nante kotoba karugarushiku kuchi ni dekinai
So please tell me why you are in pain
dakara oshiete kimi ga kurushimu wake o
I want to try my best to do for you whatever I can
boku ni dekiru seiippai no koto kimi ni shite agetai kara
To you, living in this moment, I'll send my song
ima, toki o ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
To you, trying your hardest to live on, I'll send this song
seiippai ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
You've been through so much up to today,
kyou made konna ni kurushinda kara
but you'll definitely have a happy tomorrow
ashita kara wa tanoshiku sugoseru yo kitto
So please, don't keep suffering alone
dakara kimi yo hitori de kurushimanaide
I'm back.
Welcome back, Takashi.
Shigeru-san, is that...
I found this old camera when I was cleaning.
I was testing whether it still worked...
It's making a weird sound.
The film must've jammed.
I only used this when I went on trips with Tohko-san.
It's been gathering dust for ages.
Maybe I'll have it repaired.
Once it's fixed, let's all take a photo together.
Sure.
A photo, huh?
A Single Photo
Thanks for going shopping for me, Takashi-kun.
I made some iced tea. Take some up with you.
Thanks.
I'm back, Nyanko-sensei.
Welcome back!
Welcome back, Natsume-sama.
Welcome back! Welcome back!
Don't welcome me back!
I told you not to come in without asking!
Where's Sensei?
Hey, Nyanko-sensei!
An acquaintance said their name is written in the Book of Friends,
so we brought them here.
Hello.
You who protect me, show your name.
Stare...
Don't stare! It's creepy!
He's so cute when he's angry!
Thank you, Natsume-sama.
I'm tired.
Such a wimp.
You sure you're Reiko's grandson?
Her grandson, huh?
So Reiko had a family...
A family...
I wonder.
You gave back another name, didn't you?
What are you doing to my Book of Friends?
My grandmother kept the name "Natsume" her whole life.
I never dared ask any of the relatives I was staying with...
I was scared to hear them say something bad about her,
or tell me how lonely she was.
What's wrong, Natsume?
You're all pale.
You guys kept me up all night.
Takashi-kun, it's time for breakfast!
Okay.
It wouldn't bother me now.
Good morning.
Good morning, Takashi.
Because of these people I've met,
Good morning, Takashi-kun.
I'm sure it wouldn't bother me anymore.
I can just forget all the pain now.
Let's eat.
What are you looking for, Natsume?
Here it is.
It was in this.
What is this?
This is a picture of my parents.
I didn't know you had one.
I think it's okay for me to look at it now.
Takashi-kun!
Your friends are here!
Okay!
Takashi's Things
Soda water?
You mean like pop?
That's right.
Kitamoto said he knows a place
where soda water flows naturally.
What do you think, Natsume?
You're from the city, so you don't believe me, do you?
A soda spring?
I know two sake springs...
Sake?
I dream of that sometimes.
Weird dreams.
So, how about it?
Why don't you come with me tomorrow,
and see if it's true or not?
To the soda water spring!
I want to go.
Me, too.
Right, that settles it.
Nishimura will be here, too.
He said he'll be here later because he's got cram school.
Nishimura does?
Weird for Nishimura, huh?
Let's scare him.
Hide somewhere.
Hide?
Why?
Oh, come on, why not?
Okay, I'll hide here.
Coming!
Yes, this is the Fujiwara's.
He won't find me here!
Takashi-kun, excuse me.
Do you have a second?
Yeah, sure.
I got a call from Tachibana-san.
He says he needs to talk to you directly.
I'll go.
Um, Tohko-san.
Who's Tachibana-san?
He's a relative. Takashi lived with her when she was young.
He cares for the house Takashi and his parents
lived in when he was little.
Yes.
Yes... I'm doing well.
Is something wrong?
The house?
Yes, I think we've finally found a buyer.
What do you think, Takashi?
That house isn't doing you any good, is it?
You're doing well there, right?
Yes.
That's right.
It's not something I can do anything about.
Yes.
I'd imagine you barely remember it,
but I thought I should contact you.
So I can go ahead with this, right?
Yes.
You'll still be able to visit for another two weeks.
If you want, you can look around before it's sold.
Tohko-san?
What did Tachibana-san want?
It was about my house.
It's a small house, but it's been abandoned for years.
He said he finally found a buyer.
It's fine.
He's going to handle all of it.
Oh, my... but...
It's all right.
Hello!
It's Nishimura.
You're late.
Sorry.
I heard you're going to cram school?
Here I am!
Where's Kitamoto?
What is this?
Are you a little kid?
But Natsume, what's that?
In the back of the closet.
What is it?
You don't have to look.
Hey, Nishimura!
Now I'm curious.
You, too, Tanuma?
Nice, Tanuma.
H-Hey!
Stop it!
What is it?
Stop! Wait! Wait, I said!
What are these?
What?
What are they doing there?
Well, you know.
If I put them up somewhere people could see them,
it'd be embarrassing.
Yeah, but does that mean you should put them up in the closet?
Forget about it.
What are we doing tomorrow?
What about the soda water?
We're going to see the soda water?
Yeah.
Is it real?
You still doubt it?
Well, look forward to it.
It comes bubbling out of the ground like this.
Bring a canteen.
And eat lunch first.
We meet here at 1 o'clock.
Yeah.
Okay, 1 o'clock.
Don't be late.
Bye!
See you tomorrow at 1 o'clock!
Tomorrow sounds like fun. Won't it, Sensei?
You sure about your house?
Relatives of the Spotted Butterfly
Relatives of the White Butterfly
Relatives of the Helmet Bug
Relatives of the Spotted Butterfly
I am, Sensei.
The most important place to me right now is here.
Besides, it costs money to maintain it.
I've forgotten almost everything that happened there.
So, you do remember some of it.
I don't remember my mom, since she died right after I was born,
but I remember a little about my dad.
He raised me on his own.
It was only a few years, though.
He would pat me on the head,
or put me on his knees,
and we'd sit on the porch for hours...
Remembering it hurt,
so I tried as hard as I could to forget.
Then, sooner or later, I did.
So I'm okay now.
I couldn't bear to look at this picture, you know?
Now I can.
It's fine.
There are things you can't have no matter how much you want them.
So it's easier to just forget about them, Sensei.
Right?
Natsume Yuujinchou
Where is it?
Where's my house?
I don't know.
I can't go home.
I forgot.
I tried so hard not to, and I still forgot where I live.
Takashi-kun, your friends are here.
Right!
Hey, Sensei, wake up.
We're leaving.
Bye, Takashi-kun.
See you later.
Hey, guys.
There he is.
Let's get going.
Yeah.
It's hot today.
Hey, is this really the way?
According to the map I made when I was a kid, it's this way.
Goal
Haunted House
Here it is
Scary big tree
Wild Dog! Careful!
Old lady's
ramen shop
This is a map?
First, which ways are north and south.
Don't worry about the details.
If we just got there by following the map, it wouldn't be an adventure.
Details?
I told you it'd be easier to get there from the road.
But just going straight there on our bikes isn't an adventure.
What?
We could've taken our bikes?
Shaddup.
You need more stamina, Natsume.
So do you, Tanuma!
Right, right.
Anyway, let's just keep going.
It's fun to get lost, too.
That house isn't doing you any good, is it?
Natsume?
About yesterday...
No...
You know, when I was a kid,
I made a secret base in my closet.
That again?
I put what I cared about in the closet, too.
It reminded me of that.
Hey, which way is it?
I dunno.
You wrote it!
Wait, wait. Gimme a second.
Do you think we'll ever get there?
The map. Look at the map.
Takashi...
Takashi, look at that.
See?
It's right over there.
Your mom planted seeds.
She was so happy to have a garden.
She secretly planted the seeds to make us happy.
I hope they bloom again this year, Takashi.
No.
I can't remember it.
I can't go back there.
It's empty now.
It's okay.
It doesn't hurt.
Forget.
Oww...
I thought I smelled something delicious.
It's a human!
Wait!
I can't believe I found such a feast all the way out here!
Delicious!
Jeez.
Begone!
Sensei.
You idiot, what's wrong with you?
You could've knocked that guy's lights out.
Sorry.
What's your problem?
Yeah...
I let my guard down.
It's because I was looking at this picture.
The picture's gone!
What?
It's gone.
When did I drop it?
You don't know when you dropped it?
It's gonna be impossible to find in the middle of the forest.
Natsume!
Where'd you go, Natsume?
Oh, there he is.
What happened, Natsume?
You trip?
I'm glad.
You okay, Natsume?
I found the path.
Let's go.
Yeah.
You scared me when you just vanished.
Sorry, sorry.
You're a mess.
Right.
Natsume's got it tough.
More youkai stuff, Sensei?
Nope, he lost a photo.
A picture of his parents.
You sure about this?
I think it was that tree...
What did you drop?
Tanuma...
Nishimura. Kitamoto.
It looks like Natsume dropped something.
Help me look for it.
You dropped something?
No...
You idiot, why didn't you say so?
We were about to leave.
It's fine, really.
I can come look for it later.
Natsume!
I can tell you're lying by the look on your face!
Come on, Natsume.
Don't lie if you don't have to.
I'm sorry.
Would you help me look?
That picture's important to me.
It's really important...
You find it?
Nope.
Huh?
What's this? Oh, a porno mag.
What?
You're in the way, Ponta.
I found it! I found it!
Is this it, Natsume?
I looked at it...
Is that your mom?
She really looks like you.
They look like nice people.
Yeah.
Thanks, guys.
This picture is of the two of them,
from just before I was born.
When I looked at their kind smiles,
and thought that I was supposed to be there smiling, too...
I couldn't stop crying.
It hurt so much that I wanted to forget.
Huh?
It's Sasada and Taki.
Taki-san?
Taki-san!
Hey!
Hey, I don't see you two together often.
I just met her back there.
Right?
Yeah.
We wanted the same CD, so we decided to take turns listening to it.
Where've you been?
You're all a mess.
A boy's adventure.
What?
We went to see a soda water spring.
A soda water spring!?
Don't laugh! It was bubbly!
Did you actually find it?
Well...
We're going back.
You got lost, didn't you?
You need to get directions first.
Right?
Fluffy... fluffy...
Fluffy!
Welcome back, Takashi-kun.
How'd you get to be such a mess?
I dropped something.
Everyone helped me look for it.
Did you find it?
Yes.
I see. I'm glad.
Go change.
You must be hungry.
Yeah.
Come on, Natsume.
Don't lie if you don't have to.
Shigeru-san,
Tohko-san.
I want to see my parents' house one last time, before it's gone.
Is it okay if I go?
Yes, of course.
We'll wait for your return, Takashi-kun.
As you stood smiling,
hohodenda ushirosugata ni
I, behind you, was holding back my tears
nakisou na kao wo kakushiteta
My chest was hurting from all the kindness,
yasashisa de mune ga itakute
and the days were so lovely and precious
konna ni hibi ga itooshikute
To the sound of the wind, to the night's darkness,
kaze no ne ni yuuyami ni
I nostalgically remember you
natsukashii kimi wo omoidasu
"We will always be together forever"
"itsumademo issho dayo" to
I kept repeating this impossible wish
kanawanu koto kurikaeshi
With warmth in my hands,
nukumori wa kono te ni
I am now living with bright colors
azayaka na mama ikite iru
I do not want to forget,
wasuretakunai mono
the love I received that changes the future
uketotta ai wo mirai ni kaenagara
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Door Of Memories
I've got a place I have to stop first.
You always have places to stop.
Hey, wait!
Will he ever get there?
Mom and Dad were both nice to you!
I'm going back to the home I love...