Natsu
me
Yuu
jin
chou
Natsume Yuujinchou
Just why are you crying? I don't understand at all
kimi ga doushite naite iru no ka boku ni wa nani mo wakaranai
I can't just thoughtlessly tell you that I "do understand"
"wakaru yo" nante kotoba karugarushiku kuchi ni dekinai
So please tell me why you are in pain
dakara oshiete kimi ga kurushimu wake o
I want to try my best to do for you whatever I can
boku ni dekiru seiippai no koto kimi ni shite agetai kara
To you, living in this moment, I'll send my song
ima, toki o ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
To you, trying your hardest to live on, I'll send this song
seiippai ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
You've been through so much up to today,
kyou made konna ni kurushinda kara
but you'll definitely have a happy tomorrow
ashita kara wa tanoshiku sugoseru yo kitto
So please, don't keep suffering alone
dakara kimi yo hitori de kurushimanaide
It's been a long time, Natsume Takashi-kun.
Matoba-san.
You snuck in here just like a cat or a youkai.
No. One of your youkai dragged me here.
Then I apologize.
Still, it's good timing.
I was just thinking that I'd like to talk to you.
Come to think of it, is your cat not with you?
The Eastern Forest
Natsume disappeared?
Yes. I caught some delicious minnows,
and I wanted to show him,
but he's not at his home or that "school" of his.
You don't think it's those eastern monkeys
that showed up a while ago, do you?
I don't know.
Misuzu-sama said there's been youkai hunting around that exorcist's mansion again.
Are they after the Book of Friends to put a stop to that?
It's possible.
What's wrong with you guys?
W-Well...
You're the ones from the east.
What do you want?
Where is this Natsume kid?
Return our friend!
What are you talking about?
Didn't you take Natsume?
We did take him to the eastern forest,
because he refused to give us the Book of Friends.
Instead, he worked with the exorcist
and kidnapped our friend!
That's why we don't like human children.
Where is Natsume?
Where is our friend?
You know what will happen if you hide him from us!
Buddha save us!
I don't really have any reason to save them,
but I don't like when people misunderstand Natsume.
What do you mean?
Natsume would never ally with an exorcist,
and he wouldn't kidnap any youkai.
She's right.
Begone.
I am hungry.
We're saved.
Saved...
The monkey masks in the eastern forest
were lead by a powerful youkai named Rokka.
For them to kidnap a human child...
What are you going to do?
You wanna know?
Natsume-dono is in a bad spot, though.
He should just let go of the Book of Friends.
He won't.
Then you should take it from him
and make it so he can live solely in the world of humans.
If you truly care for him.
That's not what he wants.
You think?
I don't understand the hearts of humans.
Have some tea.
Don't worry.
It's not poisoned.
You seem to really dislike me.
More importantly,
what do you want?
I've told you before.
You interest me.
Would you join the Matoba clan, Natsume Takashi-kun?
After what happened, I did my research on you.
I'm told you were passed around
between relatives after your parents died.
You were even sent to an orphanage once.
Some of the other children were scared by your behavior,
and you didn't stay there long.
It must've been difficult.
You can see them, but others can't.
Living like that...
Join me and you won't have to worry about that.
Everybody here understands.
No one here will be scared, or put off.
You'll be spared the pain of living with those who do not understand-
I refuse.
Why?
It's true that it's been difficult at times,
but I've met many kind people.
Like the Fujiwaras, who you're living with now?
But do they really know and accept everything about you?
Do the two of them know what you see-
That's not your concern!
I'm leaving.
I'm not done talking to you.
I don't understand.
I would've thought the cold treatment you
received from others as you grew up
would lead you to be entranced by the youkai,
and thus to side with them,
but that doesn't seem to the case.
Why do you side with the youkai?
They deceive and betray humans.
You've experienced that, I'm sure.
And more than once or twice.
You're right.
But... that's not all.
Some aren't like that...
Have you met many like that?
What's strange about that?
That's the same thing you said a moment ago.
Do you perhaps believe that youkai and people are the same?
Sensei!
Natsume.
Oh, there you are, kitty.
Is this the place?
Yeah.
I told you not to get any ideas, exorcist.
You seem quite intent on killing me.
You'll be quite useful.
We are leaving.
My bag.
He found it?
Let's go, Natsume.
Yeah.
Nyanko-sensei!
You are dangerous.
The youkai have stolen away your heart.
It's time to wake up.
No!
Move.
That youkai is with you because he can gain from doing so.
He does not like you,
nor does he feel any kind of affection.
Move.
Throw them in the prison.
Don't let them go any further.
Protect the master.
They're here!
Split up!
We have no intention of leaving this forest
until we've captured your master, Rokka.
We won't give you the master.
Why? Why do you obsess over this forest?
Why the master?
What have we done to you humans?
It's simple.
We've heard this forest is ruled peacefully by this Rokka.
Our leader is interested in such a powerful youkai.
Just for that?
Looks like the exorcists are involved.
Who are you?
Where is my master, Natsume-dono?
Natsume?
Wanna fight?
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume Reiko...
For now, we thank you.
If you hadn't come, they would've hunted us.
So?
Where is this Rokka?
He is hiding somewhere safe.
Guess he doesn't care about you.
W-What?
Mock the master and we'll make you pay.
But I'm right, aren't I?
Your master sent you to steal the Book of Friends
while he hid in the forest.
No!
Our master isn't like that.
He is asleep.
Asleep?
Then what about the book?
W-Well...
It might be best if we met this Rokka.
I'm hungry.
I'm bored.
Natsume, bring me a drink!
Bring me squid!
Don't be stupid, Sensei.
I'm bored.
I was planning on taking down that stupid Matoba kid!
Instead, you got knocked out.
What?
And who protects their own bodyguard?!
I protected the Book of Friends.
You just happened to be there.
What?!
I don't understand.
You don't intend to control or lead the youkai,
so what good does it do you
to have the Book of Friends?
Even the wimp knows better than you.
That's why I told you to give it to me.
What good does giving it to the white pig do?
Give it to our master!
What?
I'm gonna put a letter in you and toss you into the ocean!
Oh, there he is.
You're...
Where's the Book of Friends?
Where is our friend you stole?
Hey! I'm in here! In here!
I know that voice!
We'll make you pay for throwing him in there, kid!
Wait!
I didn't put him in there!
Are you trying to lie to us, human child?
That's...
No, that's...!
Look inside! The Book of Friends might be in there!
No, wait!
Don't touch it!
That's even more suspicious!
Do it now!
Yeah!
Wait.
The Book of Friends isn't in there.
I looked myself.
Is that true?
Yeah.
More importantly, get me out of here.
The guards will come.
It's Matoba's servants.
Get going!
B-But...
I came to see how you were doing.
I guess you have the power to command youkai.
Command them?
If not, then who called for them?
The cat?
Or...
Nobody had to call for them.
My friends can get in here easily!
Oww!
What?
What are you doing?
Punishing him.
A youkai shouldn't come into a human home uninvited.
Please stop.
He's got nothing to do with this.
It's a lesson for the rest of them.
He doesn't seem like he's useful for anything,
and he has an attitude problem.
Stop it.
Please.
Stop it, please!
Jeez.
You can tell me to stop holding back if you want, Natsume.
Sensei.
When you go easy on the ones with just a bit of power,
they give you more trouble than anybody else.
Just a bit?
That's not very nice.
I am the leader of the Matoba clan...
Not happening!
He got away again.
You saved me, Sensei.
I was just protecting the Book of Friends.
Thank you,
for not telling your friends about the book.
I don't understand it.
To humans, youkai are like a mist.
Why protect them?
I couldn't help it.
My body moved on its own.
It's really important to me.
We'll be going then.
Run before Matoba-san and the others come.
It's a simple seal.
Your friends can undo it.
Natsume.
Yeah.
Natsume,
you may be right.
If I took the Book of Friends
and brought it back to the master, they might be sad.
There they are.
You guys.
Human child!
You tried to hand us over to the Matobas!
No, I never...
He's right.
I hate to say it, but he protected me.
Don't be fooled!
Then why doesn't he give us the Book of Friends?
If he wants to help us he should give it to us.
No, it's...
Give it to us.
Enough of this.
Nyanko-sensei!
Stop it!
Natsume!
Oww...
Give it to us.
You bring disaster.
You bring disaster!
You bring disaster to us...
Stop it.
How much tragedy must you bring to us?
Begone!
No, it's not like that!
Begone, human!
Human, begone!
Yeah, we're leaving.
He and the Book of Friends are going back where they belong.
I'm his bodyguard, after all.
Come after him again,
and you'll have to deal with me, not the exorcist.
Come whenever you like.
That's enough.
Misuzu.
Master!
My, my...
What are you doing?
You know better than this.
I'll ask you to forgive their rudeness.
Who are you?
I am the ruler of this forest.
My name is Rokka.
Rokka was weakened by the seals
that the exorcist placed on the forest.
He fell into a deep slumber in the depths of the forest,
guarded by the monkey masks.
They must have felt scared.
They sought the Book of Friends to give them power.
How foolish.
Then the Book of Friends...
Your coming undid a small number of the seals,
and I was able to awaken.
I would never seek to steal it.
Natsume-sama!
Come on, monkeys!
Bring it on!
Don't you know that he is the savior of Yatsubara?
Savior! Savior!
The middle-class youkai?
Natsume!
Hinoe?
Natsume, don't worry.
Don't worry! Don't worry!
Let's do this, Natsume!
I will now drink the water of life
and become a powerful god to save you!
Now, let us fight!
Fight, fight!
Bring it!
Stop!
Don't make things any worse!
[ Sign: The Dogs Circle ]
Are you sure it was right to let them go?
Even without the Book of Friends,
we could've asked them to help restore the forest.
They're doing more than enough.
Can't you tell?
Oh my...
It bothers me how my master refuses to call my name.
Thank you, Misuzu.
You could have just given them the Book of Friends.
I could...
if they would return the names in my place.
The deal is that I get it.
He's too powerful.
Even all our servant youkai together
might not be able to hurt him.
If the ruler of the forest was that Rokka youkai,
then there may be nothing more we can use here.
You're going to abandon the forest?
Yes,
but there are many ways to do things.
Thus, the eastern forest was liberated,
and the matter settled.
Okay, then we meet at eight.
Don't be late.
Yeah.
Natusme, you need to eat liver before you come.
If you're missing school from anemia, it means you need more iron.
Yeah.
Iron, iron, liver, liver.
What's wrong?
Is there another problem?
No.
There was something I forgot to say.
I'm sorry we made you act strangely
in front of your friends.
Natsume, it's ready!
I'll be right there.
You have youkai who will help you
even without the Book of Friends, don't you?
Yeah.
My friends.
Will I ever be able to talk about this feeling?
Okay, I'll be back.
You've must promise, okay?
If you'll be late, you have to call us!
Yes, sorry.
You're making too big a deal out of it.
He's in high school now,
so a little's okay, right?
Nope!
Okay, pinky swear.
Lie and you have to swallow a hundred needles!
This frustrating happiness...
You don't think you should wear some more layers?
Shigeru-san used to wear this.
Is it too big?
It's fine.
It's very warm.
Don't worry.
You'll get bigger soon.
By this time next year...
Days so warm it almost makes you dizzy.
It may be time for me to stop looking away and know for real.
Natsume.
You're late.
Since I've decided to protect the Book of Friends...
Since I decided to live accepting what I hear and see...
As you stood smiling,
hohodenda ushirosugata ni
I, behind you, was holding back my tears
nakisou na kao wo kakushiteta
My chest was hurting from all the kindness,
yasashisa de mune ga itakute
and the days were so lovely and precious
konna ni hibi ga itooshikute
To the sound of the wind, to the night's darkness,
kaze no ne ni yuuyami ni
I nostalgically remember you
natsukashii kimi wo omoidasu
"We will always be together forever"
"itsumademo issho dayo" to
I kept repeating this impossible wish
kanawanu koto kurikaeshi
With warmth in my hands,
nukumori wa kono te ni
I am now living with bright colors
azayaka na mama ikite iru
I do not want to forget,
wasuretakunai mono
the love I received that changes the future
uketotta ai wo mirai ni kaenagara
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Little Ones
Tama, Nora, Chibi...
What, are you going to keep a cat or something?
You've already got me!
I brought them home...
But these are really boring names.
You think of some, too!
Like this one.
Oh no, the scrub brush moved!