Natsu
me
Yuu
jin
chou
Natsume Yuujinchou
Just why are you crying? I don't understand at all
kimi ga doushite naite iru no ka boku ni wa nani mo wakaranai
I can't just thoughtlessly tell you that I "do understand"
"wakaru yo" nante kotoba karugarushiku kuchi ni dekinai
So please tell me why you are in pain
dakara oshiete kimi ga kurushimu wake o
I want to try my best to do for you whatever I can
boku ni dekiru seiippai no koto kimi ni shite agetai kara
To you, living in this moment, I'll send my song
ima, toki o ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
To you, trying your hardest to live on, I'll send this song
seiippai ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
You've been through so much up to today,
kyou made konna ni kurushinda kara
but you'll definitely have a happy tomorrow
ashita kara wa tanoshiku sugoseru yo kitto
So please, don't keep suffering alone
dakara kimi yo hitori de kurushimanaide
Thank you for riding JR Kyushu.
This is the express train to Hakota, Yamome 38.
Hey.
Would you let me sit there?
It's my seat.
Sir, is something wrong?
No.
It's nothing.
My old house, which had been empty for years,
is going to be sold.
I decided to go see it one last time.
My mom died just after I was born,
and I lived with my dad there for several years.
I was too young to really remember it, but...
I can probably follow the map there.
Hey, Natsume.
Buy a boxed lunch at the station.
That's the first step.
Nyanko-sensei!
Why are you coming with me?
Boxed lunch! Boxed lunch! Boxed lunch!
The Door Of Memories
Lunches,
tea, coffee, juice.
Beer and snacks, too.
[ Label: Yamome Boxed Lunch ]
I'll take a boxed lunch.
One boxed lunch, yes?
No, two, please.
Two?
Yes.
Two.
Hakota.
Sensei, we're switching trains.
There's somewhere I need to stop at, first.
The home of my relative closest to that house.
They have the key.
I have to go get it.
You know the way?
I stayed there a while when I was little.
I can probably remember the way, once I get close.
So, right?
Left?
Just a second.
I'll check the map.
You don't even know if it's left or right?
I stayed at so many places, I don't even remember...
I think it's this way.
You don't have a clue, do you?
Oh, Natsume.
[ Signs: Udon ]
There's an udon seller.
You can remember from there.
I never really paid much attention to udon sellers.
This scent...
Just an Udon Shop
I remember I'd always smell this on the way home from school.
That's a weird thing to remember, isn't it?
It's this way, Sensei.
Hey, wait!
What about the udon?
You just ate a boxed lunch.
Udon...
This is the way.
The leaves from this tree would fall onto the road.
See that?
The camellias at that house were always so pretty.
And there was a nice old lady at that house.
Once in a while, she would give me candy, without telling my dad.
Why did I forget all this?
Hey, Natsume.
Get walking.
Yeah.
I sense a youkai.
That's right. There are a lot of youkai around here.
I think that's it.
I'm just going to get the key.
You wait outside.
It'd be weird if I brought a cat.
What's weird about it?
In exchange, Sensei, I'll buy you udon on the way back,
but if I don't come back for a long time, you have to come help me.
What?
Is there something there?
You mean I can eat the people here?
No.
I remember.
There was this weird youkai who was living here.
That's right, when we were in elementary school.
You don't remember?
He was here for a while.
Natsume Takashi, huh?
He'll be coming here today.
He said he wanted to see his old house.
Why, I wonder.
I don't wanna go home.
Why?
I don't want to see him.
He was a gloomy little kid.
I didn't like him.
Something super-weird is sitting on our wall!
Shoo! Shoo!
Who's that?
Can that be him?
He looks cute!
Cute? Maybe...
Oh, Takashi-kun.
Hello there.
You've grown up.
It has been a while.
Um, Tachibana-san said the key was here...
Yes, he told me everything.
Um... would you like to come in?
No, that's fine.
I'll be leaving right away.
Will you?
Aww, why?
You've come all this way.
Have some tea.
Come on in.
Miyoko.
I'm back.
Mom, get some tea ready.
I'm thirsty.
That kid.
Takashi-kun, come inside.
Please.
Yes.
Thank you.
This is bad.
I knew it was here.
It's looking at me.
If I don't look at it, I'll be okay, right?
I don't want any trouble.
It's somewhere around here...
Ah, there it is.
This is it.
Thank you.
Um, well... we haven't really cleaned it.
That's fine.
It's an old house, you know?
Even if we find a buyer, they're probably going to tear it down,
so we haven't worked on it.
We all took turns going to see it once in a while...
It's fine.
I just want to see it.
I see.
Takashi-kun?
No... I'm sorry.
Can I use your bathroom?
That's right.
He used to try and scare me.
Still, am I imagining it, or is he bigger?
I'm kind of surprised, though.
He's changed.
Maybe I should've been nicer.
What are you talking about?
You hated him.
But...
You and dad were always so nice to him,
and he'd always say the most depressing things.
Or just wander off.
People started to talk bad about the family because of it.
He's the one who was a weird liar.
Stop it, Miyoko.
He's got lots of problems.
See, like that.
You're spoiling him.
That's what I hated most.
Miyoko...
But I guess he's not a liar anymore.
Mouth... draw a mouth...
Let me go.
Draw... draw a mouth...
Natsume Yuujinchou
I need to leave.
If I'm here, he'll...
Takashi-kun, what's wrong?
No...
It's nothing.
That youkai's bad.
He'll grab me and attack my mind.
Um...
Anyway, you've really grown up.
I was worried.
Fujiwara-san, was it?
They're a very distant relative,
and one day they just came and asked to take you.
They never had children,
so I thought they might not know how to treat you.
Draw... draw...
Takashi-kun?
Actually, you look kind of thin.
Are they feeding you?
Draw a mouth.
If you draw one, I'll eat all the people who say bad things about you.
I'll eat them all.
I remember.
I know you.
You can see me.
So you can draw a mouth...
If you want to forget...
The sad memories,
and the warm ones...
I'll eat them all.
Draw a mouth.
What?
You're not going to say something weird again are you?
Somebody's here.
Dad!
This weird thing that was on our wall came into the house!
What? is it?
A stray cat?
Is it a cat?
Sensei?
Are you okay?
He scratched your face.
Mom, get the first aid kit.
Oh, right.
Dad...
I'm fine.
Thank you.
I'll be going.
Um, but...
What's your problem?
Thanks for the key.
I'll take this cat out with me.
You could at least have some tea.
No, thank you.
I'll worry them, if I'm out late.
Thank you.
I-I see.
What about your face?
Is it okay?
Yes.
Thank you.
You saved me, Sensei.
Jeez... you always run into the weirdest things.
Sensei, can you tell me anything about that youkai?
When I was a kid, it wasn't that big.
I think it's called a Mushikui, a bug-eater.
A mushikui?
It didn't have a mouth, right?
It sucks away the strength of insects who come into the house,
and gets bigger.
It eats bugs?
Then, we can ignore it.
Yeah, you've probably got two or three years left.
Two or three years?
You felt it, right?
When they get that big
they can't get full off of insects anymore.
Youkai like that foster darkness in human hearts
and then devour them.
Let's get going, Natsume.
Hey! Wait!
How could you leave like that?!
You haven't changed at all!
You're just like you were!
My mom and dad are so nice to you!
What's your problem?
Don't try and get attention from my parents by being weird!
They worry about you, they really do...
Even though they're my mom and dad!
A mouth... draw a mouth.
Hey, if you want me to draw one, follow me.
Don't worry.
I won't take your family.
Goodbye.
It's following us.
What is wrong with you?
Why can't you just leave them alone?
Even a dog doesn't forget to repay a meal he's been given, Sensei.
I'm not a dog and neither are you!
Damn it, how long do I have to run this marathon?
He's a wimp anyway.
You're my prey, he doesn't get to touch you.
Begone. Now.
Thank you, Sensei.
Idiot.
They let me into their house.
They let me into their family.
I'll go back to my home, too.
It's like a treasure hunt.
Come on!
One! Two! One! Two!
I just ran as fast as I could, so I don't know where I am.
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
I'm looking for this spot on the map.
Hmm, you can just go up that road...
We're still not there yet?
If we don't get back soon,
we won't be in time to eat Tohko's dinner.
That's right.
Let's hurry.
We're still a ways away.
I won't take your family.
He wouldn't have been able to say it like that a long time ago.
A long time ago, huh?
He was a kid, I guess.
But, Takashi-kun, I was a kid, too.
Miyoko?
Miyoko.
Dad...
Why did he come here?
Miyoko, want to have a nice talk with Dad tonight?
Then you can go to school with Takashi-kun tomorrow.
Walk further behind me.
Hey, where's your house?
Your real house.
My real house?
The house where your parents lived!
Don't you remember?
About your mom and dad?
I don't remember my mom.
And your dad?
My dad either...
But he was... really, really nice!
You're weird.
How can you say that when you don't remember him?
How dare you talk like that?
My dad's much, much nicer!
He's going home...
To the house where his "really really nice" dad lived, huh?
Miyoko, can you come here?
Okay.
Come to think of it, one time I tried
to go back to that house by myself when I was little.
How did I forget?
So did you-
Natsume!
What's wrong, Natsume?
Go home...
I have to go home...
Natsume? Natsume?
Natsume!
I could hear Sensei calling.
But it felt like my heart was looking for something...
Natsume!
getting lost in distant memories.
I have to go home.
As you stood smiling,
hohodenda ushirosugata ni
I, behind you, was holding back my tears
nakisou na kao wo kakushiteta
My chest was hurting from all the kindness,
yasashisa de mune ga itakute
and the days were so lovely and precious
konna ni hibi ga itooshikute
To the sound of the wind, to the night's darkness,
kaze no ne ni yuuyami ni
I nostalgically remember you
natsukashii kimi wo omoidasu
"We will always be together forever"
"itsumademo issho dayo" to
I kept repeating this impossible wish
kanawanu koto kurikaeshi
With warmth in my hands,
nukumori wa kono te ni
I am now living with bright colors
azayaka na mama ikite iru
I do not want to forget,
wasuretakunai mono
the love I received that changes the future
uketotta ai wo mirai ni kaenagara
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Long Way Home
I have to go home.
My real home.
Actually, I'd called out for it again and again.
There's my home.
No matter how many times I called for it,
I couldn't have it.
I need to get back.
I have to hurry... hurry...
Let's go home.