Natsu
me
Yuu
jin
chou
Natsume Yuujinchou
Just why are you crying? I don't understand at all
kimi ga doushite naite iru no ka boku ni wa nani mo wakaranai
I can't just thoughtlessly tell you that I "do understand"
"wakaru yo" nante kotoba karugarushiku kuchi ni dekinai
So please tell me why you are in pain
dakara oshiete kimi ga kurushimu wake o
I want to try my best to do for you whatever I can
boku ni dekiru seiippai no koto kimi ni shite agetai kara
To you, living in this moment, I'll send my song
ima, toki o ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
To you, trying your hardest to live on, I'll send this song
seiippai ikiru kimi ni kono uta wo okurou
You've been through so much up to today,
kyou made konna ni kurushinda kara
but you'll definitely have a happy tomorrow
ashita kara wa tanoshiku sugoseru yo kitto
So please, don't keep suffering alone
dakara kimi yo hitori de kurushimanaide
I can see the youkai?
Why?
A youkai?
Oh, my.
What a strange human,
to wander into the world of the youkai.
The world of the youkai?
Is that why I can see them?
My, my...
I'll let you go, so get going.
If someone finds you, you'll be eaten as a snack for the banquet.
But, my friend–
Oh, no.
It's probably a bad idea to say anything.
Anyway, it's not a good idea
to wander outside of your territory.
Now get going.
Thank you.
I guess some youkai are nice.
Well, I wouldn't know about that.
He said that there was a banquet.
It's safe to assume that's where he was taken.
I need to sneak in somehow.
Be quiet, idiot!
The Gap Between Humans and Youkai
The Gap  Between Humans and Youkai
Come on, come on!
Until the master comes, put your gifts on this altar.
This is a glorious event.
Drink, drink!
Offerings...
Everything here is a present to Omibashira?
There are so many youkai here...
It's up to me if I want to help, right?
I'm sure Tanuma is looking for me.
I need to get out before he comes here
and something happens to him.
I see.
So this is the Natsume human?
He's too small to really see.
He's a human, but he's supposed to be really strong?
They know who I am!
A splendid find, yes?
Omibashira-sama will be pleased.
He must be delicious.
Is it true you found Natsume?
I saw him once from a distance.
Let me see.
He's pretending to sleep?
Hey, there!
Don't be fooled, everyone!
That bottle is a fake.
What?
Tanuma!
The real Natsume is inside this bottle.
He said he had an idea, so I let him go in.
Let's see how well he can do.
Hey, are you okay?
What happened to your kimono?
Did someone take it?
I know you...
I suppose now's not the best time to just squash him.
Go get 'em, Tanuma.
I finally caught Natsume, and now I find that
someone else claims to have found him first?
Are you saying that I'm lying?
I am.
I know you want to stand out,
but your lies won't work.
You're the liar!
Then let's see who's got the real one.
Fine.
Hey, kid.
Show them your face.
Tanuma!
Hey, kid!
I told you to show your face!
Damn it.
He's opening it.
He smells like a human.
What?
Crap!
Natsume!
You're a pain to watch over, you know that?
Who are you?
Run.
W-What?!
They'll get away!
I didn't expect any humans to come here.
It doesn't matter.
They can't escape this mansion, so we needn't worry.
If I've come this far, I'm fine.
This place is big...
Much bigger than it looks on the outside.
This might be trouble.
Natsume?
That's right. He's still somewhere in the mansion.
Supposedly, he's got a fat calico cat with him.
This is hard.
We'll be okay here for a bit.
Thanks.
I told you to stay away, you know that?
It's fine, Natsume.
This youkai helped me
when I was about to come in the mansion...
That's no youkai.
What are you doing here?
I'd rather not say.
We'll get into another fight.
Besides, that's my line.
What's going on, Natsume?
I guess he's just a normal kid.
You shouldn't have brought him here.
I know that.
Wait.
Natsume didn't bring me here.
I came on my own.
It's fine.
Natsume...
It's my responsibility.
I was careless and got trapped in that bottle, so you...
I guess you're starting to learn
how dangerous it can be
when you spend too much time with youkai
and they learn your name.
You're not a youkai?
Who are you?
I'm Natori Shuuichi.
I work as a youkai exorcist as a second job.
A youkai exorcist?
But I've seen you somewhere before...
Umm...
My other job is as an actor.
Oh, right.
I'm going to be in a movie soon.
I'll give you a ticket.
It was right here...
Now's not the time!
We need to escape somehow.
Hiiragi and Urihime.
Good timing.
Get them masks.
They'll need kimono as well.
Yes, sir.
Hiiragi.
Natsume?
You look pale.
Do you know them, Natsume?
Yeah.
Who is this?
Come to think of it, I didn't get your name.
Natori-san.
Don't worry.
I'm not gonna try and recruit someone
who's just a little sharper than average.
Tanuma.
Tanuma Kaname.
Tanuma-kun.
Nice to meet you.
Tanuma is getting more and more drawn into this world,
and it's my fault.
I smell a strong human scent.
Is it coming from here?
Hiiragi.
Yes, sir.
Is this where you are, kids?
Oh, Natsume.
You got out.
Not bad, Tanuma.
Is that you, Sensei?
Sensei?
Jeez.
They know too much.
It's hard to go around in my beautiful form.
I didn't know you could take human form.
Of course I can.
Taking human form is normally
something done by beasts and lower class youkai.
It's not for a noble being like me.
But why that form?
The only humans I've ever gotten a good look at
are Natsume and Reiko.
No matter what I do, I end up looking like one of them.
Who's Reiko?
Who knows?
This one won't break either.
A barrier?
Do we have to go back to the entrance?
No, that won't be so simple either.
What do you mean?
Come this way.
What's this?
There aren't any stairs or an incline,
but that window shows the view from the first floor,
and this has the view from the second floor.
It's pretty complex.
Is it to keep us from getting out?
I thought it might be, but it's too big and involved.
They were talking about offerings,
but Omibashira himself is nowhere to be seen.
Something's wrong.
This energy...
The evil energy is getting stronger.
I'll go upstairs.
Thanks.
I'll go check over there.
Wait.
What's wrong?
You stay here, Tanuma.
If anything happened to you...
I told you back there.
I'm here because I want to be here.
And Sensei was saying it's because
I wandered into the world of youkai,
but I can see them just like you, now.
So I can help...
You two.
Did you see my friend come this way?
No.
Nobody's come this way.
He must've left already.
Natsume, you're shaking...
I'm happy you feel that way,
but if it got you hurt...
The world of youkai is just that dangerous.
Natori-san, isn't this blood?
Yes.
It's likely they were eaten.
Eaten?  Who was?  By whom?
Omibashira-sama.
I was planning on sealing it while it was still weak,
but it looks like that's no longer possible.
I see, so that's it.
So what's it?
The Onizarus didn't spread
those flyers to gather offerings.
They wanted to lure the less powerful youkai here,
so they could be eaten by Omibashira.
Right now, they're all locked inside and lost,
and it's eating them one by one to revive itself.
This is bad.
No way...
Then to get out...
We'll have to either find the exit,
or seal away Omibashira before it completely regains its power.
One of the two.
It'll be fine.
Natsume...
I'll get you out of here.
I'll get you out of here, no matter what.
No matter what happens.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Let's split up.
Natsume and I will look for Omibashira.
The cat and Tanuma-kun will look for the exit.
Whether we find it or not, we come back here in one hour.
Got it?
Got it.
Nyanko-sensei, take care of Tanuma.
Yeah.
If he stays by me and doesn't get any ideas, he'll be fine.
Here, this stone will protect you.
Hey, Natori!
Are you saying you can't trust me?
It's my policy not to force a lady to work.
Creepy!
This is just a temporary form.
Okay, see you in an hour.
I guess a crazy kid gets crazy friends.
It's not funny.
Still, I'm sorry about earlier,
for yelling at you when you saved him.
No, it's my fault for talking like that.
You hadn't told him you knew any exorcists, had you?
I suppose not.
Even though he's your friend?
Or is it because he's your friend?
Yes.
That Natori exorcist guy might actually be pretty nice.
He's kind of high-pressure
and at first I didn't like him very much, but...
Those are just habits he's picked up.
That's what happens when you have a lot of enemies.
Enemies?
You mean youkai?
Yeah.
When you're in that line of work,
you end up with more enemies than just youkai.
I see.
There's a lot going on in this world.
Well, don't get too involved in it.
Somebody as weak as you will get eaten quickly...
If he's eaten this many,
Omibashira must have regained a lot of his power.
This isn't something you could tell Tohko-san about.
Is that why Natsume...
I'll get you out of here no matter what.
Sensei?
What?
What did Natsume's face look like
when I said I'd help him?
When I said I'd do what I could,
what did he look like in the bottle?
I thought he'd be happy.
I thought he'd feel a little better.
That's why I...
But...
Ask Natsume.
I don't know.
These are...
Are these...
Omibashira's footprints.
What's this presence?
That was Tanuma!
Tanuma!
He was attacked, but the stone kept him safe.
The poisonous aura was enough to knock him out, though.
Tanuma...
Jeez... everybody keeps wandering off!
You're late.
Shut up!
So where's Omibashira?
Close, most likely.
Which means, even if we did find the exit,
we can't just run.
We have to seal him.
You've been planning to do that the whole time.
I suppose so.
Natsume, help me ready the seal.
This has always scared me.
That this would happen someday...
Natsume?
Tanuma isn't the kind of person
who would come to a place like this.
He's not like me. He's cautious and thoughtful.
It's just him and his dad,
so he never does anything that would worry him.
When he's with me,
sometimes he wants to say
things but holds back for my sake.
Then I brought him here,
and I made him do all these crazy things...
What should I do?
Maybe I can't stay here anymore.
Natsume.
You're strong, Natsume.
I hated that feeling so much
that I gave all that up long ago,
so I don't know how to say this, but...
You can't abandon it.
It might be hard, but you need it.
You need it.
Master.
Omibashira is in the corridor above.
I see.
Hiiragi, you stay with Tanuma-kun.
Natsume, I'll prepare the seal.
You'll help me, right?
Natsume, if you can't do it, I will.
No, I'll do it.
I'll go.
Save us!
The windows!
The windows won't open!
Save me!
Omibashira-sama, you're hungry, right?
Come this way!
No, you don't!
Shadow of the one who hides in the gap,
grab hold and sleep,
and answer my call!
The master's power had almost returned!
How dare you!
You'll pay for this!
Hey, there's a human child here!
An exorcist, too!
What?
A human child?
Jeez...  This is the problem with youkai.
Shut up!
Weak youkai, those two Onizaru
tried to feed you to Omibashira!
What?
Then that was Omibashira?
His barrier is gone.
Now go!
The banquet is over.
Anyone who remains, I will eat myself.
He's gotten far enough from the mansion
that the poison is receding.
Thank you.
Natori-san asked you to come finish things in the mansion.
Understood.
Tanuma.
Natsume?
Thank you.
I escaped from that bottle,
and we were able to seal Omibashira.
It's all thanks to you.
The truth...
Tell me the truth.
Tanuma?
My getting involved made things worse for you, didn't it?
It made you suffer, didn't it?
I'm not really good with other people.
Even if there are things I want to know,
I don't know how much I can ask.
I want to help you, but I don't know what to do.
Well...
If you don't like it, say so.
If you don't want to answer, you don't have to.
I'm glad you told me you can see youkai,
but I don't want you regretting it,
or it putting a wall between us.
I was so happy you told me, so it would hurt.
Tanuma.
What should I do?
I'm sorry, Tanuma.
I'm sorry.
Where do I go from here?
It's probably the path that Natori-san gave up on.
The one that Reiko-san wanted to follow, but couldn't.
Will I be able to follow it?
Bye.
Natsume...
You'll be at school tomorrow, right?
Yeah, I have to take my chance to complain.
You told me to complain once I got out of the bottle, right?
I'm back.
That's right...
They said they'd be home late.
I'm hungry!
Food!  Food!
I'm back.
I'm tired...
Natsume!
Wake up!
We're gonna eat that gratin.
Hey!
You can't abandon it.
It might be hard, but you need it.
Hello?
As you stood smiling,
hohodenda ushirosugata ni
I, behind you, was holding back my tears
nakisou na kao wo kakushiteta
My chest was hurting from all the kindness,
yasashisa de mune ga itakute
and the days were so lovely and precious
konna ni hibi ga itooshikute
To the sound of the wind, to the night's darkness,
kaze no ne ni yuuyami ni
I nostalgically remember you
natsukashii kimi wo omoidasu
"We will always be together forever"
"itsumademo issho dayo" to
I kept repeating this impossible wish
kanawanu koto kurikaeshi
With warmth in my hands,
nukumori wa kono te ni
I am now living with bright colors
azayaka na mama ikite iru
I do not want to forget,
wasuretakunai mono
the love I received that changes the future
uketotta ai wo mirai ni kaenagara
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
When I Was Deceived
We'll exorcise anybody who tries to stop us, even the cat.
You're merciless, aren't you?
I wasn't always like this.
Humans and youkai are all born with their own karma.
I want to be strong like you!