Natsume Yuujinchou
The Stone Waker and the Strange Visitor
Ever since I was little,
I've seen strange things every now and then.
Other people can't see them.
They're probably what people call youkai.
Hey, mid-ranks!
Nyanko-sensei!
Hey!
My, Natsume-sama!
What is the matter?
Well, Nyanko-sensei hasn't been home for a few days.
I'm off to have some fun!
He scampered off in a good mood, so I'm not too worried, but I can't help but wonder what he's up to.
Now that you mention it, I haven't seem him lately.
But never mind that, Natsume-sama.
There have been rumors of something black
and evil with horns coming here from the east.
If it attempts any mischief here, do teach it a lesson, will you?
Good day.
Huh? Hey, wait!
I'm just a slightly skinny high schooler, you know!
I can't do something like that, you hear?!
The Stone Waker
Something evil...
I wonder if it has anything
to do with Sensei not coming home.
A youkai?
But what if it's a human?
I think it came from over here.
A spiderweb?
That scared me.
It's just a piece of paper.
Dammit.
Where'd that runt run off to?
Find him!
Any luck?
If it wasn't a human that got attacked, then I shouldn't get myself involved.
I'm sorry!
Are you okay?
Please keep your voice down!
They'll hear us!
Is this who the youkai from earlier were looking for?
It would seem that they're gone now.
You appear to be a child of man.
I'm terribly sorry for involving you.
It's fine.
Why were they chasing you?
That would be because I am the Stone Waker.
Stone Waker?
Oh no! What have I done?!
I'm not supposed to mention it to others!
Why must I always fail like this?
I see.
If it's not something I should ask about, then I'll leave you to it.
One moment, please!
I'm sorry to keep you after such a shameful display,
but I don't suppose you have seen a map in the vicinity?
A map?
It got carried away by the wind as I was running from my pursuers.
Oh, if I can't find it...
it's all over for me!
Sorry, but I can't say I have.
Do you remember how large it...
Wait, now that I think about it...
I did find this weird piece of paper.
That's it!
Thank you ever so much, thank you ever so much!
How can I ever repay you?
Thank you ever so much!
It's fine. I didn't do much.
Oh, I know.
When I have fulfilled my duty and received my reward,
I shall gladly share some of the spoils!
Reward?
Oh!
Pardon the late introduction.
I am Gantetsu-sama's 89th follower.
My name is Mitsumi.
Gantetsu-sama?
You are aware of the ninefold valley that lies beyond here, yes?
At times, evil spirits will descend upon them in want of the intense spiritual energy in the area.
Gantetsu-sama is terribly mighty and will gallantly tear them to shreds, sending them flying.
However, until the time comes, he rests quietly in his shrine.
His slumber is one so deep that he cannot wake up of his own accord.
So that Stone Waker thing you mentioned...
Indeed, Gantetsu-sama bestows the duty of waking him upon one of his followers.
And what an important and honorable duty it is!
I see.
And the guys chasing after you were trying to stop you?
No, quite the opposite.
They were trying to steal the role of Stone Waker.
Why would they do that?
You see, in order to prevent evil beings
from disturbing Gantetsu-sama in his sleep,
his shrine is located in a hidden swamp which normally cannot be entered.
And this map is the only means of making one's way to the hidden swamp!
Only those chosen for the duty of
Stone Waker are entrusted with it!
However...
Gantetsu-sama is exceptionally good-natured and generous.
He will always appoint a Stone Waker before falling asleep,
but upon awakening from his slumber, he will reward whomever happened to wake him up with fine sake.
What?
Regardless of if it was the Stone Waker or not, he will be exceedingly pleased with whomever wakes him up.
Thus, there is no end to those who pursue
the Stone Waker for the sake of the reward.
The duty of the Stone Waker is a frightful trial.
It's gotta suck to have such a fickle boss, huh?
But I am still grateful to have been chosen as the Stone Waker.
He was generous enough to entrust a small and ugly good-for-nothing like me with this task,
and I must live up to his expectations.
Is that right?
I'm rooting for you.
Thank you.
He wants to live up to the expectations of someone dear to him.
Book of
Friends
Thirty steps west of this thicket. Left at the stone.
Oh, have no fear.
The voice came from this.
Thirty steps west of this thicket. Left at the stone.
Wow, the map can talk?
Get a move on already, you dullard!
Talk about foul-mouthed!
This map is made from a small part of Gantetsu-sama.
O-Oh?
I should stay away from him.
We are surrounded by an air of greed.
Huh?
Unsavory characters are drawing near.
From behind the bushes?
There's something coming!
Hey, the runt over there!
Huh? Nyanko-sensei?
Madara-sama, did you find that Stone Waker?
Stone Waker? Stone Baker?
This is our chance to take him on.
Chance, chance?
Good grief!
Why are you so violent?!
Who goes after someone without even seeing who it is first?!
I said I'm sorry.
But you're the one who caused me grief. I looked everywhere for you, you know?
What are you doing out here?
I'm on the hunt for that so-called Stone Waker.
It's got nothing to do with you.
You wouldn't happen to be doing something so petty as to steal the duty for the sake of the reward, would you?
My, if it isn't Natsume!
Hinoe! Mustache!
What's this? Are you so thirsty for sake that you're participating in the snatching game?
What a naughty boy!
Why, you're bolder than I thought, Natsume-dono.
N-No, I wasn't—
Now, now, Natsume-sama,
this is something akin to a festival.
Many here are indebted to Gantetsu-sama for protecting these rocks.
"I'll be the one to show him my gratitude by waking him up!"
Or something to that effect.
So do you two and Sensei feel indebted to him too?
Not that a kid like you would understand, but it's important to take part in festivals.
So you want the sake, in other words.
Obviously.
Hold on, Sensei.
I'll get you something later, so—
Well, there you have it.
See you, Natsume.
Wait!
We're off to find the Stone Waker, mid-ranks!
Yeah!
Hey, hold on! Sensei!
Come on...
Say, Natsume, don't tell me this little one is...
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Mitsumi.
Let's find that hidden swamp and
get to the shrine before Sensei and his friends.
Thank you so much!
Sounds fun.
Very well.
I'll help you out, Natsume.
Hinoe.
I shall partake as well, looking on as the rabble run about like headless chickens.
Mustache...
All right!
Let's go, Team Twig!
Down with Team Drunkards!
Yeah!
So even Natsume has gotten himself involved?
Now that's a pain in the behind.
Okaka and plum!
Sour and delish!
Heeeeey!!!
Over here!
Yum, yum, yam, yam.
Take this seriously, would you?!
You're the ones who told me that you could get fine sake by waking up Gantetsu!
I'm sacrificing Touko's food to come here!
Natsume-sama said he got worried and came looking for you.
He's a simpleton, plain and simple.
Why would you worry about me?
Wasn't there some small spirit
together with Natsume-sama?
Now that you mention it...
Well?
Where do we go from here?
Just a moment, if you would.
This is taking so long...
You with the map! You're the Stone Waker, aren't you?
Fork over the map! Where's the hidden swamp?!
What? The Stone Waker's here?
The reward is ours!
Give it here!
Stop!
How heroic!
You look just like Reiko when you swing your fists like that!
I-Incredible!
He did this with that dry twig of an arm?
One of them appears to have escaped.
If we don't hurry on ahead,
they'll come back with reinforcements.
You're right.
Mitsumi, how does it look?
J-Just a moment!
The commotion just now distracted me.
There they are! This way!
Oh no!
Stop lazying around, you dullards!
We were just about to!
This might be harder than I thought.
Natsume Yuujinchou
You weaklings! One step closer and I'll curse the lot of you!
Fork over the map!
Give it here, give it here!
How captivating!
He's powerful!
Despite his lanky build!
I'll curse you so that your roof
starts leaking above your beds!
I wonder where Nyanko-sensei is now.
If we encounter them again,
they'll probably realize that Mitsumi is the Stone Waker.
Natsume-sama,
I'm terribly sorry for involving you in this.
It's fine.
I'm the one who chose to tag along.
But it's not easy to be the Stone Waker, huh?
Is it always like this?
Y-Yes, I'm told not a single Stone Waker has managed to fulfill their duty in recent years.
Really?
Did he entrust Mitsumi with such a difficult task out of trust?
Or could it be that this
Gantetsu-sama is enjoying the commotion?
Not at all.
Huh?
You are a kind person, Natsume-sama,
so you may be doubting
Gantetsu-sama's intentions out of worry for me,
but he entrusted someone as small as me with this duty, over all his many other followers.
Who'll be the next Stone Waker?
I hear the underlings got in the way
and usurped the Stone Waker again.
What can you do? He was outnumbered.
It's practically impossible.
All that awaits you is humiliation.
You dullards, is there no one willing to accept the task?
Yes, I volunteer.
I vow to wake you up.
What, Mitsumi?
As if a small, ugly creature like him would be able to.
I do not ask those who cannot do it.
I trust you will carry out the task without fail.
I will!
He understood the pain of being
entrusted with an impossible task,
but he believed that I could do it.
I must prove him right.
Don't you agree?
Yeah, you're right.
I'm sorry.
You're strong, Mitsumi.
And Gantetsu-sama could see that.
There are some things you can only see after spending time with someone.
I'm afraid not...
What was that just now?
I guess I imagined it.
Hey, map.
We're where you told us to go.
Where do we go next?
Proceed southwest from here and
enter the thicket by the large cedar.
There you will find the hidden swamp.
Get running already, dullards!
I'll tear you into pieces!
I heard that loud and clear!
It's southwest!
The thicket by the large cedar!
The reward is ours!
Sake! Sake!
I guess we don't have a choice!
I'll fend them off here, so you two run on ahead!
Thank you, Hinoe!
Let's run, Mitsumi.
R-Right!
Hey, look! There he is!
It's the Stone Waker!
Hey!
There's the large cedar!
It's the other side of this thicket.
I will... I will succeed!
I will!
Gantetsu-sama!
Is this...
Yes, this is the hidden swamp!
Is that the shrine?
Is that where Gantetsu-sama is?
Indeed.
It's much larger than I expected.
How do we get all the way over there?
It appears I will have to swim.
Huh? But you'll drown with this much seaweed.
Natsume-sama, please take care of the map so it doesn't get wet.
A hole... the fallen tree...
Did it say something?
Something creepy has snuck in!
Natsume-sama!
Look out!
How fortunate, I happened upon a child of man on
my way to bathe in the spiritual energy of the valley.
You look delicious.
Natsume-sama!
Please flee while I hold it back!
Mitsumi!
Don't! You'll get yourself killed!
Oh, is this the hidden swamp?
Hidden-bidden, swamp-stomp!
So that's where the sake is?
Sensei!
The bark of that tree should work as a boat, Madara-sama!
Nyanko-sensei!
Hey, dullard.
What are you doing in a cramped place like that?
Thank you ever so much! Thank you ever so much!
And what's that?
Oh, well...
Their mother seems to have abandoned them,
and they've been crying for days.
I thought I would feed them some insects,
but then I ended up becoming stuck in the gap.
I even ended up destroying the nest in the process...
I'm so very ashamed.
I like your pluck.
Hey dullard, how long are you planning on staying here?
You're not fit to follow Gantetsu-sama!
My dear brothers, please allow me to stay here.
I cannot leave until I have repaid Gantetsu-sama.
I beseech you.
Was that Mitsumi's memories?
Mitsumi, are you okay?!
I'm quite fine, thank you.
What about you, Natsume-sama?
I'm fine.
What a relief.
But how long were we unconscious?
Mayhaps the evil one from earlier has already entered the ninefold valley...
Mitsumi.
Let's focus on getting to the shrine first.
Gantetsu-sama is waiting for you.
Right.
It looks like we fell pretty far down.
How do we get back up?
Follow this tunnel straight east.
There is a staircase at the end.
That will take you to the shrine.
Run, dullards!
R-Right!
Looking closely,
various figures were carved into the cave walls,
flowers were blooming on what looked like tree roots,
and something sparkled like a starry sky in the darkness.
Any normal day, I would've been able to enjoy this sight with Sensei.
Look, Natsume-sama! The stairs!
We're outside!
Where'd it go?
The shrine!
There's no one here!
Hurry, Mitsumi!
Yes!
Please open, please open, O door of stone!
I am number 89! Please awaken, Gantetsu-sama!
Well done, dullard!
You've completed your duty.
You can have the reward, my dear 89th follower.
Crap!
I was waiting so I could reach the goal before the eyes of those sluggards, but they took so long that I fell asleep!
Dammit! Where's my sake?!
The Stone Waker managed to wake him up.
What?
Hmph. That's no fun.
That was a dumb festival.
It's not a festival.
By the way, did you see that black, horned youkai?
Do you know what came of it?
Who knows?
Let's head home already.
It's a hop, skip and a jump from here.
Hold on a second.
Why don't we take the underground tunnel?
It was very pretty.
I'm sure you'd like it too.
Natsume-sama!
Thank you so much!
Allow me to share some of the sake with you!
What was that?!
Sake! Sake!
Hey!
Madara-sama!
Natsume!
Let's party!
Hearty party!
You did it, Natsume! Team Twig takes it home!
We'll have to celebrate!
Moosic to my ears!
What a festive occasion!
Come on!
Huh? Wait!
Let's start with a bang!
A beast! A feast!
Hey!
This is...
Wasn't I supposed to be meeting someone?
Natsume?
No, that's...
From time to time,
I see light reflected off water on doors and ceiling.
There's no pond in our garden,
but there is one here in the world of spirits.
Natsume told me that this is the reflection of that pond.
He can see that invisible pond.
Good morning, Dad.
Morning, Kaname.
Oh?
You look a bit pale.
It's fine. I'm not sick or anything.
Anyway, what was that sound just now?
Sound?
I couldn't say.
Kaname, I'll be stepping out for a bit.
A friend might come by while I'm gone.
If he does, would you mind preparing some tea and entertaining him in the meantime?
Got it.
Now, then...
It sounded like it came from somewhere above me.
Excuse me.
The Strange Visitor
Natsume! Wanna drop by the
movie theater on the way home?
Huh?
I want to book a ticket for
The Sparkling Detective Akeboshi Koutarou 2!
The one starring Natori-san?
Wait, there's a sequel?
I'm gonna ask Kitamoto and the other guys too!
Oh, Tanuma!
You wanna stop by the movie theater after school?
Sorry, but we're having guests today again, so I need to go home right away.
Too bad. See you tomorrow.
See you.
Huh?
That person is back.
Look, by the entrance.
They've been waiting for Tanuma after school lately.
Oh?
Is it a girl?! Don't tell me it's a girl!
No, I think that's a guy.
He comes to see him every day?
Aw, bummer.
Forget about it.
That Tanuma kid has a lot of spiritual power,
but unlike you he can't see spirits.
Still...
I'm sure it's just some eccentric human.
Hello, Tanuma here.
Oh, Natsume.
Morning.
Tanuma, could we speak for a bit today?
Actually... I'm seeing someone later.
Are you talking about the person who's been visiting lately?
Yeah.
I see.
Hey Tanuma, has anything strange happened lately?
Thanks for worrying.
To tell you the truth, there's something that...
Was that the sound of water just now?
Huh?
Water?
There it is again. See?
I was actually planning on going to see you myself.
Natsume, would you mind coming over right now?
The guest won't be here for a little bit.
Got it.
I'll be right there.
I'm able to talk openly with Tanuma
about ayakashi without hiding anything now.
But if I spend our time together only
talking about sights that he can't see,
how long will he keep listening to me with a smile?
I'm not sure how to explain.
He's a bit of a strange person.
Strange?
A few days ago, my dad asked me to look after a guest.
Here you are.
What is your name?
Oh, I'm Kaname.
Is that right?
I'm sorry?
Are you aware of the Black-Handed Statue nearby?
Oh, yes.
It's a shrine located at the back of a large field.
Would you care to join me for a walk there?
Huh?
It's an important place to me.
I assumed he realized I didn't have
anything to talk about, so I decided to join him.
I figured my dad would be back soon,
so I suggested that we go home, when...
I think my father will be back soon.
I'll come by again.
Welcome back, Kaname.
Where were you off to?
This is my friend, Sawamura-san.
Huh?
I told you about him this morning, remember?
Apparently the friend my dad had mentioned was someone else.
So who was the man from before, then?
That's creepy.
He came by the next day as promised.
Ever since, I've started bumping into him elsewhere too.
What?
He'll show up randomly and speak to me for a bit, then leave again.
I'd feel bad turning him down.
Tanuma, you should be careful with strange people like—
Excuse me.
Good afternoon.
He's huge!
Oh?
Who might this be?
He's a friend of mine.
Oh?
A friend, you say?
What was that just now?
Would you mind joining me today again?
I'd like to visit the large cedar by Umegahara.
Yes, of course.
What is this feeling?
It's like he's seeing right through me.
I feel somehow restless.
Sensei, what do you think?
Sensei?
Watch out here.
It's easy to slip, so be careful.
Tanuma is considerate.
I feel as if this guy is taking advantage of that.
Are you human?
Natsume?
Or...
are you a ayakashi?
Yes, I'm a ayakashi.
I'm impressed you noticed.
However, I assure you I'm not up to any mischief.
I only wish to speak to this gentleman for a little while.
He's one of my closest friends.
I don't want unidentified creatures coming near him.
I can sympathize, but it's not you who gets to decide.
Whether or not he wants to stop seeing me,
knowing that I'm a ayakashi,
is for him to decide, not you.
I enjoyed our time together,
and part of me would love a chance to talk to a ayakashi.
But I don't want to make Natsume worry about me.
I'm sorry, but I can't see you again after toda—
Tanuma.
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't worry about me.
You've been there for me lots of times when I've been dealing with ayakashi.
Now it's my time to have your back.
Are you sure, Natsume?
If you're curious about your
relationship to this spirit, then I'll help you out.
Thank you.
My mind was suddenly drawn to Natori-san.
Perhaps he felt something similar
seeing me involve myself with ayakashi.
Ayakashi seem terrifying when they
approach someone you care about.
However...
We're here.
This is the cedar tree.
This is an important place to me.
Do you see the large hole in the trunk?
Of course.
Hey.
I will come back again tomorrow.
I had no idea he was an ayakashi.
I can't believe it. He looked completely human.
Natsume is strong.
If I was as strong as him,
I wouldn't have to worry him like that.
This isn't like me.
I'm getting greedy.
What does that ayakashi want from me?
Now that I think about it, I never even got his name.
Why are you following me?
I'm going in the same direction.
You're...
Hey, you're Misuzu!
Took you long enough!
You finally realized?
You can take a human form?
Why are you messing with Tanuma?
Well, I have my reasons.
Not to worry. It's of no concern to you, Natsume-dono.
Of course it is!
Why do you have to involve Tanu—
As I said earlier, my business is with him.
I'd advise you not to get in my way, Natsume-dono.
Misuzu!
Natsume Yuujinchou
Huh?
Good morning, Tanuma.
Morning.
What are you doing here?
I told you I'd have your back, remember?
Think of me as your bodyguard.
Huh? O-Okay, then.
Good morning.
Misuzu!
Misuzu?
Natsume was too dimwitted to realize at first,
but he knows that ayakashi.
What?
So I've become acquainted with one of Natsume's ayakashi acquaintances, then.
There's something you'd like me to do, isn't there, Misuzu?
Oh? Why do you say that?
I'm not entirely sure.
I just have a hunch.
You see, there's something I don't quite understand either. I'm at my wits' end.
Huh?
There's something lodged in the roof.
When did that show up?
Huh? Where?
It's right there.
He can't see it?
Tanuma! Are you okay?
Yeah, it's just a headache.
No, these headaches I've been getting are...
If you're not feeling well,
why don't we choose somewhere nearby today?
How about somewhere around Senbabayashi?
Come, let's be on our way.
Hey, Misuzu!
Oh, I wonder what it looks like now.
It's been so long.
What are you trying to do, Misuzu?
I'm simply going on walks to
places that I remember fondly.
Why are you dragging Tanuma along?
Does it have anything to do with that weird thing that was lodged into the roof?
I suppose so...
It'd better not be anything dangerous.
Maybe you don't think it's got anything to do with me,
but if you're trying to do something to my friend...
Dear me.
You're quite the curious one, Natsume-dono.
Forcing me to talk would be a simple task for you.
Now then, I shall take my leave,
my master.
This dream again...
Natsume?
No, that's...
This is... our garden?
Book of
Friends
I've taken a liking to you, Natsume-dono.
I shall entrust you with my name for the time being.
You may call for me if you see fit.
Misuzu!
Why, if it isn't Natsume-dono.
What business does a child of man have here so late into the night?
Down we go.
I want to hear the full story, so I came to see you, Misuzu.
You could have simply used the Book of Friends. Why come all this way?
You've entrusted me with your name.
I'd only just found out what the Book
of Friends was, and I was full of worry.
Your trust served as emotional support.
I feel like if I forced you to talk,
I'd destroy something important.
So I'm here to ask you instead.
You always say the strangest things.
Damn straight.
The moon is beautiful tonight.
I will give you a ride home.
So you still won't talk?
It would be no fun to tell you.
That's all.
Oh, what a wonderful moon.
It was beautiful even from the bottom of the swamp.
They call me the guardian of the swamp,
but I once was a nameless being with neither shape nor form.
One year when harvest was poor,
the humans threw a horse into the swamp as an offering.
I took a liking to its form and made it part of myself.
Since then, I've amassed an unexpected amount of power.
I don't understand it myself.
Oh, we just happen to be passing by the old Yatsuhara temple.
Tanuma's house?
And look.
Over there is another swamp.
Now it's shrunk and you can barely see it,
but once upon a time it was like a twin to my swamp.
Oh, how it takes me back.
Will the day also come when I look back fondly on how I viewed the moon together with a tiny child of man?
Oh, I'm sure...
it won't take long.
Natsume, could you come have a look at something?
I've been having dreams about a lake recently,
and yesterday I had one where Misuzu was looking between the tree and the stones.
I got curious and had a look, and I found something weird.
Huh?
Whoa!
What's this?
They're puppets.
Puppets?
And why would Tanuma have a dream like that to begin with?
Natsume, there's something I've been thinking.
Huh?
Excuse me.
I've been happy that Misuzu, one of your spirit friends, has seemed to be showing an interest in me.
But it feels like he's actually talking to someone else.
What?
Misuzu!
Is there something possessing Tanuma?
Tanuma?
This concerns me and him,
so I wasn't planning on telling you.
"Him"?
Just as I'm called the guardian of the Suzunaki swamp near Yatsuhara,
there's a guardian of the other swamp called Sasame.
We will sometimes meet up here and battle to see who is the stronger guardian.
Battle?
When Sasame, who unlike me has no form,
has built up enough power,
he will possess a puppet placed in between the swamps,
then place a monk's staff on the roof to inform me that he is waiting.
Yet when I stopped by this time, I came to find that he had entered not a puppet, but a child of man.
That vessel is easy to possess and has a lot of spiritual power, so he seems to have taken a liking to it.
If we battle like this, I may end up hurting the child of man serving as the vessel too.
Therefore...
I hoped that visiting places we'd fought in the past would make him itch for battle and move to the puppet instead.
That's why I took him to all these different places.
So you did this for Tanuma?
But now that the person
in question has noticed, I have no choice.
I'll force Sasame out.
Even if I have to be somewhat violent.
Misuzu!
With the power of you and your cat doll, perhaps we can get him to leave.
Really?
Tanuma!
Tanuma...
I was supposed to have your back...
He gained a form and became powerful,
while my power continues to diminish.
All that grows is the gap between us.
But as long as I have this vessel...
Are you the one Misuzu was hoping to see?
Can you catch up to Misuzu if you're inside me?
If my power is of any use to you,
I'll let you use it, for just a little while.
It must be hard,
not being able to catch up to your friend.
Good grief, what a fool Tanuma is.
Who are you?
I'm busy thinking.
Do I drag you out right now,
or do I let Tanuma do as he wants?
Which will Natsume make the least fuss about?
You're a funny furball.
Misuzu must lead a merry life
with individuals like you around him.
A merry life is not necessarily the same as a fulfilled one.
This is an important place to me.
It's been so long.
Tanuma!
You don't need to worry.
I was a fool to depend on a child of man.
He does not only seek me for my strength.
As my power dried up, perhaps so did my heart.
Forgive me, child of man.
Even if I don't catch up to him, I'm sure...
Tanuma!
Farewell.
Misuzu! Battle me!
Very well!
I'll take you on!
Tanuma!
Goodbye...
The puppets holding Misuzu and Sasame
crashed into each other in the sky for a while
before disappearing beyond the mountains.
I wished that I could show Tanuma this beautiful sight,
but he came down with a fever
and was bedridden for a few days.
I wonder what ended up being Misuzu's next important place.
Listen here, Tanuma brat.
You can't let spirits talk you into something like that so easily!
You especially shouldn't go along with
something you can't deal with by yourself!
You're right.
If you'd only told Natsume earlier,
we might've been able to solve it more easily.
Sorry.
I was a bit hesitant to suggest he could be a spirit when I can't even see them normally.
It doesn't matter if it's a spirit or not!
If there's something worrying you, I'll listen!
Yeah, you're right.
I'm not sure if it's because of the
fever or because the spirit left me,
but I can't actually remember what happened clearly.
Huh?
I can't remember what he looked like,
but there was a spirit friend of yours called Misuzu,
who I think I visited a bunch of places with.
It probably wasn't me he was talking to,
and something that lived inside me for a while left me.
That's about all I remember.
I almost feel this sense of loss.
I'd only just gotten to know them...
Still, I had a lot of fun,
getting to see the same things as you.
Bye, Natsume, Sensei.
See you tomorrow.
See you.
Bye.
Tanuma Kaname...
He's quite the interesting character.
So?
Who won the battle?
That's not something I could tell a human.
I see your footprints in the sky
sora ni wa kimi no ashiato
They fade away like vapor trails
hikoukigumo ga kiete yuku
As if tracing a memory,
I ran my finger across the sky
omoide wo nazoru youni,
sora ni te wo kazashita yo
I want to, I want to become strong, become strong
watashi wa tsuyoku tsuyoku naritai naritai
Because even if I can't see you in this world
kimi ni aenai sekai da to shite mo
I still have to keep on living without you
watashi wa ikite iku kara
I see your smile in the sea
umi ni wa kimi no hohoemi
Its light shines in between the waves
namima ni hikari ga kagayaku
I stared at the horizon like a girl lost in dreams
yumemiru shoujo no youni suiheisen wo niranda
Even if I'm sometimes weak, so weak, and start to cry
toki ni yowaku yowaku naitari shite mo
I still believe my words will always reach you
kimi ni todokanai koe wa nai yo to
watashi wa shinjiteiru kara
Forever, forever
I want to stay by your side
zutto zutto soba ni itakatta
Even now, even now
I can hear your heart beat
ima mo ima mo kikoeru kodou ga
Today, tomorrow
it echoes inside me
kyou mo asu mo watashi no kokoro no naka
As I take deep, deep breaths
tsuyoku tsuyoku iki wo shiteiru
I see your profile in the mountains
yama ni wa kimi no yokogao
Cherry blossoms run down your cheek
sakura ga hoho wo tsutatteku
Even if I get a little angry
karakai atta hi no youni
Like when we used to tease each other
sukoshi dake okotta to shite mo
I still want to, I still want to keep on smiling, keep on smiling
waratte waratte itakute itakute
I want to embrace the world
kimi ga shiawase da yo to waratteta
That you said you loved with a smile
sekai wo dakishimetai nda
I see your heart in the river
kawa ni wa kimi no shinzou
Its flow is endless
doko made mo nagarete yuku
I slowly play this melody as I follow your life's course
jinsei wo tadoru youni yukkuri to senritsu wo kanaderu
It's long, it's long, yet short, yet short
nagaku nagaku mijikai mijikai
And so my sadness is embraced by your kindness
kanashimi wa yasashisa ni idakarete
As I whisper "thank you"
arigatou to tsubuyaita
Forever, forever
I want to stay by your side
zutto zutto soba ni itakatta
Even now, even now
I can hear your heart beat
ima mo ima mo kikoeru kodou ga
Today, tomorrow
it echoes inside me
kyou mo asu mo watashi no kokoro no naka
As I take deep, deep breaths
tsuyoku tsuyoku iki wo shiteiru
I'm always searching for traces of you
sagashiteru itsu made mo anata no omokage wa
Even my tears are dear to me, and I don't want to wipe them away
namida sae itoshikute nuguitakunai yo
I love you from the bottom of my heart
kokoro kara aishiteru
Forever, forever
I want to stay by your side
zutto zutto soba ni itakatta
Even now, even now I can hear your heart beat
ima mo ima mo kikoeru kodou ga
Because today, and tomorrow too, it echoes inside mine
kyou mo asu mo watashi no kokoro no naka
As I take deep, deep breaths
tsuyoku tsuyoku iki wo shiteiru
One day, one day
I hope we meet again
itsuka itsuka aeru to ii na
If we're ever, if we're ever reborn
moshimo moshimo chigau ningen ni
As different people and cross paths
umarekawatte surechigattara
Give me a wink, just like that star
uinku shite ne ano hoshi no youni