It's freezing.
I guess it's winter already.
Geez.
You're a weakling as always.
You're weak against the wind because you're as thin as a pencil.
Well, are you going to hibernate?
You're as chubby as a meat bun.
What?!
This isn't meat!
This is fur!
Fur!
Haven't you heard of winter fur?!
Geez!
Well, I think you've gotten a lot fatter recently.
Oh?
A dragonfly!
A dragonfly, Natsume!
Wait! Wait!
Wait up!
Hey, Sensei!
Wait up, dragonfly!
I guess it can't be helped.
Nyanko-Sensei's First Errand
Gotcha!
Hey! Stop that! It tickles!
Natsume, as soft and puffy as my coat is, stop that, I can't breathe!
Stop, Natsume!
What?!
I caught a Tanuki!
Tanuki!
W-Who are you?!
Ah! The Tanuki talked!
Yeah, you're right!
Who are you!?
Meow.
There, there.
It doesn't hurt, it doesn't hurt.
Geez, don't cry!
You can't cry, big brother's here for you.
If you cry, the one-eyed monster will come!
The one-eyed monster?
This is intolerable!
As if I'd let them follow me!
I'll just back away...
I'm outta here!
What troublesome human children.
You guys!
If you want to eat them, you're going to have to face me!
They're my snacks!
If you don't want to get injured, pick a fight with something else!
Whoa, he'll kill us!
Hmph, lowly creatures.
Hm?
Do Tanuki eat childern?
Like hell they do!
And anyway, I'm not a Tanuki!
See, it did talk!
Who are you!?
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
That's right, I'm a talking Tanuki!
Got a problem with that?!
Whoa!
Cool!
He's so fluffy!
Chubby!
Anyway, what are kids like you doing on a mountain, stop-
We're on an errand!
We're going to three fonster!
Three fonsta?
Wrong! Three fonster!
Three fonsto?
This is why I'm bad with kids.
In any case, we'll get out of this spirit filled forest, and find someone who's good at handling human children.
Hey! If you pull that hard, I'll choke! Stop, hey!
Geez, where did he go?
Hey, Natsume!
Why're you wandering around like that?
Is there a cute girl around?!
What're you saying? He's not like you.
What?! Don't say that, how mean!
Only you would do that!
Have you seen Nyanko-sensei around?
Oh, Nyan Nyan-sensei?
I haven't seen him...
What, is he missing?
Want us to make a search party?
No, it's fine.
It's always like this.
He'll come back.
Yeah, he'll be back by dinner. He eats a lot, so he'll be hungry.
That's true.
Geez. It's lucky we haven't run into any familiar faces yet, but…
Huh?
What?!
Where did they go?!
Up we go…
Hey! Stop that!
Hey, hey, stop, it tickles...
Let go, I told you, let go!
Huh?
Hat.
Hey! Stop that!
Hat!
I'll do it for you, I'll do it!
Yahoo!
Why… did it turn out like this…
Yay!
Oh?
Well, if it isn't Madara-sama?
I hope you're having a wonderful day!
Wonderful day, wonderful day!
You guys!
I'm saved…
Huh?!
Yahoo!
One more time!
Oh, that's right.
Normal kids can't see them.
Natsume's the weird one.
Bringing kids along with you. Are you preparing an evening snack?
Appetizers! Appetizers!
I'm not walking around with them because I want to!
Geez!
Oh, that's right! I want to ask you guys something.
Oh, how rare!
You can ask anything of us.
Anything! We'll do it!
Hey, humans.
Come here for a sec.
Who are you!?
Where did you guys want to go?
Say it again.
What? Why?
We already said it before!
Just say it again!
What?
Um, we're going to buy ham and milk!
And we can buy Pakurin Choco too!
Pakurin?
Milk?
And we're going to three fonster!
Mama said it was really close by.
And that's the situation!
If it's you guys, you can understand them, right?
No way, you ask too much of us…
Too much! Impossible!
You guys are useless…
Yahoo!
Oh, that's right! I came across Master Hinoe around the boulders ahead of here.
If it's her, I'm sure…
If it's her!
Sorry for the wait, Hiiragi.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Master seems to take a liking to that.
Oh, this?
When I was a kid I couldn't stop eating them.
Pakurin Choco!
Geez!
She should have appeared by the boulders those chumps told me about by now.
I can’t walk anymore. Piggy back!
What? No way, I’m tired too…
There, there.
It doesn't hurt, it doesn't hurt.
It doesn't hurt!
Don't cry!
You can't cry!
This is intolerable!
I don't care! I'm getting out of here!
Piggy back!
Then at least hold me properly!
Natsume Yuujinchou
I'm sure it was over here…
Huh? Natsume?
Tanuma?
Out for a walk?
Well, it is warm today.
Yeah, but I got separated from Sensei…
Ponta?
I haven't seen him around here.
That's okay, it happens all the time.
He'll probably be back by dinner.
Probably.
There's no way he'd miss Touko-san's dinner.
Definitely not.
Where did he go!?
Hey, stop that!
Stop!
Hey, stop! You're tickling me! Let go, let go!
Roll, roll, roll…
Argh! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Can’t you stand by yourself?!
Why am I doing this…
Rub, rub.
Oh, cat doll.
Fancy seeing you here.
Oh, Hinoe?
I'm saved…
Huh?!
You!
I heard that you were by the boulders!
Huh?
I've been here the whole day.
Those chumps!
You actually believed those two?
Your senses have dulled.
In any case, what's with the kids?
Are they snacks?
I'm not taking them along because I want to!
Geez.
Oh yeah, I want to ask you something.
Hey, humans!
Come here.
Who are you!?
Where was it you wanted to go?
Say it again.
What? Again?!
We said it before!
Just tell me!
Um, three fonster is straight from our house!
And we can buy Pakurin Choco!
Well, well!
Okay!
The great Hinoe-sama’s divinations will guide you there!
Really?! Just this once, there's a halo around your head!
Hmhm, watch this!
There, it's done!
Bam!
What's this? It's weird!
What are you doing, you human?!?!
Calm down! Calm down!
I'm sorry! Please calm down!
What you're looking for is to the right.
Right? So north.
It seems like a formidable spirit will come to your aid along the way.
What?! That’s promising!
In any case, be careful.
That 'formidable spirit' might not be that easy to deal with.
Ramen
Three Forest Store
Ramune
Oh? Natsume-kun!
eam
Ramune
Sasada, Taki.
What a coincidence!
Yeah. Shopping?
We're here for…
This! Pakirun Choco!
When I was talking to Taki-chan, she said she's never tried one before...
Well, if I eat one and get addicted…
But really!
It's weird enough that you've never even had one!
What about you?
You've tried it, right?
Well, I've seen classmates eat it… I think?
What?
You haven't had one either?
Then have this!
I'll give you one!
Oh, thanks!
It's not my fault if you get poisoned!
Well, see you at school on Monday.
Yeah.
Ah! Oh, yeah!
Have you seen Nyanko-sensei around here?
What?!
What happened to Tsuruka-sensei?
Well, I just got separated from him while we were out for a walk.
What? Won't Fatty be back for dinner?
Yeah, I think so, too.
But… I kinda think that he's in more of a pinch than usual.
Geez.
The formidable spirit that Hinoe was talking about should have appeared by now…
Hm?
I can’t walk anymore.
Don't cry! You can't cry!
This is intolerable! I hate this! Hurry up and appear, my aid!
Oh? I hear a bit of a ruckus and a rice cake appears before me...
What an opportunity!
Mustache!
The formidable spirit was you?!
I don't know what this is about.
But around here there isn't anyone else as noble as me, no?
How cocky!
And anyway, I'm not a rice cake!
Are you gonna eat me or not?! Here!
If I eat such a dirty rice cake, I won’t be able to reach a ripe old age.
In any case, hiding behind Natsume again?
Eating all you can get, are you?
As I thought, you're despicable.
That's why you're so fat and round.
I'm not walking around with these kids because I want to!
Geez!
Oh, yeah.
Since you're my aid, I'll have you answer this.
Hey, humans.
Who are you!?
Shut up.
Where did you want to go again?
Say it again.
Um.
We're on an errand!
I love Pakurin Choco!
It's at the three fonster!
So, we're buying some!
Is this like that saying that goes, “if your three-year-old self can't understand, you never will, even at a hundred”?
There's no way that's the problem with these kids. There'd be an apocalypse.
If anything,
it’d be something more like… “Three's a crowd, and a hundred times more warm.”
I have no idea what that's supposed to mean.
Shut up!
Then why don't you try saying something better than me?
Go on!
Say something! Go on!
Three fonstere, right?
Maybe they want to count to three, one, two, three?
Maybe they're trying to find three fond stars?
Ah.
What the heck is that?
"Three Forest Store".
"Ham, milk, fish sticks, two Pakurin Choco"?
What the heck is that?
It seems like something one would use for their first errand.
Three
Forest
.
Store
Ham....
Milk...
Milk
Fish sticks
2 Pakurin.......
choco
.
Ramen
Three Forest Store
It's over there.
It's three fonster!
Theefonstar!
Hey! It's dangerous if you run out like that!
Be careful!
Geez.
I don't know if you were helpful or not, but you took care of us.
I'll return the favor some day!
Come visit me any day!
Why are you here?
Mama!
Where did you go off to?
It's already dark.
It's so late. I was so worried!
That's a relief.
Mama was looking for you.
Mama, you know, a Tanuki gave me a piggy back!
That's right!
It can talk!
And he pulled us along!
Is that so?
I'm glad you’re safe!
Next time we'll go together, okay?
That's right.
Oh, kitty!
Ice cream
You walked all the way here today?
Welcome home.
We're back.
What's wrong?
Welcoming us back?
Oh, yeah.
Welcome home.