I heard the faint sound of something banging on the window,
and for a moment, I thought that someone had come to have their name returned.
It's snowing.
It's snowing, Sensei!
That hot-water bottle is all yours now, Sensei.
Sometime on a Snowy Day
I've seen strange things ever since I was a child.
Those things that only I could ever see were probably "youkai".
Touko-san!
It's snow–
Touko-san?
Are you looking for something?
Huh? Oh, Takashi-kun.
Would you lend me a hand, please?
Yeah, sure.
With this?
Yes, thanks.
Finally got it out.
Thanks, Takashi-kun.
No problem. What is it?
A heater?
The washroom's pretty cold, don't you think?
It's an old heater, but I think it'll still work.
I started finding all kinds of nostalgic
things while looking for this
and got sidetracked with all the memories.
Like the bowl Shigeru-san made, or souvenirs from a trip.
Oh no! I have to get things ready for dinner!
I'll clean up when I have some time again tomorrow.
I'll carry this to the washroom for you.
Oh, thanks!
Oh, by the way, it started snowing.
I see. No wonder it's freezing.
Um, do you mind if I go take a walk outside?
I'd like to see the snow falling.
My, sounds like something a child would do.
Put on some warm clothes before heading out.
Don't forget your scarf and gloves.
Okay.
We're having hot pot tonight.
With clear soup.
All right.
The snow makes everything look different from usual.
I feel good even though it's so cold.
It's suddenly gotten dark.
I got carried away and walked too far out.
Maybe it was a bad idea to go out on a day like this.
I didn't even bring Sensei along.
Feels like a snow fairy could show up any moment.
I have to find it.
Speak of the devil!
Though it looks more like a fluffy snowman than a snow fairy.
I have to find it.
I wonder if it's looking for some–
Uh-oh!
Can you see me?
Hold on, strange boy!
Help me look for it!
I'm sure you can find it!
It's following me, huh?
What are you looking for?
What am I looking for?
Something warm.
Looking for something warm in all this snow?
Are you cold?
Well, shoot. This is about the best I can do.
Here.
You can have this.
Cold!
Whoa! It's frozen!
Stay back!
If you don't keep your distance, you'll end up freezing me too.
Something more sparkly.
Sparkly?
That isn't what you said before.
This is the first time I've spoken to a person.
It feels strange.
Was it something you lost?
Are you sure it was around here?
I'm not sure.
I can't remember.
It was warm, sparkly, and smelled good.
Hold on.
You can't remember?
You mean you're looking for something with no idea what or where it is?
I only know that I have to find it.
I've never once forgotten that.
I've even been looking for it in my dreams.
Aren't you an oddball?
Let's look for it together!
You're looking for something too, right?
No, I'm not looking for anything.
Really?
I was under the impression that humans are generally in search of something.
Huh?
You're always looking for something or forgetting something.
Humans are much stranger than I am.
Anyway, I'm sorry to say that I can't help you unless you remember something.
See you later.
Wait, thin one!
How cold can you be?
Cold? You're the one who–
Ow...
What a strange guy.
I'm sorry!
Shigeru-san?
Takashi?
What's wrong? Something happen?
No, uh... the snow just got me a little too excited.
Oh, is that why you were running so fast?
Yeah, it doesn't snow much around here.
When I was a kid, I'd get all excited when it snowed like this.
I had fun leaving footprints in the snow.
I wanted to be the first one to leave my footprints in the snow, so I ran all over the place.
Really?
Apparently we're having hot pot tonight.
Oh? Sounds good.
Oh, you two came back together.
Welcome home.
Now, eat up.
This looks great.
Doesn't it?
Here.
Not again.
What kind of a moron was it this time?
Not someone after the Book of Friends, I hope?
No.
You're drinking again?
Hm? Snow is best watched with a drink in hand.
But you're not even watching the snow.
Jeez.
It didn't mistake me for Reiko-san or anything.
And it didn't seem like its name was
in the Book of Friends, either.
Hm? Did you say it was looking for something in the snow?
Does it ring a bell, Sensei?
I'm not really sure... Uh...
I don't remember!
It's because you've had too much to drink.
My, my, I didn't think there would be such a beautiful spirit of a lady here–
It looked like this.
What's this dull looking thing supposed to be?
This fluffy thing is it.
All right. It's time to get some sleep.
No! I want to drink more!
I wonder if it's still searching.
All alone.
I was under the impression that humans are generally in search of something.
You're always looking for something or forgetting something.
That might just be true.
Where am I?
I can't see anything.
What am I looking for?
I have to find it.
So cold.
Way too cold!
Fluffy!
You followed me here?!
Is that the–
What's with this chill in the air?!
Get the heater, Natsume!
J-Just its presence makes it cold!
Where's my hot-water bottle?!
I'm here to give this back to you, thin one.
I-It's frozen solid!
M-My scarf...
You! Get out of here!
Hold on, Sensei.
It came all this way to give back the scarf.
Let's hear it out.
Natsume Yuujinchou
So, do you think you'll be able to find it?
Yeah.
I did find something warm.
You found it?
Right here in this house.
Huh?
I found so many warm things in this house!
Oh, come on.
The things in this house couldn't be what you're searching for.
This is it.
It's so frozen that I can't tell what it is!
So warm...
But this isn't it.
You trying to freeze us?!
Don't get violent!
Look who's talking!
Listen up, Fluffy.
It's something important to you, right?
Very.
Then try to remember what you're
searching for, and where it could be.
Fine.
I'll think about it.
Don't doze off!
I remember now!
Really?
Something nostalgic.
Nostalgic yet brand new.
Why is it that you're looking for something that you don't even remember?
I have to find it.
Hey!
I found something warm, but that wasn't it.
I found something nostalgic, but that wasn't it.
None of this is what I'm looking for.
The strange boy asked me why I was looking for it.
Why, indeed?
I used to know the answer to that question.
Well, I'm sure I'll figure it out when I find it.
The snow's all piled up!
Sensei!
School's canceled today.
Let's head out later and be the first
to leave footprints in the snow.
What are you so excited about?
Wait a second.
Whoa, it melted!
What did it even–
Shigeru
This is...
Maybe it was talking about warm,
gentle memories back then.
With loving, warm people like
Shigeru-san and Touko-san around me,
Shigeru
I was able to recover something I'd forgotten all about.
I'm off!
Now, even the things I'd wanted
to forget feel precious to me.
See you later!
I found that glove I lost in the field over there, but it was frozen solid!
Are you serious?
How far are we going?
Well, we're trying to be the first to
leave footprints somewhere,
so we need to find a place nobody has set foot in.
Marbles?
What are you looking for?
Don't tell me you're trying to help that...
That fluffy thing is more dangerous than you think.
If it so much as breathes on you and you get frozen solid, not even I would be able to help–
Stop, you idiot!
Something seems wrong.
What's the matter, Fluffy?
Thin one.
You must be tired.
Have you been walking around looking for it all this while?
I have to find it.
I remembered.
It'll vanish once it gets warmer!
Huh?
It will vanish!
Hey! You all right?
Be careful!
What are you doing?
Forget it. I'm in a hurry.
Hold on, Fluffy!
Leave me alone!
Don't come crying to me later.
Hm...
Oh! Would you look at that.
Shigeru
This is surprising.
So you had held on to this too.
I didn't realize what it was yesterday.
Hey, why don't you open it up?
Okay.
Just what you'd expect from a boy's treasure box.
Oh, I'd completely forgotten about this.
Brings back memories.
These kind of things were still rare back then.
I want Takashi to have this.
Huh? Are you sure?
On second thought, he's not a kid anymore.
I guess he doesn't need it.
It's snowing again.
Hey, what do you mean when you say it will vanish?
I have to find it.
You mean it'll melt like the snow?
Hey, could what you're looking for be–
What's all this racket?
A human?!
Not that hairy thing again!
I don't want it anywhere near me!
Oh, please. One could swallow it whole.
It's a real eyesore watching it loiter about.
We should eat both of them.
Hey!
Watch your tongue, you lowlifes!
Sensei!
The cold makes me angry!
This is my prey.
I'll eat anyone who dares to lay a finger on it!
Nothing good ever comes of this.
We're going home, Natsume.
I'm sorry, Sensei.
but I kind of know how it feels to want to recover something you've forgotten.
So I'd like to help look for it.
Tell me, is the thing you are looking for really a physical entity?
What?
What else could it be?
Like a memory or something.
You're a strange one.
And you say some funny things.
Am I wrong?
Fluffy, there's something on your chest.
There it is!
It's so warm!
Oh, right! That's right!
Fluffy?
Oh, that's a seed.
A seed?
These things exist in this world for hundreds of years, wandering about searching for it.
They know they're fated to look for it, but at the same time, they're also fated to forget all about it.
But on one snowy day, it sprouts forth within their bodies, buds a flower, and vanishes.
That is what Snow Flower is.
I've remembered it all.
I was meant to become what I am now.
And once that flower blooms...
So all this while, she was looking for something that would make her disappear?
Look!
She's vanishing!
No!
Thank you for finding it for me, strange guy.
You strange, lovely guy.
Don't look so sad.
I'm sure you'll find what you're looking for as well.
One day.
Cheer up, Natsume.
I hear that not even many spirits get to see this flower.
I'm sure it means something good that we both got to see it.
Really?
Don't ask me.
Snow Flower may have vanished but a faint fragrance still lingered in the air–
the scent of a spring yet to come.
Welcome home.
Thanks.
You see, I found Shigeru-san's childhood treasure box while I was cleaning the storeroom.
Oh, you did?
He said he wants you to have this.
Snow Flower, I don't know what I'm looking for either.
I don't know what I'll find in the future.
Or if I'll be able to keep the memories of the things I find.