Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
I was on my way back from an errand
that Touko-san had asked me to do in the next town.
I'd tried to take a shortcut and gotten lost.
Hatsuna!
It's Natsume Reiko!
Reiko?
One Night's Cups
Reiko! Are you okay?
Oh, you're awake, Reiko!
No, I'm...
I'm sorry. That One-Horn got angry just because he got close to Bousui Rock...
That's why I said we didn't need that thing!
But aren't you curious? I am!
It's almost time!
Oh, they say that it's almost time for the water from
Bousui Rock to make the one who drinks it more powerful,
an event which happens once every twelve years.
That big thing wants it all for himself.
What a jerk.
Does your head still hurt?
No, I'm okay now.
You saved me and brought me here?
You're the one who saved us.
You're as amazing as they say, Natsume Reiko!
You drove that thing off with a single punch!
Wait, I'm not Reiko-san.
I'm Natsume Takashi, her grandson.
Reiko-san passed away years ago.
Grandson?
Passed away?
She's gone.
Maybe she hit her head...
Rest a bit more, Reiko.
It's true.
I've never even met my grandmother.
Hey, can you tell me about Reiko-san?
I told you something seemed off!
What?
You said this smell was definitely Reiko! You were sure of it!
You had a huge fit and said Reiko might die!
Oh, I see...
So Reiko's gone...
That's a shame...
We should've come sooner...
The two of us, husband and wife, are travelers.
Husband and wife.
We met Reiko here, so we thought we could meet her again.
The two of us make sake cups.
We make them in a kiln wherever we go.
Hey, what's that?
A child of man, talking to us!
Are you Natsume Reiko, the girl everyone's talking about?
What? A girl like this?
How rude.
She answered!
This is a kiln, right?
Yeah.
We're about to fire the sake cups.
Reiko, if you're free, want to fight me?
If I win, you have to drink with me.
If I win, you can have my name or a sake cup.
So you can drink—
Hey, stop being so stupid, honey!
This is my fight!
You stay out of it!
There's no way you could win!
You two are really close, huh?
See? She's laughing at you!
Sorry, but humans can't drink until they're grow-ups,
so no fighting.
I was looking forward to drinking with Reiko when she became this "grown-up."
Well, but you know...
It must be Reiko that forged the fate that brought us together,
and caused you to save us.
Natsume, rest here as long as you like.
That's right.
Don't push yourself.
I know! Natsume, you want some water?
Yeah, thanks.
Aww, so you're still a kid who can't drink, either?
Here you go.
Did you two make this cup?
It's good!
It's the power of the One Night Cup!
It makes sake taste even better!
If you drink sake with the cups we make,
it will taste delicious, no matter what kind of sake it is!
I bet Sensei would love this...
Everybody says it doesn't just taste good,
it makes them feel powerful!
Yeah.
Yeah, I feel stronger somehow.
Right? Right?
He forms them, and I glaze them,
and it gives them this strange power.
But it disappears in a night.
It disappears?
Funny, huh?
So they started calling these One Night Cups,
and everybody loves them.
That's a test fire we just made.
It's well-made.
We'll make a lot more tomorrow.
As we travel,
we make these cups for the youkai we meet.
And we always look forward to the sake and snacks they give us in exchange...
We have a party almost every night.
And as the night goes on,
we hear more and more stories, which is the most fun thing of all.
No matter where we go,
youkai hear about the One Night Cups and come in huge numbers.
Well, some of them are bad news,
and come to interrupt us, or start fights.
And because of that, the two of us have become quite strong on our journey.
I know. Help me a little, Natsume.
What? Natsume still needs to rest!
I'm fine now.
I want to thank you for what you've done for me,
but I have to get home.
Can I come back tomorrow?
Yes, that would be great.
Hey.
Right-o!
I'll take you home, Natsume.
Sorry about all that, Natsume.
Hizuchi is so stubborn.
And he's so blunt, too.
You must have felt exasperated, right?
No.
Have you two always been together?
That's right.
For a long long time now.
We've made these cups together for a long time.
But it's quite rare for him to ask anybody else for help.
He's never let anybody else touch the clay.
Is that true?
He's being stubborn,
but it's possible he's feeling a little weak-kneed.
If only time would stop for just a little...
He loves making cups so much.
Oh, sorry.
It's nothing.
Hizuchi must've been really happy to meet you, Natsume.
I know I am.
Come tomorrow.
Oh, look!
That's one of the human paths ahead.
You're okay now, right?
Got it.
Thanks, Hatsuna.
Bye, take care!
I'm back!
Sorry I'm late!
Welcome back!
Sorry, I got lost.
I see.
Thanks for going all that way.
It was nothing.
Welcome back, Takashi.
Thanks.
What?! The One Night Cups?
I figured you'd know about them.
A sake cup like a dream that disappears after a single night.
And they say the sake tastes so good it's like a dream, too.
I've heard that couple has been making those cups for over a century.
That long?
Every sake drinker in the world wants to try one!
Let's go now, Natsume!
It's late.
We'll go tomorrow.
No, no, no!
Goodnight.
I want to drink sake!
Why? Why can't I go? Tell me!
I don't know why,
but those two reminded me of old memories.
Hatsuna and Hizuchi,
the two of them always together...
I can't even sleep!
Sake!
Someone bring me sake!
Natsume Yuujinchou
It's the perfect day for a drink!
What are you talking about?
Who would've thought that the One Night Cups were so close, though?
This is the smell of sake! I know it!
Hey! Sensei!
Sake! Sake! Sake!
Hey, I haven't seen you before.
Did you come for the banquet, too?
Yup. Let me join you.
With pleasure!
Sensei!
Oh, there's a child of man with you?
That was nice of you to bring a snack.
You can't eat him. He's all tendons and skin!
He'll ruin the good sake!
Yeah, he doesn't look like he'd taste good!
Natsume!
Hatsuna!
Welcome, Natsume!
Hey, give me a sake cup.
Sensei, don't be rude!
Oh, you know Natsume?
The cups are right over here, Mr. Bean Bun.
Who are you calling a bean bun?
Call me Nyanko-sensei!
Now take whichever you like.
Which do I want?
The biggest I can find?
Or is it more important to have something that fits easily into the hand?
Hizuchi.
Oh, Natsume!
Welcome! Welcome!
The banquet's already started, huh?
The ones who can't wait for evening gather like that.
I can't wait to drink, too.
But I've still got more cups to make.
Want to try, Natsume?
Sure.
More!
Put more power into it!
I didn't think it would be this heavy!
Hey, don't let me catch you trying to push Natsume too hard!
What? Get lost!
You're good at that!
Maybe I'll have Natsume take over for me.
What are you talking about?
My wife can be so annoying.
But she's so silly, too, at times.
The clay is nice.
It doesn't talk.
I've been with them a long time.
Both my wife and the clay.
He loves making cups so much.
Now it's my turn.
I glaze them with this.
This part is up to me!
Natsume,
I'm going to fire them!
This is the most important part.
The quality of the fire controls how they turn out.
You really are like Reiko.
That was the first time I ever talked to a human.
Hey, Reiko!
Well, are you a grown-up yet?
Hey, are you still not a grown-up?
All she'd ever do was laugh.
They say human lives are short.
It's so frustrating.
It's so strange...
I can't even imagine how long your journey has been,
but it's amazing that you were able to get strong during that time.
It's not just getting strong.
It's nothing...
My cup...
What?
So they didn't last until night, huh?
I'm sorry, everyone, but that's all for today.
I'm sorry.
It's over already?
The night was just getting started, too.
It was good sake, though.
Thank you.
It was great sake.
The sake was even better than I'd heard.
Hey!
What? I know!
It's a shame, but it looks like they don't have
the power to make those cups anymore.
But why?
Nothing happened.
They're just reaching the end of their lives.
Oh, but the end isn't as soon as you think it is.
If only time would stop for just a little...
It's not just getting strong.
Maybe they were here in search of the spring water from Bousui Rock.
I think I heard it only comes once every twelve years,
on the closest night of the full moon.
So that's tonight, huh?
Hey! I was just feeling good!
Don't make me run!
Sensei, take me to Bousui Rock.
Hatsuna! Hizuchi!
You're in the way, child of man.
I'll eat you first!
What are you doing here, Natsume?
He drank his fill of water and got stronger,
but he's no match for me!
He's just another wimp!
Now begone!
I'm sorry, Natsume!
You saved us again...
Thank you, too, Sensei.
Nah, I owed you for the drink.
Natsume, you have a powerful friend, don't you?
I wanted to mix this water into the glaze.
Thanks to you, we can make our cups again.
I see.
We'd always said that if we couldn't make them anymore,
we'd just give up.
But she just wouldn't shut up about it...
What? I'm doing this for you...
I know! That's why...
Let's make our sake cups together, with that, just for the two of us!
I've been thinking...
We've made thousands, maybe tens of thousands, of these cups.
But we've never made any for ourselves.
For the first and last time, we can make our own...
Honey...
I'm happy.
It's finally time for the two of us to drink together.
Bye, Natsume.
I'm glad I got to meet Reiko's grandson.
Really...
Don't make that face.
Even if we can't make our cups,
as long as we're together, we'll continue our journey.
Once you become a grown-up, let's drink together!
Thank you, Natsume!
Thank you!
I'm back.
It's so late!
You should've at least called...
I'm sorry.
What happened?
You're covered in mud!
No, um...
Let's eat.
Takashi, go wash your face.
Okay.
Shigeru-san.
Now, now, Touko-san.
We can hear the story while we eat.
The food will get cold.
But...
You're right...
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru