Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
I couldn't turn down Matoba-san's request.
I ended up going with him to a meeting where he'll attempt to lure out the exorcist
who is attacking the other exorcists.
I'm very happy you came today.
Why have you been wearing a suit the past two days?
I was meeting with a politician in this area.
People with a lot of enemies are often very superstitious.
We've had a long relationship,
and I like to keep on good terms with people who can be useful.
You should make use of what's available to you, as well.
No matter what it is.
The Matoba Clan was originally
formed by the eleven great exorcist families which
were lead by the Matoba,
as part of a contract they each signed out of their own self-interest.
Self-interest?
Some of those families are gone now, though.
I wonder what happened to my letter, though?
Shadow of Linked Chains
We're here.
This is the place.
It's huge!
What is this? Your house?
It's one of our villas where the meeting will be held.
A villa?
Again?!
Welcome back.
You'll have to change for the meeting in an hour.
Use the room in the back.
This place is huge.
How many of these villas do you have?
We call them villas,
but we simply use the homes of families who worked for the Matoba
that no longer exist, or whose masters are gone.
What do you think happens to exorcist families without an
heir who can see youkai?
Just because they can't see youkai,
the hatred the youkai have for them doesn't disappear.
Most clans are confronted with this problem and the terror that results.
Even the Natori clan, a famous family that had many enemies,
ran around desperately seeking heirs to adopt that could see youkai.
In the end, they abandoned the business.
I'm told that the clan became
terrified with every small disaster that a youkai was behind it.
And then Shuuichi-san, who can see them, was born.
I'm sure he got sick of his relatives.
And so the Matoba clan supports each other whenever a family no longer
has someone who can see youkai.
It can be a bother, sometimes, running the clan,
but there's quite a few advantages.
So now we're looking for more people to work for us.
So how about it?
Do you want to join the Matoba clan?
If you do, I can protect you.
You just told me to use whatever I can.
Are you serious?
That's true.
My apologies.
I often say the wrong thing.
Let me put it this way...
Master.
Yes.
I'll go check that out.
You wait here.
It's no good.
I don't even want to talk to him.
And I don't like the way this place feels.
It's filled with the presence of humans and youkai,
and I feel like I'm going to be sick.
What do you think, Sensei?
Sensei!
That's the Matoba clan for you.
This barrier is brutal, and I feel just awful.
Hang in there, Sensei.
After all you said...
Weren't you going to eat a bunch of them?
Don't talk about eating or drinking...
I've got heartburn...
Why are you talking like a middle-aged man who drank too much?
Even a family with a big mansion like this
can cease to exist, huh?
Oh, my. I haven't seen you before.
Sorry to scare you.
Are you human?
Don't worry. So am I.
From the look of things, did Matoba blackmail you into coming here?
Are you with the Matoba clan, as well?
Of course not.
I'm an exorcist, too,
but I haven't fallen far enough to join the Matoba.
I don't know what's going on with you, but cheer up.
Have some gum.
It'll calm you down, if you chew it.
No...
Kids shouldn't refuse their elders.
Thank you.
I don't like the Matoba, do you?
They always dress so weird.
Huh?
What was that?
I'm back, Natsume-kun.
A youkai leapt through the barrier and was causing chaos in the yard.
I took care of—
Oh, there you are.
Yes.
I thought I'd participate in today's meeting, too.
I have something secret to talk with you about, as well...
This is weird.
It's hard to tell, unless you look carefully.
It looks like she's moving, but she isn't...
except for her eyes.
Why are you wearing a mask?
It's no mask!
Get back!
There's a youkai on her face!
You'll pay for seeing through my disguise, kid.
You'll pay for interfering!
Splendid, Natsume-kun.
That's amazing.
It's almost impossible to tell when someone's being possessed.
A youkai who clings like a mask to people's faces and controls them?
Likely it's a type of Magatsumen.
Magatsumen?
Yes.
The Magatsumen possess someone,
then send out other masks to control people who can be of use to them.
You could call the original mask the parent,
and the one on this woman the child.
In other words, if we can't deal with the parent, this will never end.
Is she all right?
Yes, I suppose.
But who knows who will be attacked next?
From my perspective, it just looked like a normal woman talking.
But perhaps with eyes like yours,
you could see that her face was strange, like a mask.
I know you don't like exorcists,
but why not help us this one time?
Call it your good deed for the day.
The possessed people will keep attacking talented exorcists.
They might go after Natori-san eventually.
I think back then I wanted you to be my ally.
But now, I'm happy to be able to help you.
Just this once.
And I'm not doing it to help you.
I'm doing it for myself.
To know how I can protect the people I want to protect,
and what I'm supposed to fight, and how.
The meeting will now begin.
It's been so long!
You, too!
Things have been violent lately.
Look, the Master of the Matoba is here.
All of his shiki look so creepy.
I see one with him that's slightly different...
Matoba-sama, who is that?
Oh, that's my new shiki.
Don't mind him.
[Sign: Seal]
And he may not look it, but he's very short-tempered,
so stay away from him.
Thank you all for coming today.
I hope that this gives you a chance to establish new relationships
and exchange information on spells and youkai.
Please enjoy yourselves.
Matoba-san.
Thank you for inviting me.
Matoba-sama, I hope you'll hire us again.
Will I be able to find the person who's possessed by a youkai
in this crowd?
Just what I'd expect from a meeting sponsored by the Matoba.
There's a lot of big names here.
Is the young Natori here, come to think of it?
No, it seems he didn't come.
Good.
If he saw me like this, who knows what he'd say?
Hey, you.
You're Matoba-san's new shiki, huh?
Him?
He looks weak.
Exorcists?
Hey, pour me something to drink.
What can he do?
Do a trick!
Come on, do it!
What?
I feel something heavy on my foot...
What is this sack-shaped cat-like thing?!
Sensei!
Excuse me!
You're running?
You brat!
What happened?
Are you okay?
I think something brushed against my foot...
Sensei, do you feel better?
Yeah.
This mask nullifies the barrier.
Now let's go hit up that free sake!
Sensei, did you just hear a weird sound?
A sound?
Yeah.
Like a winding spring...
Something wrong?
Um, was there something weird outside just now?
Everything here is weird.
You're a shiki?
Who do you belong to?
No, um...
Natsume, what are you doing here?
Matoba-san.
I felt a strange presence outside.
I don't see anything.
What are you doing here, Matoba-san?
Call him Matoba-sama!
Never!
I'm not dressed like a shiki because I want to be!
It's for your own good.
If I walked around with you like Natori does
and the other exorcists noticed you, it would make things difficult.
And this makes it harder to find out who you are.
Oh, right.
Put out your hand.
I'll draw a protective talisman.
A talisman?
If you see someone suspicious and touch them with this,
this will reveal who they are.
If I just ran around and started touching everybody with this,
the Magatsumen might get scared and run away.
And my shiki are youkai, so I can't write it on them.
You really are helpful.
A talisman?
It looks like a tattoo.
Do you know a lot about Natori-san?
I've known him longer than you.
What is that lizard on his body?
Do you know?
I don't.
Even I don't know every youkai.
I see.
Come to think of it,
he says that lizard never goes to his left leg.
Why?
I don't know.
The simplest explanation would be that someday he's going lose it.
It's just a hypothetical.
But that's what youkai are.
They're creatures that cast a dark and uncertain shadow
on the human heart.
Humans are cowards, correct?
If youkai threaten their lives and hearts,
then it's our job as exorcists to get rid of them.
If you go back to that house,
won't you blame anything bad that happens there on yourself and the youkai?
Can you live with that?
I...
If you join me, I can protect you.
Enough of this.
No matter how many times you ask, I won't join you.
I have my own way of being connected with others.
That guy ticks me off.
I'm willing to eat him whenever you want.
Yeah.
Idiot.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Is something wrong?
Yes.
When I opened the break room, there was a person the floor.
Are you okay?
This is the inexperienced exorcist we saw yesterday.
Maybe he has a mask.
This is kind of embarrassing.
He's not possessed?
What happened?
It flew at me...
What did?
A face.
What's going on?
What did you do?
Get back!
No, I...
Liar!
A sack-shaped raccoon-like thing bit me!
Hey, wait!
What's wrong?
I don't know!
Something tripped me!
Looks like the parent Magatsumen
is sending out masks to look for more people to control.
Inexperienced people, like that, are easily controlled.
We need to find the parent mask that's causing this!
Sorry.
Um...
There was something on your cheek.
Did you see any flying faces?
What are you talking about? That's scary!
Excuse me.
Did you see any weird faces?
You're quite the friendly shiki, aren't you?
This is so inefficient!
That's Matoba for you.
Sure this isn't him playing a big trick on you?
With so many people and youkai here, he can't help it.
Let's just be glad there's a way.
This place is huge!
Reminds you of the Omibashira mansion, doesn't it?
Yeah.
But this place is different.
The aura here is totally different than a gathering of just youkai.
I heard exorcists are being attacked lately.
I heard someone from the Matoba clan was attacked, too.
Serves them right.
Hey, what if someone hears you?
The Matoba bring shame to exorcists everywhere.
That eyepatch is a sign that they don't keep their contracts.
That's why they can't make any decent youkai
or good people make a contract with them.
They either blackmail them or use spells to make them obey.
Only the ugly join them.
What are you talking about?
You didn't know this?
An ancestor of the Matoba
offered their right eye in exchange for a help with a job,
but they didn't keep their promise.
Ever since then, the masters of the Matoba clan
have had youkai come after their right eyes.
The eyepatch is to protect them from that, I've heard.
In the end, the few decent shiki they have now
were the ones they had when they were still the eleven great families.
Where is this sound coming from?
From the floor below?
That's a child mask it sent out.
The parent Magatsumen is below.
Right!
Oh, I saw you before.
You...
I found you!
I did it!
I'll crush the Matoba!
I'll crush them!
I'll crush all allies of the Matoba!
It's running! Sensei!
A giant dog?
A cat?
Run away, please!
This youkai possesses people!
What's that little oni doing?
Is that beast yours?
How dare you let it run wild in a place like this?
Get away while Sensei's got it pinned down!
Natsume!
Anyone weak, hide your face.
The youkai will possess you.
Amazing, Matoba-sama!
Matoba-sama! Matoba-sama!
Matoba-sama!
Is the person who was possessed by the parent Magatsumen all right?
He won't wake up for a while,
but that's his own fault.
How can you say that when he was being controlled?
In the case of the child masks, sure.
But he is one of the exorcists who oppose the Matoba clan.
If he was behind this, it's likely that
he wanted the power the Magatsumen has to control others,
and allowed it to possess him.
Many of those who work for the Matoba clan were victims.
I thought that it was a plot by someone to weaken us,
but I couldn't narrow down who it could be.
However, thanks to you,
I was able to find an enemy of the Matoba.
Don't worry about it.
Now we've been able to minimize the damage.
Did you know?
It's said that having a connection with a strong youkai
allows you to maintain a strong power.
So if you join the Matoba, I can protect you.
As long as I, the clan's master, have my right eye
targeted by a great Youkai.
There's something in your hair.
Come to think of it,
I wrote what was an unusually long letter for me.
But where did it go, I wonder?
But if you didn't read it, that's all.
Perhaps it's fate.
The Matoba shall behave like we always do.
If something happens, help us again, please.
Sensei, we're leaving.
Hmph. Finally?
How did you form a contract with such a great youkai?
I have no contract.
I made a promise.
Well done.
Oh dear, Natsume.
I was able to resolve this,
but things are always so dangerous around you.
Mr. Natsume Takashi
Are you sure about this?
Yes,
this is for the best.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
It Must Not Be Bound
My grandfather's magic circle is a forbidden technique?
Taki still believes.
The one who believed was kind, weren't they?
The youkai had left me proof that I met them, but...
It's... it's just as if...