Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Wait!
Where are you?
So heavy!
Move, child of man!
Sorry!
You okay?
I'm not okay!
I was almost crushed!
He's tiny.
Kid, you can see me even though you're human?
Okay, I'll make you my servant.
Perfect. Follow me.
That hurts! Let me go!
There you are!
Natsume of the Book of Friends!
You look delicious!
Oh, I see something tiny.
I'll eat you both!
He's got nothing to do with me!
So yummy!
Natsume!
Following a Narrow Path
You'll be fine here.
You're strong enough to punch out that youkai!
No...
Can you get home on your own?
How impressive.
Wh-What's wrong?
A scratch.
A scratch?
I knew it...
There's an outlaw-like scratch on my beautiful cap.
Sorry, was that me?
Dummy! Dummy!
How are you going to fix this?
Shuon-sama is a very noble person!
Sh-Shuon-sama?
Oww!
He won't like me if I look like an outlaw!
You've no choice, kid.
You're going to be my servant and work for me for a while.
Get lost, wimp.
He's mine.
Sensei!
When did you get here?
This is my walking path.
Throw the mushroom in the bushes and let's go home, Natsume.
Mushroom?
I'm an acquaintance of the great Shuon-sama, you rude thing!
Shuon?
Yes!
I finally might be able to see him again.
So I have to prepare for my plan.
And you have to help, kid.
Me?
You have to pay me back for the scratch on my cap.
What's with that bratty mushroom?
Let's cook and eat it!
Just try it, you mitarashi dango!
So I ended up helping the mushroom youkai.
I'm not a dango!
You look good!
I'm a sweet!
So, who's Shuon-sama?
What? You don't know him? How ignorant!
Well, I guess low-born humans like you
and low-ranking youkai wouldn't know them.
Fine, I'll tell you.
Ahem.
I was always noble and alone.
I spent my busy days fishing, eating, and sleeping.
So you're just sleeping and eating?
Sensei, let him finish.
Continue.
One day, I was caught by a hungry animal,
and almost eaten.
A youkai got caught by an animal?
What a wimp!
Just as I was prepared to be eaten...
Help me!
Someone help me!
There, there...
I don't know where he came from,
but he was a youkai like none I'd ever seen before.
Beautiful beast, eating a youkai will not calm your hunger.
Can you let him go?
I'm saved...
Aah... I did it again.
Animals have their own rules.
If I cannot allow them to follow them,
I still have a long way to go...
I don't understand,
but you saved me.
I owe you my life.
Thank you.
That was how I met Shuon-sama.
Ever since then,
I would sometimes see him in the forest and talk to him.
He probably came because
he enjoyed making small talk with me.
This is fun.
And we started to fish together
But Shuon-sama was strange.
There was never a hook on his line.
I told you, you can't catch anything without a hook.
I prefer it this way.
Fine.
I'll catch something and feed it to you.
Look, I caught something!
Dang it! It got away!
Don't laugh!
This is so much fun.
We're in luck!
The humans say that a wish on a shooting star will come true!
You won't make a wish?
Everything is alive.
Even the stars.
And then one night...
My friend, thank you for everything.
My fellows and I leave this land tonight.
I am on a journey of spiritual training.
I will return to the path of a hermit.
The path is narrow,
and we will never see each other again.
I am Shuon.
Farewell.
W-Wait!
Where are you going?
I like traveling, too!
I was so happy to have a friend!
Take me with you!
Take me! Take me, too!
I learned later that Shuon was so noble a being
that most aren't allowed to even speak to him.
And he saved me and called me his friend!
I was so jealous of the beautiful ones who were with him.
I wanted to join him.
Ever since then, I've journeyed in search of him,
and I heard that he'll be passing by that hill on his journey this evening,
so I hurried here.
That's stupid.
What will you do when you catch him?
I'll dress up like a monk
and join the end of the line,
and act like I belong there!
That's such a dumb idea, it's kind of refreshing.
So if I have this awful-looking mark,
they'll find me out!
I-Is that the problem?
Wake up.
Stop chasing weird dreams.
There's no way something like you
could be with somebody like that.
That's not true!
If I'm beautiful when I see him,
I'm sure Shuon-sama will...
I'm sure he'll take me with him.
If I didn't look so pathetic,
I'm sure...
So you're going to help me, kid!
Don't boss people around!
You lazy-butt mushroom!
I'm not a mushroom, you ball of fried lard!
I'm not a ball of lard!
I'm a noble...
Natsume Yuujinchou
So what are you going to do with these rocks?
Rub the powder into my cap to hide the scratch.
Oww!
You suck.
well, this is plenty, I guess.
Achoo!
What are you doing, you rice ball?!
What? You bratty mushroom!
I'm going to eat you after all!
Hey, Sensei!
I'll wear this beautiful flower...
How beautiful!
If I dye my clothes that color...
If I wear that shining stone...
Are you okay?
I'll do anything I can.
Just tell me.
Maybe I can use this nut for something.
It's fine to collect things,
but are you thinking about what you're using them for?
Oww...
What are you doing, fool?
Take care next time.
Filling in the scratch with tree sap?
Smart, kid.
Stay put until it dries, okay?
Yeah.
I'm tired...
Leave that spoiled brat alone.
But..
The issue isn't his appearance anyway.
They live in different worlds.
He may want to be with him, but sometimes it can't happen.
You're right.
Natsume of the Book of Friends!
We live in different worlds...
Did you have a nightmare?
No.
Hey, kid!
I brought you an akebia fruit.
You've got such strong spiritual power,
how can you collapse after just that?
He's tired.
He was up late last night returning names, and hasn't slept much.
Names?
Don't worry about it.
Anyway, eat something sweet and rest for a while.
Thank you.
You're nice.
I'm so busy.
I need to get the flowers ready.
I don't have nearly enough!
Sensei, let's eat this when I wake up.
Sheesh...
You'll help anyone who asks, won't you?
I can see Shuon-sama soon.
Will he remember me?
No. I'm sure, if he sees me, he'll be overjoyed,
and ask me to go with him!
Did you hear about Shuon-sama's group?
They say they'll be passing by this area soon.
Shall we go see them?
Fool!
We might invite divine punishment just going to see them.
Yeah?
But if we make some kind of offering,
they might grant our wish.
Offering?
Yeah...
Expensive books, robes, sake...
Perhaps a delicious child of man!
So yummy! Natsume!
I see...
A child of man... an offering...
Well, it'll be good medicine for him, once in a while.
It's done.
I look as beautiful as a messenger from God!
Now I can fit right in with his group!
Are you sure?
I think you'll stick out a lot..
I'm fine.
I'll uh...  use perspective tricks to fit in!
It's twilight.
They'll appear on the other side of this bamboo stand soon.
Yeah?
We'll be leaving then, so we don't get in the way.
No!
Stay with me!
Hey.
You're right.
You gave me that akebia fruit.
I guess I'll see this to the end.
It might be hard, but I'm sure...
I hope it goes well.
You seem down.
Is something wrong?
Oh, right.
Sensei, were you about to say something?
Nah.
It's Shuon-sama.
He and his entourage are coming!
The air changed.
Would you look at that...
Wow.
The light hurts my eyes.
He's at the front!
Stop it, mushroom!
They might think you're rude!
Shuon-sama wouldn't do that.
I mean his followers!
They won't let you get close!
Okay, here I go!
Are you okay?
Who's there?
This is the procession of Shuon-sama.
You will not be allowed to taint it.
I am Mitsuzara of the Shihara woods!
Please let me join Shuon-sama's procession!
You seem to be very small and pathetic.
Give up.
You have nothing with you.
What will you offer?
Well...
Nothing...
I have nothing to give...
But Shuon-sama saved my life.
I want to serve him to repay that debt!
Please take me with you!
I want to go with him!
I'll work hard at the spiritual training!
So please!
Please!
Mitsuzara-dono...
I apologize for my kindness to you.
As I said, our path is a narrow one.
I cannot take you with me.
My friend, return home.
Some wishes can't come true.
You find hope,
and it still doesn't work out...
And your heart continues to waver forever.
I'm sorry, child of man.
You did so much for me.
But I actually was going to...
What will you do now?
Go home?
I've nothing to do.
And if they can't take me because I'm too weak,
I'll train to become stronger!
You're still going to follow him?
I can't just copy his appearance after all.
Even if we live in different worlds,
I want to struggle to get closer to him.
I want to try and be worthy of being by his side.
You're the one from before...
Mitsuzara-dono,
we need no offering.
Complete the training we have written of in here, and join us.
I apologize for teasing you earlier.
Complete the training, if you have the resolve!
You okay?
There's no need to help me.
I'm fine!
I'm sure I can do it!
Right?
Yeah.
Yeah...
I'm sure you can.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Touko and Shigeru
The days are so peaceful and so calm.
Together forever...
When we met, that child was so thin,
and looked so bored.
That crow always flies alone.
Which is it?