Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
I'm hungry.
Want to get something on the way back?
Your treat.
Why?
Hey, you two.
You'd better get back soon. It's going to rain.
It's sunny out.
It was on the weather report this morning.
They say the autumn sky's as fickle as a woman's heart, right?
You've sure got your act together, Sasada.
Okay, see you.
Natsume, Nishimura.
Let's go home.
It really did rain!
It doesn't look like it'll let up for a while.
What do you want to do?
Run?
Okay!
It's raining harder!
Here, take this.
I've got another one.
You don't have to give it back.
B-But...
I'm getting on that bus.
W-Wait!
Good for you, Nishimura.
Your face is red.
Get in!
Three boys together?
Just do it!
It's cold!
She gave it to you, right?
A towel?
Give it back.
A kid.
No, a youkai?
Is this yours?
What are you doing, Natsume?
You get colds easier than anyone in the world.
Try to stay out of the rain.
Come on!
What's with that towel?
Oh, no...
Come on!
You too, Kitamoto! Get in here!
Mischievous Rain
So I brought the towel with me.
What a scummy-looking towel.
Okay, I'll be going.
Going where?
To give it back.
What a pain. Leave it be.
I can't do that.
And I don't want her coming here to get it back.
Before that happens—
She's here already!
Sensei, how was she able to get in so easily?
I make it easy to get in because there are
wimpy youkai who come to get their names back.
If I chased them away, you'd get mad!
A child's clogs?
Is it that a youkai, then?
Where are you?
I've got what you're looking for.
Let me have that!
We just need to throw it out into the yard or something!
Stop it, Sensei.
What if we make her mad?
She's not that powerful.
Takashi-kun, put your wet uniform out, okay?
Okay!
Let's head back to my room for now.
But since the other two boys saw the towel,
it originally belonged to a human.
Something's there.
I know.
Why don't I get some tea.
I'll just leave this towel here.
Let's go, Sensei.
There it is.
I'm so glad.
So it was a kid...
Hey, little girl!
Take it and go!
A mochi monster!
Sensei, don't scare her like that!
Come on, get out of there!
How long are you going to stay in my territory?
Sensei, get back for a second.
Can you hear me?
Sorry for scaring you.
And for taking your towel.
I won't hurt you, so take it and go, all right?
Are you Natsume?
She sounds meaner than I expected.
Yes.
So the rumors were true,
and you can really see youkai, and see me?
Do you need something from me?
That's right.
I was looking for you to ask you something,
when my towel was blown away.
Just like you said, this belongs to a human.
I want to give it back to its owner.
Look for them with me.
Look for them?
He's a handsome man who looks like this.
Find him for me.
Impossible.
There's nobody else as handsome as him.
I'm sure he'll be easy to find.
Then you can find him yourself, right?
I have no duty to help you.
If there's anybody you want to put a curse on,
I'll do my best to take care of them, so please.
I'm sorry. I can't help you.
Please.
I don't know what else to do.
And like usual,
I don't know what to do at a time like this either.
Can you come out of there?
I can at least hear you out—
Really? You mean it, Natsume-sama?
Yeah.
Then let's go home, Natsume-sama.
Where?
Hey, you!
No more of this!
Put that down!
Get lost, mochi monster!
What did you call me?
Stop it!
Good morning.
Morning, Takashi.
Morning, Takashi-kun.
Um, I'm going out for a little today.
I see. See you later.
Take care.
Right.
It's my first time visiting this town.
It's a little further up.
She came all that way alone in search from me?
It's dangerous.
Here.
No, I...
You could just get lost in the crowd and disappear.
Oh, I guess I could.
We're a long way outside town.
Look.
It was at that "bus stop" thing where I met him.
That's it, huh?
Looks pretty old.
Most of the time, when that's the case...
When did you first meet them?
About 50 years ago.
He came here for years,
but about a year ago, he suddenly stopped coming.
Then he was here until a while ago?
If he used that bus stop for fifty years,
he might live around here.
He might've moved, but if I can find his old house...
If I...
If I can see him one more time,
this time I have to give it back.
If I knew his name I could ask someone, but...
Sorry.
I'm going to take a little break.
Y-You're so weak!
Actually, I've heard that people can get sick just from standing in the rain.
H-Hang in there, Natsume-sama!
You can't die here!
I'm fine.
Thank you.
I don't know anything about humans.
Natsume-sama, how long do humans live?
Is he alive, do you think?
I'm sorry.
I don't know.
But if you want to see him, let's look.
Okay!
All right.
If something is lost,
I think it's important to know it.
This way!
I smell him!
This is the smell.
Look!
It's coming from that girl!
You're looking for an old man, right?
A man. A handsome man.
Well, you smell like Reiko, too.
I see.
Maybe that's his granddaughter?
She's leaving!
Excuse me, um...
Yes?
Do you have a grandfather?
Oh no. I wasn't thinking...
Um...
I used to see him at the bus stop up ahead all the time,
but I haven't seen him lately, so I've been worried.
Nanako!
What's wrong?
Excuse me.
Was he hitting on you?
Stop it.
I'm sorry.
I failed at talking to her.
But I'll come back and try again.
Thank you.
Natsume Yuujinchou
What's wrong?
Even you're looking glum.
Did you catch cold in the rain yesterday?
Oh, no...
Leave us alone!
Right, right.
Nishimura?
Did something happen?
I went to return her umbrella.
Umbrella?
That red umbrella?
Yeah.
I left early this morning and waited at the spot where I met her.
Were you able to give it back?
Yes.
Then you were able to see her.
I was, but...
She was...
She was with her boyfriend!
I gave it back and she said,
"Thanks so much!"
She was smiling...
Nishimura.
I'll take you out to eat somewhere.
Thanks.
There she is.
Excuse me.
I won't take up a lot of your time.
Will you talk to me?
That bus stop—
You're lying.
That's a lie.
Why are you lying?
I asked my grandfather and he said he'd never
met a boy who looked like you.
What are you thinking...
Good...
He's doing well, then?
Anyway, that's how it is.
Don't talk to me anymore.
Wait.
Thank you, Natsume-sama.
I'm glad.
He's still alive.
That's enough for me.
I'm sorry, Natsume-sama.
She called you a liar because of me.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
Anyway, tell me about who you're looking for.
It was a rainy day...
The rain felt so good,
and I was running around and having fun.
And then...
Hey.
What are you doing?
You'll catch cold.
This way.
You can see me?
Come on. This way.
Where are you from?
Can you make it home?
Of course.
I live right nearby.
I see.
You can have that towel.
So wipe yourself down and don't catch cold.
I have to go.
See you.
So I took the towel home.
And it was warm, and soft...
It felt to me like something incredibly wonderful.
I went the next day to give it back.
Hey, thanks for yesterday.
I've come to give back what you gave... me...
Hey!
I was so happy that I'd been able to talk to him
that I'd forgotten...
It's very rare for humans to be able to see me or other youkai.
Some strong ones, or beast youkai,
can deliberately show themselves.
But weak ones like me can only be seen during sunshowers,
or on certain beautiful spring days, when the weather is mischievous.
Perhaps for me, that rainy day was the one time it would happen.
Every time it rained after that,
I went to that bus stop.
I thought that if I played in the rain, he might see me again.
That someday he'd come over to me, just once... just one more time.
Hey, look over here!
If I'd wanted to give back the towel,
I could've just set it down and left.
But for years, and years,
as I stood there in the rain looking at him,
I couldn't do it.
But it's okay now.
Just knowing that he's safe
makes the pain from not being able to see him
over the past year much less.
Wait here.
Natsume-sama?
Sensei, wait with her!
Idiot!
Excuse me!
What is your problem?
Do you need something else—
My name is Natsume Takashi.
To tell you the truth, someone I know was helped
a lot by your grandfather.
They wanted to see him themselves,
but they couldn't come here.
They couldn't?
Are they sick, too?
My grandfather is in the hospital.
In the hospital?
You're really worried about him, aren't you?
It's okay. He just has a cold.
He should be leaving the hospital soon.
His granddaughter says he's at Yamato Hospital #2,
and his name is Kurosaki Sougo-san.
Sougo-san.
Let's go tomorrow and give back the towel.
Okay!
Are you sure you want to stay there?
This is where I feel calmest.
Okay, goodnight.
Goodnight, Natsume-sama.
I'm so tired.
We should go to bed, too.
Yeah.
Even if we do go, he probably won't be able to see her...
Should I go borrow that circle that Taki's grandfather
left her that lets her see Youkai?
No. That doesn't always work.
You might need the same power that Taki and Tanuma have to see them.
And that thing hurt Taki.
People and youkai...
If they'd never interacted,
they never would have suffered.
Sensei...
Sensei?
Did you go to sleep?
Sensei.
Yamato Hospital #2
Go give him this, Natsume-sama.
You're not going?
If I see him,
it might weaken my resolve again.
And if he sees this towel and remembers me...
I'd be so happy I'd cry.
Okay.
I'll be back.
A person meets many people in their lifetime.
Unlike a youkai, who may remember a single encounter forever,
they meet new people, and say goodbye to others behind,
at dizzying speed.
Kurosaki Sougo
Hello.
My name is Natsume Takashi.
I'm sorry for coming by so suddenly.
Oh, my granddaughter told me.
My aunt tells me that when she was little, you lent her this.
It bothered her that she was never able to return it to you.
Oh my. I see.
Do you remember?
When you gave her that towel?
It was a rainy day, at a bus stop...
She was a little girl.
I'm afraid I don't.
But thank you anyway.
I thought she'd come.
Sougo-san.
Oh my. It's raining.
Yes.
But I'm sure it will stop soon.
Farewell.
I'm going home, Natsume-sama.
Thank you.
Yamato Hospital #2
Hello.
I'm Natsume, I was here yesterday.
Oh my.
I'm sorry.
Could you give me something to show that you received the towel?
It doesn't matter what.
I just want something to give her.
That's true.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I know. How about this?
There's still one I haven't used yet...
Oh, here it is.
Thank you.
Sheesh!
Are you still here?
Can you hear me?
There's something I want to give you.
Natsume-sama?
Sougo-san gave me this as a sign that he received the towel.
He says it's for you.
It's so pretty.
It's for me?
Thank you, Natsume-sama!
I'm so glad the weather's clear today.
I'm so glad this pretty towel didn't get wet.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Letter From the Exorcist
I feel bad about getting you involved in that exorcism business.
I wanted your help back then.
Is it okay to talk to Natori-san about Matoba-san's letter?
I don't want to get involved with them.
Let us go, then.