Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
Nyanko-sensei!
Where are you going?
Heading home, Natsume?
There was something that's been bugging me.
Bugging you?
Yeah. I'm going to go check it out.
Be a good kid and stay at home!
Hey, Sensei!
Bugging him?
He's not going to check out the new sweets at Nanatsujiya, is he?
Hey, Natsume.
Nishimura?
What are you doing here?
Cram school.
What a pain, though.
Wait, who were you talking to?
I thought I heard what sounded like an old man's voice.
No. I was talking to myself.
Oh yeah?
I want to skip school.
It's a waste, right? You're paying tuition.
Then you want to go for me?
No.
I knew it.
But this cram school has this really cute girl!
Her hair's long and um... silky!
And the way she talks and everything, she's just so elegant!
But then this fall she ended up taking a different course than me.
I'm so disappointed.
To protect these peaceful days,
the fact that I can see youkai needs to be a secret.
I'm back.
Welcome back, Takashi-kun.
Can you check the mail for me?
Sure.
For me?
Mr. Natsume Takashi
But this doesn't have an address or a stamp.
Matoba
Mr. Natsume Takashi
The Letter from the Exorcist
Matoba
Matoba...
Matoba is that clan of exorcists, right?
Takashi-kun?
Is something wrong?
No.
Um...
I'm going to go look for Nyanko-sensei.
Matoba-san sent me a letter?
What is it?
A scream?
Somebody's being attacked by a youkai!
Watch out!
I was able to seal it just fine.
Exorcising youkai is easier than I thought.
An exorcist?
The letter!
It was blown away?
That's bad. Did I drop it around here?
Is someone there?
Oh, it's just a cat.
Well, whatever. On to the next one.
The letter... the letter...
Where is it? Oh no.
It's no good.
I can't find it.
Hey, Natsume.
What are you doing?
What? A letter from Matoba?
Yeah.
Perfect.
There's no need to read a letter from him.
I wish I'd ripped it up and thrown it away.
Ignore it.
I can't do that...
What are you doing here anyway?
I was patrolling because I felt an ominous presence over the past few days.
And I ran into an inexperienced exorcist sealing a youkai into a pot.
So that cat was you?
You saved me.
This is a problem though.
That half-assed exorcist.
He left an imperfectly-sealed youkai here.
You can sense it, right?
A raging youkai, infuriated at being locked away?
The way this is sealed, the youkai's going to break out
and go on a rampage in two or three days.
No...
What can we do?
We might need to reseal it or it will be dangerous.
Reseal it?
How?
This is close to my home and the route Nishimura takes to go to school.
Hey, Natsume!
Sensei,
I'm going on a short trip.
Will you come with me?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Well? Youkai that weak are easy.
Splendid.
Young, talented people like you make valuable partners.
Of course.
Oh, right. There's a meeting soon.
I hope you'll come.
The note he gave me before said that he lives in a condo around here.
Looks like the perfect place for a show-off.
He's not picking up his phone either.
Maybe he's not home.
If we wait here, he'll come back later.
What?
Why are you so haphazard?
I can't help it.
I couldn't think of any other ideas.
Hey.
Hiiragi?
I came down to see what the fuss was.
It was you, Natsume?
What are you doing here?
Actually,
I wanted to talk to Natori-san about a pot with a youkai sealed in it.
I'm sorry for coming over so suddenly.
Talk to him?
To Natori?
I see. Welcome.
Natori is in his room.
He's cut off his "phone", if that's what they're called, and is fast asleep.
Keep pressing the number for his room.
He'll answer eventually.
Yes?
Excuse me, Natori-san.
It's Natsume.
N-Natsume?
W-Wait a second!
No, come up!
Welcome.
Now come in.
Sorry to interrupt your rest.
There's nothing here, but come in.
Thanks for coming.
That's right.
There's not much here.
Pretty empty, right?
This is just a room I borrow for work.
All I ever use it for is sleeping.
Oh, sit down.
Thank you.
My home's a little bit away,
but the most I ever do is go there to get tools for work.
Really?
That's the bedroom, huh?
What's this room?
I'll make some tea.
I see. This is a very simplistic seal.
Lately there's a lot of people who learn the knowledge
of how to do it and try their hands,
and people looking for talented successors.
Successors?
So now there's quite a few people who do
these things to test their strength and show off their skills.
We exorcists are having some arguments over it.
I'm sorry to only rely on you when it helps me.
Why?
I'm happy.
I'll reseal it. Will you help me?
Yes.
I'll get my tools ready.
You wait here.
Hiiragi, help me.
Yes, sir.
This sounds fun. I'll go, too.
Testing their strength and showing off their skills.
There are exorcists like that, huh?
What did Matoba-san's letter say?
Should I ask Natori-san?
This is bad.
The presence inside is getting stronger.
Natori-san, your phone.
The person you are calling is unavailable.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Clan of accursed paper-wielders,
accept the curse of the abandoned.
What is this?
He's mumbling something.
Accept the curse of the oppressed.
Is it some kind of spell?
Accept the curse of the sealed.
Fools who inherit accursed karma,
be ye cursed.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume!
Natori-san!
The pot's going to shatter!
I'm ready!
Let it go and head right into my circle!
Right!
Let's go!
What moves in thy presence is not wind...
Be thee sealed!
For you are different than they!
All done.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Your room's a mess now.
It's fine.
But what was that call?
I told you. Things are difficult now.
Sometimes people in the same line of work send curses to harass me.
So when I sleep, I unplug the phone.
This time, that pot happened to respond to that curse.
But exorcists are people, right?
Why would they do something so terrible?
I told you before, right?
The Natori clan was an old clan of exorcists.
Eventually people who could see the youkai stopped being born.
Its descendants gave up the business.
But I'm back in business now.
Some of the other exorcists don't like that.
Really?
They used to make fun of us for running away,
and now someone as talented as me is back.
They're probably quite jealous.
They may have a history of rivalry with the Natori clan dating back generations.
It's scary to think that those old hatreds survive.
But when I decided to go into the family's line of work,
I was ready for it.
But...
Lately, there's been a lot of problems going on even between exorcists.
Some of them have started dabbling in forbidden techniques.
Forbidden techniques?
Even in this business,
there are quite a few rules between exorcists.
Rules?
For instance, techniques that show youkai to people who can't normally see them.
So Taki's grandfather's circle is a forbidden technique?
It may seem quite convenient at first glance,
but there are probably all kinds of nasty side-effects.
Of course,
I'm told that one no one's ever actually mastered such a technique.
I had no idea that circle was such a thing...
There are also certain methods of exorcisms and contracts that are forbidden.
Contracts?
Some of the most dangerous can even curse people who aren't involved.
For example...
When an exorcist makes a contract of mastery with a youkai,
you have to give them a fake name,
and never bind their real name, for instance.
If you bind their real name,
even your normal speech becomes words that they must obey.
There are also cruel spells that allow you
to crush their name and take their life.
Well, that's another technique that takes a lot of power and may not actually exist...
Natsume?
What's wrong, Natsume?
Nothing.
These days I feel bad about getting you caught up in the exorcism business.
I think back then I wanted you to be my ally.
I wanted your help.
But now, I'm happy to be able to help you.
Yeah.
You're sure you don't want me to walk you home?
Thank you.
There are a lot of different types of exorcists,
but I'm glad I got to talk to Natori-san.
I feel bad about getting you caught up in it...
In the end, I didn't get to talk to him about Matoba-san.
But maybe it's something I have to overcome myself.
Matoba
Oh my.
You're returning home late.
Did you read my request?
I've come to get you.
Matoba-san.
Request?
Mr. Natsume Takashi
That letter...
I didn't read it.
The wind blew it away and I lost it.
You make excuses like a little child.
It may not sound true, but it is.
This is a problem.
I'm willing to tell you here,
but I have a car waiting nearby.
Go with him, Natsume.
The more people around, the more filling my meal.
Sensei!
That would be a problem.
I'm not here as an enemy.
Shall we go for a walk?
I found a place nearby that seems appropriate.
Hey, Natsume.
Are you sure it's okay to follow him?
What if I didn't,
and he did something weird in front of the Fujiwaras?
Don't worry.
I'll send you back safely.
The real thing is tomorrow.
The real thing?
The meeting.
Lately, talented shamans have been being attacked by someone.
It's a problem for the Matoba clan as well.
And when we looked into it,
it seems that the person behind it is an exorcist.
And to make things more difficult,
the exorcist is likely being controlled by a youkai.
We'd have to find him from among our fellow exorcists.
And it's hard to see when somebody's possessed by an youkai.
It's proving difficult.
Given the issues we're having,
we decided it would be best to gather all the talented exorcists in one place
and see what happens.
That's why you're having the meeting?
When you don't know who's going to be attacked, or when,
isn't that dangerous?
Yes.
It's stupid to do something with no chance of victory.
We wouldn't bother.
So I sent you a request for your help.
You're not an exorcist, but you're quite powerful.
You'll help, yes?
Why would I accept a selfish request for you?
Think about it for a night.
I'll be back in the morning.
You can't just—
I don't want you coming to my house, either!
Why?
You haven't told the two of them about your power?
I'll tell them then.
I'll tell them all the terrifying things you've seen,
and the terrible things you've endured,
and that they continue to this day,
and that the two of them lack the power to protect you.
Stop it!
Anyway,
just stay away from my house.
I'm leaving.
I'll be waiting here tomorrow at noon.
If you're not here, I'll come to get you.
To much has happened today. I'm tired.
What will you do?
I don't want to get involved with Matoba-san.
I can't let him find out about the Book of Friends.
But...
If you're not here, I'll come to get you.
Talented shamans being attacked by someone, huh?
Was the one who attacked Natori-san maybe...
Takashi-kun, dinner!
Coming!
Touko-san, this rice is delicious.
Sakamoto-san gave me some maitake mushrooms.
There's still lots left.
Maybe we'll make stew next.
I see.
We have to get him something as thanks.
That's right.
You eat a lot too, Takashi-kun.
Yeah.
Oh, right.
Once my work calms down,
why don't we all go pick grapes?
How about it, Takashi?
Yes, I'd love to.
If we wait for things to calm down at your work, Shigeru-san,
it'll be next year.
That's so cruel, Touko-san.
Right?
To protect these peaceful days...
Oh, thanks.
Oh. You came after all.
Though you don't seem happy about it.
Of course.
Let us go, then.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shadow of
Linked Chains
If you join us, I can protect you.
How can I protect the
things I want to protect?
What am I supposed to fight?
I want to know.
You really are convenient.
You anger me.
Can I eat him, Natsume?