Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
That was heavy.
Thanks for helping me with that.
Sure thing.
I've gotta go get the textbooks.
It's hard doing after-school cleanup.
Nishimura, that...
Shouldn't we clean that drawing off the blackboard?
Drawing?
On the blackboard?
I'm heading out.
"Save..." "Take you..."
Natsume-kun?
It Must Not Be Bound
I see.
In the Earth Science classroom?
It's hard seeing things that
nobody else sees, huh?
Actually, lately a youkai's been showing up at my house.
Wait a second.
You can't see them, can you?
That's right.
About a week ago I started feeling a presence inside my house.
I heard sounds like something running around,
or tripping...
And then I started hearing voices in my dreams.
I want to go home.
Help me!
I couldn't really hear them,
but they were crying desperately for someone,
searching for someone, as if they were in extreme grief...
I didn't want to do anything risky,
but I thought that maybe another
youkai was suffering because of what my grandfather did.
So I decided to use the circle that my grandfather left me,
that let him see youkai.
Is anyone there?
Little girl.
Can you see me?
It's huge!
Calm down! Calm down!
If you can hear my voice,
I want you to help me.
I'm sorry, child of man.
I've no intention of frightening you.
I tried to take a shortcut,
and found myself trapped in this mansion.
My grandpa put up a lot of talismans and things when he was still alive,
so I looked at where the spells and talismans were,
1st floor
This room
2nd floor
Bath
Toilet
Kitchen
and drew him a map.
I hope you can make it out.
If I do,
I will leave a branch of flowers by the gate,
as a symbol that I have succeeded.
I was so happy.
I realized that sometimes I could save someone with that circle.
I'm glad.
Yeah.
Taki still believes that not all encounters with inhuman things have to be scary.
She's right.
But...
Hey, Natsume, open this can for me.
Sensei?
S-S-Shiny-Fluffy-Sensei!
Stop it!
That was a meal.
Come to think of it,
I smelled youkai on that girl.
Oh, actually...
She used her circle to help a youkai?
Yeah. I wonder if that's where the smell came from.
I don't know about that.
What do you mean, Sensei?
That smell was still new.
I bet she hasn't seen it yet.
Let's go to Taki's house.
I also need to tell her that that circle might be a forbidden technique.
Taki
Hello?
Natsume-kun?
Taki, sorry for just showing up all of a sudden.
There's something I wanted to talk to you about...
Do you know her?
She's pretty.
Oh, Taki.
I don't mean to scare you, but...
Can't you tell, little girl?
It's me, Nyanko-Sensei.
He was worried that it might cause problems for you
if the neighbors saw a boy coming over alone.
And in this form you're not likely to squeeze me.
You're so mean, Sensei.
Natsume-kun?
Oh, sorry.
Taki, I have to talk to you about your grandfather's circle—
Hey, Taki.
I'll give you a warning as thanks for this delicious shiruko.
Your grandfather's circle is something called a "forbidden technique".
Sensei!
Of course, that's only what some people called exorcists say.
If they find out, you'll have trouble on your hands.
You'll be better off just getting rid of it, or throwing it in the trash.
My grandfather's circle
is a forbidden technique?
Taki?
Natsume-kun?
Taki, what was the youkai that left like?
It was big...
Kind of hairy...
But why?
So it was the thing I saw at school?
It's upstairs.
Taki, there is still a youkai presence in this house.
That youkai is back, then?
Where is it?
This way, Natsume!
Stop moving around!
Gotcha!
Let me go!
No way.
Natsume-kun...
Taki, you should get back.
If you won't let me go, then...
Now you've done it, rat!
Stop it, Sensei!
So was the youkai presence in my house the youkai that's right there now?
I can't see it.
Oh, no, Taki.
It's over here.
So what were you doing?
I'm a travel rabbit, as you can see.
My friend and I were traveling on a journey
where we did nothing but eat and sleep.
You're a rabbit?
You look like a rat.
Ignorant idiot!
You can tell if I'm a rat or a bunny by looking at my tail, right?
Yeah, it's cute.
What?
What's cute?
Oh, um, this youkai looks like a rat.
But it's actually a rab—
Can't you pay attention to me, child of men?
As we were traveling, we saw a big hairy youkai go into this house.
There were invisible walls and endless hallways,
and eventually I got separated from my friend.
And ever since then, I've been looking for them.
Then the voice Taki heard calling for someone came from this youkai?
What's your friend like?
A traveling rabbit like me.
Then the hairy youkai and two rabbits came inside this house and got lost?
Natsume-kun?
Yeah.
So if we find your friend rabbit, you'll leave, right?
Of course.
What sort of youkai would willingly hang out with humans?
Especially the ones who use magic...
They're the worst sort!
Are you okay, Natsume-kun?
What did the youkai say?
It says it'll leave if it finds its friend.
Mr. Rabbit, I'm sorry this house is so strange.
We'll find your friend,
so hang in there a while, okay?
You help too, Sensei?
I'll make sure to thank you.
Yes! You know just how to deal with me!
But what did the one at school want?
Hey, do you know what happened to the hairy youkai?
Sometimes it comes back and looks through the window, actually.
That one, right there.
A plum flower?
At this time of year?
That's the flower branch the youkai left.
Pretty, huh?
Yeah.
I think it's lasted a long time,
but the flowers are probably going to fall soon.
I was so happy that a youkai left a sign that we met, too.
It makes me a little sad.
Taki, get away from the window!
Nyanko-sense, take care of her.
Taki, you stay here.
Natsume-kun!
You're the youkai that Taki let out of her house, right?
Wait!
Why are you still hanging around Taki?
The words on the blackboard were your doing too, right?
What did you mean you're lost? Or that you were taken?
Child, did you read that?
Natsume Yuujinchou
A child of man read that...
How pathetic! How pathetic!
What was that?
You look straight into my eyes too, don't you?
Yes, it must be fate that someone's appeared
who can listen to my story.
What I'm about to tell you is a secret, child.
I can't promise that.
For a long time I lived in an ancient tree in the north,
but humans cut it down.
No matter how much I screamed in my rage,
no one heard me.
There is a tree on a southern mountain that is the twin of the one I lived in.
I thought that I could live there, but...
On my way I cut through this house and found myself trapped.
My heart was filled with irritation and anger, but...
Is someone there?
She was a strange girl who used a strange technique.
She was shaking,
but when I asked her for help...
I saw the eyes of a human for the first time.
They were so... so...
Hey, Natsume.
How long you gonna keep talking to that thing?
Let's find the rabbit and split.
What is that creature that looks like a ball of wool?
What did you say?
What does he mean by "rabbit"?
I'm no ball of wool! I'm a noble youkai! Don't ignore me!
Two youkai followed you in.
Taki's worried about them,
so I want to find them and help them escape.
Excellent. I'll help.
I was looking for a way to repay the girl for letting me out.
Natsume-kun?
Is everything okay?
Do I still need to stay away from the window?
Oh, no.
Taki, it's okay now.
You're safe, right, Natsume-kun?
Yeah, I'm fine.
And what's here is—
Silence, child.
Another word and I snap your neck.
Natsume-kun?
There aren't many places I can go,
but thankfully I have the map the girl gave me.
That youkai...
it's like...
What's wrong, Natsume?
No, it's nothing.
Got it.
We just need to look for places that youkai could get lost in, right?
No, you can't see them...
No, I'll help too.
It's because of the spell cast on this house anyway.
Man, this house is...
Huge.
Taki, what are you doing?
There's a tin under this...
Got it!
I got it, Natsume-kun, Sensei!
Well?
Is there a rabbit in it?
There isn't, huh?
Okay, the second floor!
I'll search the second floor, too!
What's wrong?
No...
Are you hurt?
It's okay.
I just cut myself on the lid of the tin...
No, Taki.
Wash and disinfect it.
But...
Th-That's right!
I'm told humans are surprisingly weak!
Go purify your wound, now!
Idiot.
You can yell, but she can't hear your voice.
Rabbit #1 tells you to go clean it up, too.
Thanks.
I'll be right back.
Taki seems to feel
responsible for the forbidden technique and her grandfather, huh?
Ooh. I couldn't go this way, but if I'm with you, I can.
It's because you're here as an invited guest.
It seems that, if I'm with you, I can go more places.
Is that how it works?
Taki's grandpa is amazing.
It's a bother, though.
But that may just show how much
the master of this house wanted to protect it.
The purpose of these techniques
is normally to allow you to do things you can't do on your own.
For some people they're a medicine, and for others, a poison.
Poison?
Hey, child!
Over here, child.
There wasn't a door here a minute ago.
It was hidden with magic.
It appeared when I was searching the wall.
Okay.
Ready...
It moved!
Takemitsu! Are you here?
Awayuki?
There he is!
Taki, we found him!
Awayuki, you're okay?
I'm so glad!
I'm sorry, Takemitsu!
I... I...
I lead us inside a human house without really knowing what they were...
I'm sorry, Takemitsu!
They helped us find you.
So did the daughter of this house.
What? A human helped?
I no longer hate humans.
But I'll never get near one again,
if it puts my friend in danger.
Okay.
I'll take them out of the house.
Wait. Taki still isn't...
Even if she does come, she can't see us.
Even if she can't see you, she can still say goodb—
If you can't see us, we may as well not exist.
The bond between us was a meaningless one to begin with.
You can see us, so you know that better than anyone.
That's...
Is the forbidden technique you were speaking of that circle?
Whoever forbid it was right.
Whoever forbid it was kind.
Ever since I went inside that circle
and saw a human's eyes for the first time...
Ever since I saw her eyes...
For some reason, it's been so hard for me to leave.
But even if I stay here,
I feel so strangely sad and lonely...
Natsume-kun, did you find them?
Wait.
At least leave her a message.
Don't you have something to say to Taki?
I have a request of you.
I had no intention of telling her,
but the feelings within me just wouldn't stop,
so I gave them an outlet.
Even if you were able to read it, please...
Please keep it a secret.
Natsume-kun?
Taki?
Natsume-kun!
Natsume-kun, are you okay?
Don't worry.
The youkai's energy when it left was just a little too much for him.
Natsume-kun.
Taki...
Goodbye! Goodbye! Children of men, thank you!
It's faint, but I can still hear it.
The rabbits and that youkai are saying goodbye.
They said thank you.
I wish I could let you hear it too,
but only I can.
I see.
I'm glad.
Then the rabbits were able to get out, huh?
Yeah.
So the youkai that appeared in the circle helped, too?
Thank you, Natsume-kun.
Even if it's dangerous,
my grandfather's circle is still my treasure.
Yeah, that's right.
Wh...When I was lost... you...
When I was lost, you saved me.
If I could, I would take you with me.
I told myself, knowing it was impossible,
that I would love to see the beautiful mountains,
the beautiful valleys,
together with you.
What do humans call this feeling?
It was...
It was just as if...
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Soundless Valley
Reiko, you're finally here.
What the heck is this thing?
More guests! I love it when it's lively!
I'm sorry. I'm not Reiko!
Got it. Leave it to me.
I'll bring back a super-duper large bunch of fish!
Go!