Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Natsume-sama!
Natsume Reiko-sama!
My name...
Sure.
But I'm not Reiko.
No. You are Natsume Reiko-sama.
I am not.
I'm Takashi, her grandson.
Reiko-san is...
No, you're Natsume.
You're Natsume Reiko.
I am not...
That scared me.
What happened, Natsume?
A ghost... a woman...
A ghost... a woman?
Was she hot?
Was it a hot ghost?
Well?
Unchanging Form
What, Natsume-kun?
You were asleep after sixth period?
I can't believe it.
Was there something good on TV last night?
No...
I'm so hungry. I want some chestnut rice!
Ever since I was little, I've sometimes seen strange things.
Other people don't seem to be able to see them.
I think they're what people call "youkai."
My grandmother, Natsume Reiko, could see them just like me.
She would battle the youkai and win,
and then make them write their names down for her.
See you tomorrow!
I inherited the book with their names, and that lets me control them.
It's called "The Book of Friends."
I spend my days returning the names to the youkai who visit me.
What is your problem?
Why do you always do this?
Am I imagining that?
A pot?
Pots don't normally roll vertically!
You got chased by a pot?
Yeah.
I may have just run into one that was rolling.
You managed to get away from it,
so it can't be that powerful.
I hope so.
Come to think of it,
how did Reiko protect herself?
Whenever I give back a name,
I always see the same thing: my grandmother's smile.
No matter how many times I do it,
I always see her by herself.
Okay, I'll be back later!
Thanks!
Natsume, what's that?
Are those round things sweets?
Buy me sweets!
Come on, Sensei. Look.
Buy them!
Sweets!
Look! That watch shop...
That's right.
My kid finally made it into that school.
I feel so relieved!
I'm jealous.
Mine's got exams next year and they aren't doing anything.
You know them?
Yeah.
I've met them when my relatives got together.
Great. Let's go, Natsume.
Wait, Sensei.
This isn't a chance I get often.
I'll go talk to them.
What?
Bye.
Yeah.
Hello.
Oh dear.
It's been a long time.
I'm Natsume Takashi.
You were very kind to me before.
Natsume?
Oh my.
Where do you live now?
I'm sorry. We were... you know.
No, everything's calmed down.
I'm sorry for everything I did back then.
That's right.
Just because you're a kid doesn't mean you can play by scaring
everyone around you.
Yes. I'm sorry.
So, there's something I wanted to ask you.
Do you know anyone who would know about
my grandmother on my mother's side?
The Natsume family?
I'd like to know about my relatives on my mother's side, too.
But you know, the Natsume family had no relatives for two generations.
That's why you came to us, right?
I remember they were very strange,
and not quite well in the head.
Especially when your mother was born...
I'm sorry.
You're right.
I'm sorry for asking something that's so difficult to talk about.
Thank you.
I see.
Well, take care.
Hey, Natsume.
Natsume.
T-Tanuma!
What are you doing here?
I was doing some shopping over there.
Are you okay, Natsume?
D-Did you hear that?
No, but I kind of saw.
Who was that?
No, sorry.
I didn't mean...
No, please listen, actually.
She's a relative on my father's side.
I wanted to ask about my grandmother,
but they almost always say the same thing.
She could see youkai, like me.
So they say she was weird,
or not right in the head.
And I remember hearing when I was young that Reiko-san,
my grandmother, had a child without getting married.
My mother didn't know who her father was.
So they say her man must have abandoned her...
Natsume.
It's okay.
If you don't want to talk about it, you don't have to.
So I was scared to learn about Reiko-san.
However...
What the youkai tell me about Reiko-san is different, somehow,
so...
Yeah.
You really care about your grandma, don't you?
Thanks, Tanuma.
For listening.
I'm sorry, Sensei.
Huh? Why are you apologizing?
I don't know.
The Reiko-san you and the other youkai tell me about is always smiling,
so I didn't want to tell you about it.
Huh?
You really make no sense.
I found you, Natsume Reiko.
Give it back.
Give my treasure back.
I'm not Reiko-san.
But what do you mean treasure?
Do you mean your name?
If it's in the Book of Friends, I'll give it back.
Thief! Reiko the thief!
Thief? What did she steal?
My treasure!
You stole my friend!
Give it back! Give it back!
What's wrong, Natsume?!
If you won't give it back, I'll come take your treasure instead...
Instead?
Takashi-kun, dinnertime!
Oh no!
Did we lose it!?
I don't sense any people here.
Is anyone there?
Do you need something?
I'm sorry.
I lost sight of a pot youkai around here.
It said that my grandmother took something from it.
Your grandmother?
I don't know what it means...
Oh, you don't know?
Natsume Reiko stole a doll from the pot!
It was a very beautiful doll.
Stole? Really?
Reiko was lonely. I'm sure she wanted it.
If you're her grandson, why not look through her things?
I'm sure you'll find her stolen doll.
Hey, did she just say Reiko?
Is that...
Really! He looks delicious!
The little ones are gathering.
Let's head home for now.
Yeah.
Reiko?
This smell...
Reiko!
Takashi-kun!
Where did you go instead of eating your dinner?
I-I'm sorry.
I just really wanted to go jogging all of a sudden.
Then you should've told me first!
Takashi.
I don't mean to nag,
but make sure you say "I'm leaving" when you go,
and "I'm home" when you get home.
Yes.
Natsume Yuujinchou
I'm going back to that shed again.
Leave it alone.
I'm sure it's all lies anyway.
I have to go.
They said they'd come to take my treasure.
If I stay here, they may come after my foster parents.
Both you and Reiko love trouble.
I'm leaving!
If it decides my treasure is the people I care about...
For now, I just need to stay away from home.
Hello? Is anyone there?
Hey, kid!
What are you doing?
I don't know who you are, but get away from there!
The youkai that lives there is scary and out of control.
I talked to her a little earlier...
You're lucky.
Get out of there, if you don't want to get bit!
I see.
Thank you.
Then you're in danger too, right?
Let's go.
Do you know a lot about this area?
Of course.
Actually, I've never seen you before...
You're hiding yourself cleverly with that mask, but...
That's a baby pig pretending to be a cat, isn't it?
What did you say, you ball of rags?
You can't fool me!
Hey, have you ever heard of Reiko, then?
I'm no pig! What's your problem?
Reiko?
Oh, Reiko the thief?
Kayatsubo was once whining about how its doll got stolen.
"It was my dear friend and Natsume Reiko stole it out of jealousy."
Is Kayatsubo a youkai that looks like a pot big enough for someone to fit in?
Yeah, that's right.
What's happening?
What's going on?
Oh, he's looking for a doll.
A doll, huh?
Speaking of dolls, there was a doll a child of man
once threw once threw away in the forest of Ashihara.
It might still be there.
The forest of Ashihara?
It's just west of here.
Thanks. I'll try that!
Reiko the thief!
You stole my friend!
Did Reiko really steal something from a youkai and throw it away?
Natsume!
Is this it?
It's a little strange to hear that Reiko wanted a doll.
What's wrong, Natsume?
I want her to be happy.
But no matter what I learn now,
I can't do anything for her.
Hey, grandson.
Did you find the doll? The one Reiko stole.
Yeah.
So I'm going to look for the pot youkai...
No, that's not right.
Huh?
It wasn't filthy like that.
It was beautiful.
It didn't have mud on its hair or kimono either.
You're... Kayatsubo!
I see.
So you don't intend to return it.
Then I have no choice.
I'll go to your home to take your treasure!
Wait!
Don't get any stupid ideas!
Sensei!
It's not this doll?
Then where is it?
You are Reiko!
Natsume Reiko!
Not now!
Let me go! I'm not Reiko!
Reiko! Natsume Reiko!
It's resonating...
Is its name in the Book of Friends?
Reiko! Reiko!
Oh no! I have to get away,
or it will swallow up my mind!
Let me go! I...
Hey, did you see a girl?
I said hey!
You're so big, but all you eat is acorns, huh?
I'm looking for someone.
I thought I could find her if I went up high,
but there are so many leaves it's hard.
Can you put me on your shoulders?
I'll give you something better than acorns.
What? It's a lowly child of man.
There is nothing more delicious than acorns!
Oh, sorry.
If you help me out, I'll bring you something called a manjuu.
You're not scared of me?
I saw the birds sitting on your shoulders.
I like birds. I don't like humans.
Hey!
It hurts!
There she is.
She's a girl from one of the apartment buildings in my neighborhood.
Mom!
I thought I saw her go this way...
I knew it!
I'll find your doll.
You go home.
Go straight this way.
No looking back until you find a road you know.
This is important, okay?
Thank you!
The forest is so lively today.
Hey, you know.
Is that doll yours?
Yes, that's right.
Pretty, isn't it?
I made that girl trip and fall, so that I could make her a friend.
Then she dropped this doll,
so I took it instead.
You need to give people back what they drop.
That doll is her treasure, she says.
If it was her treasure, why did she drop it?
No. This is my friend now.
Or... I know.
You're pretty.
Shall I take you instead?
Want to go inside my pot?
Wait! What are you doing?
Foolish child of man!
She's scary!
We're getting out of here!
But...
Sheesh...
Let me give you some advice.
Her name is Kayatsubo. She's very scary.
But when the sun sets she gets tired no matter where she is,
and falls asleep in her pot.
Really?
Take it back then.
You're telling me, even though you don't like the children of men?
I dislike humans,
but I do like tiny creatures.
I see.
I'll bring you a manjuu soon then.
I met someone strange recently.
They're human, but they talk to me anyway.
They tell me climbing up trees is dangerous,
or that it's too late to be out walking.
He nags a lot for a man.
I think he lives in another town, and sometimes he just shows up here.
Sometimes he buys me manjuu
from a delicious place called Nanatsujiya.
Reiko-san...
Wow, she really is asleep, huh?
Hey, wait!
Found it!
I got it! Thank you!
I'll go give it back to her then.
She came back crying that she'd lost her doll.
Why do you have it?
I found it.
I came to give it back to her.
Can you see that she gets it?
Oh, yeah. I see.
But you can have it.
She cried so much we already got her a new one.
But I don't really need a doll...
It's fine. You can have it.
Bye!
Are you sure, ma'am?
Maybe she stole it...
Stop it.
She seems like such a poor little girl.
Hey, pot woman!
You not here?
She's rolling around during the day, huh?
Sorry, but I'll leave it here.
I'm sure it's better off with someone who will care for it.
Right?
You looked into my memories, didn't you?
You're not Reiko.
I'm her grandson, Takashi.
Your name is in the Book of Friends, right?
I'll give it back.
But will you let me go for now?
Kayatsubo is angry because she thinks my grandmother stole the doll.
If I don't get back quick,
she says she'll take something from me.
That's right! Yeah! Let him go, you big jerk!
What?
You followed me?
It's dangerous! Get back!
You're a strange child of man.
You look just like she did,
but where she always smiled your expression changes all the time.
And your heart changes as well.
What you found was the doll.
I told Kayatsubo,
but it was so dirty she probably didn't recognize it.
Thank you.
For telling me about my grandmother, too.
I'll come to give you back your name, I promise.
And thank you, too!
I have so many treasures...
So many that lately they've made me weaker.
But...
What were you doing, Natsume?
I have no duty to protect this house anyway!
Thank you. Where's Kayatsubo?
I got ahead of her and watched the house,
but she isn't here yet.
I see.
The sun's set, so she won't come tonight.
Then do we fight her in the morning?
Yeah.
But first there's something I want to try.
What happened to this doll?
It belongs to someone I know.
I'd like to clean it,
but I don't know how.
Let me see...  With this kind of fabric...
Takashi-kun, bring me a bowl.
Okay.
With Touko-san and Sensei's help,
I was able to get the dirt and grass off.
How pretty!
So there you are!
Stay with me!
I'll take good care of you, so let's go back together.
I'm so glad.
Now let's go.
Whenever I see Reiko-san in memories,
she always seems so tough.
Here's your manjuu, as promised.
Are you okay?
They seemed suspicious of you.
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm not used to trying to help people, though, and I really shouldn't.
Bye, acorn—
What's your name?
I have no name to tell the children of men!
I see.
Then want to have a contest with me?
I want to know your name.
Hey, Natsume, you're going to give him his name back, right?
This is the wrong way.
Yeah. I was going to get some manjuu from Nanatsujiya.
Buy lots!
I love them!
Yeah.
So do I.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Mischievous Rain
It was somehow warm, and soft...
I'm sure...
If it was lost, it's important to know it was lost.
Hey, girl, take it and go!
I'm glad the weather was clear today.