Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Tanuma invited me to an inn run by one of his relatives.
They're renovating it soon,
and we're going to help with the cleanup.
Sensei followed me, "because there are a lot of youkai in that area," he says.
He's supposed to be my bodyguard,
but he was all excited about hot springs and hot sake.
Sensei, want some cheese codfish?
Sorry, Tanuma, I may have taken things a little too far by bringing him.
No, I've never done anything like this myself.
I'm looking forward to it.
What should I do if a new love begins on my trip?
Hey, Tanuma, I'll take some cheese codfish, too.
Sure.
Me, too!
I'm actually really looking forward to this myself.
Enough to forget the slight uneasiness I feel.
Distant Festival Lights
Welcome!
I'm happy you brought so many friends.
Thank you for coming, Kaname-chan!
Kaname-chan!
It's good to see you again, Aunt Satomi.
Thanks for inviting us all.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
I'm glad you seem to be doing well, though.
You've grown up a little, Kaname-chan.
There's a festival on the mountain over there tomorrow and the day after.
Once you're done helping,
go and have fun.
A festival, huh?
There are five guests here besides you.
They're all here for the festival.
You can use this annex as you like.
This is great!
Okay, let's put our things down and get started!
Yeah!
We're students, though,
so we can't serve sake.
What?
I'm at a hot springs and I don't get any sake?
But if you go to the festival,
there'll be lots of food stalls, Sensei.
Fried squid!
Did you live around here, Tanuma!
Oh my!
Oh my, Kaname-kun!
It's been so long!
Ito-san, it's good to see you.
You've gotten taller!
I'm glad you don't look so pale anymore, too!
Have you been well?
Y-Yes.
Oh, what a cute boy!
Are you a friend?
H-Hello.
My name is Natsume.
He's a friend I made in Yatsuhara.
I see!
Thanks for being his friend!
No...
Hey, you guys done?
Oh dear!
All these young men!
Are you his friends, too?
How wonderful!
I know! Here, have some candy.
Take whichever you like!
Come on! Go ahead!
Ito-san, calm down.
Thank you.
That's nice of you.
You're so popular, Tanuma.
Damn it.
That's kind of upsetting.
I lived in the next town over.
I was a lot less healthy than I am now.
But my dad worked and wasn't home in the evenings sometimes.
When I got a fever, I was often sent here.
I made Aunt Satomi worry a lot.
And Ito-san, who lived close by, would bring me pears and cough drops.
So this is a little embarrassing,
but it makes me happy to see how happy both of them were.
I see.
After that, we helped serve the customers food
and lay out their futons.
The night was a lot of fun, too.
Dad snuck this photo collection into my bag!
What? Photo collection?
Ghost Photos
Taken At Inns!
Why did we look at those?
I won't be able to sleep like this.
I know just the thing to do!
What is it?
It didn't feel like we'd ever fall asleep,
but at some point, we did.
What is this?
They said there's a festival, but...
It's an attic door...
Someone moved it.
Okay, I'll follow them!
It seems like it came from the other side of the mountain.
It might be stealing the sake from the festival!
I'll defeat it and take the sake back!
Hey, Sensei!
Morning...
What's wrong, Natsume?
It was so much fun, I couldn't sleep.
I know the feeling.
Me, too.
You wouldn't wake up no matter how hard we tried.
Natsume, did something happen?
Something might have come into the inn last night.
Something?
A youkai?
Yeah.
Sensei's looking for it, I guess.
I see.
Yeah, got it.
I'm hungry...
What's for breakfast?
Good morning, everyone.
I have the seats by the window ready for you.
Thank you.
Food, food!
Huh? We're missing one.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Where did it go?
I know I made enough for everyone...
Wait, I'll get another one.
Sorry.
Am I imagining it?
Something's...
Hey, didn't they say there were five guests here yesterday?
When we brought the food out, there were five, I think.
Huh?
But there are six here now, right?
Someone else came overnight, maybe?
Maybe, yeah.
But who?
No, nobody came last night...
Is that right? Were there five?
No, there are six.
Something must have hidden itself along with the other guests last night.
The guests?
Then even people without the power to see youkai can see it?
Yeah.
Some youkai can show themselves to people if they want,
or disguise themselves as people.
There are?
That's a little rough...
If somebody you thought was a person turned out to be a youkai...
That would be kind of sad.
I let Tanuma and the others start carrying the stuff for the renovation.
I decided to do some cleaning and small errands in the building
to check on the guests.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I had a question.
His name is Yuuki-san, right?
When does the festival dance start?
They said it starts at 5:00 PM today and tomorrow.
I see. Thanks.
It doesn't necessarily have to be someone traveling alone.
The youkai seems to be able to manipulate memories.
They may have manipulated someone else's memories to help them sneak in.
Hey, don't run like that!
Festival! Festival!
The Minos are a mother and daughter traveling together, right?
Look at her cute kimono!
Yeah.
That's a couple.
Hatanaka-san and Ootaka-san, was it?
I told you!
Are you okay?
I'll go get a first aid kit.
Thanks.
There's one left, a male guest named Akasaki...
Is he in his room?
What's that sound?
This is...
Oh dear, you saw me.
A youkai!
Listen to me.
The mask I use for the festival was stolen.
I saw the thief come into this inn.
A mask? A thief?
More importantly...
You didn't steal it, did you?
Why are you...
Ito-san?
Natsume Yuujinchou
Ito-san, are you?
I served the Mizunagi shrine for many years.
My job is to protect the mountain festival.
It's easier to do as a human,
so I take this form and walk among them.
But don't tell anyone about this, until the festival is over.
If you do, I'll have to eliminate you, and anybody you tell.
I know.
If you can see me,
then help me find the thief.
I see.
There seems to be something amidst the guests.
Let me go!
Hey, old lady!
Don't touch my pet!
Sensei!
I'm stuck!
I was about to ambush her!
The white bun-creature is your friend, too, huh?
Now, then...
I must return to the festival.
I'll come back.
At least look while I'm going.
It's a mask I use at night.
A mask of a white woman's face.
Thanks so much.
Wait, Ito-san.
Oww..
T-Tanuma!
Natsume!
I'm glad.
I thought something might have happened.
You were looking for the first aid box, right?
I already brought it to them.
Thanks.
Tanuma...
No.
If somebody you thought was a person turned out to be a youkai...
That would be kind of sad.
According to the information I stayed up all night finding,
the youkai who stole the festival mask is lurking in the inn.
You were told not to say anything!
I just don't have to say who they really are, right?
A festival mask?
Why?
Probably because masks are like vessels
that hold a festival's power.
If you steal a mask, you might be able to take its power.
But why pretend to be human?
Just to be a jerk!
A nasty guy like that is about to get the power of the festival,
and it's all excited!
Something that creepy is inside this inn?
I'll keep looking into the guests.
Yeah, me, too.
Without the mask,
we can't do the evening dance.
But Tanuma, if you notice anything, tell me right away.
You, too, Natsume.
That's right.
It's a really big surprise...
Are you that jealous, Tanuma?
No...
Excuse me.
I've come to bring you a fresh towel.
Oh, thanks.
Is there anything else you need?
No, not really.
I can't tell just by looking, after all.
Natsume, we're in good shape
so they told us we can go to the evening festival if we keep this up.
Let's hang in there just a little more.
Yeah!
I guess I'll just have to ask.
A mask?
Yes.
Did you see a white mask somewhere in the inn?
No.
I'm told you use them for the festival.
I'm on my way now.
Thank you.
Wait...
I think I saw one somewhere.
Where was it?
I can't remember...
Somebody was putting on and taking off a white mask,
and getting all excited...
Am I imagining it?
A woman? A man?
A mask!
Her?
Wait!
Where'd you get that mask?
It's important!
Give it back!
This is important?
I'm sorry.
It's not her?
They seemed to be having fun with it,
so I took it.
Who was playing with it?
This is mine.
Ootaka-san?
You found me!
Wait!
Hatanaka-san!
He's just unconscious!
Leave him!
Sensei!
She was controlling him to help her blend in!
She's going up! She's heading for the roof!
Enough of this crap.
Curse you, beast!
If I can't have it, I'll break this mask!
Stop it!
Let me go!
Natsume!
Sorry I'm late.
Thank you for protecting it.
Ito-san.
Let go of the mask and begone!
Tanuma, what's wrong?
No...
What was that?
Natsume?
Sorry I can't go to the festival.
It's not your fault.
Come to think of it, the first time I came here
was when my dad took me to the festival.
I was really looking forward to it,
but I got a fever...
In the end, I didn't get to go.
My dad and I watched the festival lights in the distance.
I was just a kid, but I felt really pathetic.
So, the next year, I forced myself to go to the festival.
Rifle shooting, cotton candy...
I had so much fun,
but then I got dizzy...
And then the next thing I knew I got lost.
I was scared and lonely,
and it hurt to think that I was making my dad worry again.
I almost broke out crying...
Oh, what's wrong?
That was the first time I met Ito-san.
She helped me.
"Keep it a secret"? That's so selfish...
You care about him...
and you're so kind...
Are you okay, Natsume?
You're such a wimp, Natsume.
Here, think you could eat a rice ball?
Sorry...
It's fine.
Just rest.
Let's go to the festival tomorrow.
Together.
Thank you.
I made it in time for the dance, thanks to you.
Tanuma helped me, too.
Of course, I didn't tell him about you.
I see.
I feel relieved, a little.
He always seemed so lonely...
Humans really do grow up so fast.
He looks so happy,
and he has so many friends.
Just kidding...
I am a shrine guardian.
I don't play favorites with individual humans.
Oh, right. I hate to say this,
but keep my identity secret until the end of the festival tomorrow.
What happens after the festival?
You found out who I was,
so I can't stay here anymore.
I'll keep protecting the festival and the shrine.
But I'll have to abandon this form,
and go to a different town in a different form.
Bye!
Wait!
If I don't tell anyone,
it's the same as nobody knowing, right?
I won't tell anybody.
Ever. I promise.
So stay here!
As long as you want to... as long as you can.
Please stay here.
You don't need to read my mind.
I'm telling the truth.
That's not it.
When humans feel this way,
this is what they do, right?
The next day I worked hard enough to make up for lost time,
and was able to go see the last dance of the festival.
I'm sorry, Natsume.
I wasn't there when you needed me, again.
No, I was able to do what I needed to
because you understood what was going on.
And...
I'm sorry, Tanuma.
There's a secret I can't tell you.
It's started!
I remembered...
When I was little, sometimes I was scared of Ito-san.
I can't say why,
but she seems kind of different from other people.
It's like...
I never thought youkai were real,
but ever since I met you,
I've started to think that maybe she's one.
So...
So?
Now that I have a friend like you,
I came here because I wanted to show her my friend.
Thank you, Natsume.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
A World Unbent
There's nothing on my shoulders, is there?
Want to work with me, then?
If I follow this path,
will I find something, someday?
You have to be strong,
or you can't protect anything.
What will you do?