Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Ever since I was little,
I've been able to see things that others couldn't.
Master Shuuichi.
What is it?
There was a big bug on your shoulder.
Didn't you see it?
When I told them what I saw,
my grandfather and father got very mad,
and my mother looked sad.
The Natori clan used to be exorcists,
but they quit after there were none left who could see youkai.
Ever since then, they've lived in fear of the youkai's revenge.
Then I was born, with the ability to see and form connections with youkai.
They started thinking that anything bad that happened to the family
was brought on by me.
My mother's death from illness,
my grandfather's bad leg...
All of it.
You were in the storehouse again?
Your father will scold you.
Like I care.
Perhaps I could find something in the scrolls in the storehouse
that would tell me how to destroy the youkai, or this lizard-like thing on my body.
So, Sumi-san, do you need something?
Your grandfather has a guest...
Forget it, I'm leaving.
Begone!
We're done with the business!
I don't want anything to do with exorcists.
Let's go!
I'm not interested in any meetings.
Don't come back.
Meetings?
Three days hence. The twentieth hour,
Ishizuki Valley.
If you can see, you'll know the place immediately.
So that's an exorcist?
A World Unbent
Meeting Place
North Entrance
You'll know if you can see, huh?
Meeting
Hey, kid, I've never seen you before.
Who invited you?
If you can't answer me, I'll eat you here.
Stop it.
I brought him.
My apologies.
Thanks.
You can see them, too?
Yes.
I came because I heard there was a meeting for exorcists here.
What's a student doing here?
Seems that goes for both of us.
What are you doing here?
I'm a high school freshman.
What about you?
Sophomore.
I'm Natori. Natori Shuuichi.
I came because I wanted to learn about youkai.
What about you?
Natori, huh?
Call me Seiji, Shuuichi-san.
I'm looking for someone I can use.
Shuuichi-san, can you see that kimono caught on the branch up there?
What color is that?
A dark red.
What?
Hey, Seiji-kun.
I told you a child has no business here.
Takuma-san,
my clan's orders brought me here.
The Matoba clan is always...
Who's that?
A friend?
No.
But he's not bad.
What?
What do you mean not bad?
Hey, no fighting.
I'll be on my way.
I'm keeping Nanase-san waiting.
Farewell.
Who is he anyway?
Matoba Seiji-kun, heir to the Matoba clan.
The Matoba clan?
I saw that name in the scrolls in the storehouse...
They're among the most powerful exorcists.
They were the ones who brought together the 11 families.
And who are you?
Oh, I'm Natori.
Natori Shuuichi.
Those Natoris?
I think it was Amasaki-san who visited your home.
Amasaki?
Their family owes a great debt to the Natori clan,
so he wanted it to be revived.
They no longer had anyone who could see youkai,
so they were forced to leave the business.
There's a lot of noise in here.
Should we leave?
No...
I didn't realize that so many people could see them.
Not all exorcists can see them.
You saw a kimono outside, right?
It supposedly looks different to different people.
Sometimes it's just a white cloth,
or a kimono shining with pale light.
It looks red to me.
It looks red to me too.
Very dark red.
I see. Not bad.
No, it means you're fairly strong.
Anyone who sees it as red is said to have strong spiritual power.
It seems more orange to me.
But supposedly the truly strong
see patterns of beautiful gold chrysanthemums or large peonies.
Seiji-kun is the rare type who can see those patterns.
I'm sure, when he grows up, he'll be a powerful exorcist.
He was testing me!
Just being able to see them
doesn't necessarily mean you're cut out to be an exorcist.
My glasses are fake.
I'm not as strong as them,
but through the glass I can see the youkai a little more clearly.
This may just be my pride talking,
but I want to protect people if I can.
I want to exorcise from them their fear of the strange shadows called youkai.
An exorcist can do that.
Takuma, who is that man?
He doesn't look like a shiki.
How rude.
He's...
Natori?! Where is he?
Sorry.
Let's leave.
No, I'll stay here a little more.
Is that...
You shouldn't touch it.
If it travels to you...
You're kind, aren't you?
No. Just scared.
I don't know how normal I'm allowed to be.
There's too much I don't know.
I want to know how I should live my life.
I see.
Yes...
I can talk to him...
Can I come back?
Kids aren't allowed here.
Come to me when you're in trouble.
Okay?
I knew what Takuma-san said,
but sometimes I would sneak out and go to the meetings.
At least when I was around others who could see the youkai,
I didn't have to lie.
If I kept going there, I might find some way to be rid of this thing.
If that happened, my frustration would fade,
and maybe I could be nicer to the people around me.
Someday I could be kind to...
even my family.
Takuma-san was hurt?
You're back, young master Natori?
You didn't hear?
A huge youkai with three horns appeared near Umaaraizuka.
It attacks anyone that smells like an exorcists.
A youkai that attacks exorcists...
That's scary.
We should stay away from Umaaraizuka for a while.
Indeed.
The boy from the Natori clan's back.
That's the clan of cowards that ran away and quit, right?
How stupid.
Which of us are cowards?
But...
If I exorcised it, would Takuma-san accept me?
What's Shuuichi doing?
Is he not coming to dinner again?
He seems busy with his studies.
He's studying in the storehouse, I mean, his room.
He can't accomplish anything unless he works so hard he skips meals?
He's not worth anything.
All he can do is say weird things to scare the
rest of the family and get attention.
It's taken me a lot of work,
but I'm starting to understand how to use incantations and draw circles.
I'm tired...
But there's an uneasiness in my heart.
When I'm chasing the youkai,
it's like all the noise around me fades away.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Three-horns!
It ran?
I almost had it.
Matoba Seiji!
Are you after it, too?
Then do you want to work with me?
I refuse.
I want to see what I can do on my own.
Don't laugh!
Well, think about it, Shuuichi-san.
Shut up!
I'm not joining you, okay?
If he's from a famous family,
he's probably got all kind of flunkies already.
It's like he's looking down on and judging me...
I don't want him testing to see if he can use me.
Um... Amasaki-san, what do you want with my family?
Wait!
If you're going to do something bad...
N-No...
Just lately, I'd heard there's a youkai that attacks exorcists.
I was worried about your family.
You were trying to protect us?
Well...
I'm a powerless exorcist who's about to leave the business myself.
So I was sneaking around.
Leave the business?
It's harder to see them.
I remembered my father and grandfather saying that the Natori family
had always been very kind to our family.
I don't have any jobs to do,
so I thought the last thing I could do was repay that debt.
It may just be a bother, though.
Are you going to be an exorcist?
Yes.
I see.
I'm back.
Dad's so scared of revenge,
but if I were to save someone as an exorcist, I'm sure...
I'm sure...
That three-horned youkai was bigger than I thought.
If you're an exorcist, do you have to fight things like that?
Natori-kun,
there's something I want to talk to you about.
Can you come with me?
Sorry, I'm busy.
I see.
Sorry.
I feel like a bad guy, even though I haven't done anything.
I feel sick.
Like I'm going to throw up.
Am I doing something wrong?
Then I want to do right.
And the right thing to do
is to not hurt the people around me.
I came back to the same place as before, but...
No sign of it, huh?
Matoba Seiji!
Just call me Seiji.
Well, this was where they were attacked,
so they might not come for a while.
Why are you here?
I said I wouldn't join you.
I'm just working on my own.
Still, that's a lot of stuff you're carrying.
I'm not sure what'll work.
Yeah, if you're using cheap tools, I guess.
Are you here to pick a fight with me?
Oh, sorry.
I just said what I was thinking.
With your power, as long as you learned the circles
and had a decent enough pot,
you could do all right for yourself.
I heard that the Natori clan were skilled paper-users.
It's said that those who can use paper well can communicate with the gods.
I guess you never know what will happen.
The Matoba clan might not be on top forever, too.
I don't know.
I won't let it fall.
I don't have any burdens to bear of my own, do I?
Is that why the world seems to waver so?
Okay, let's go.
To Takuma-san.
He was attacked by that youkai, supposedly.
So I want to talk to him.
You're going too, right?
Shuuichi-kun!
You're still pretending to be an exorcist?
It's dangerous!
You gave me your business card!
I meant if you were having trouble with youkai!
Why not go home, Shuuichi-san?
You!
You too, Seiji-kun?
Come in.
My investigations show that it's appearing between Umaaraizuka and Watanose.
It seems to use smell to determine who's an exorcist.
So if anybody who seems like an exorcist comes by, it attacks?
Did it seem capable of understanding speech?
No, it's not going away unless it's exorcised.
It'll probably be brought up at the next meeting,
but you guys should stay away.
Okay...
I guess I didn't mean that.
I guess this is Watanose?
It had a frame like a horse, cow, or other animal.
Fire or cast metal will probably work, right?
Shut up.
I'm not working with you.
I don't need hints.
Hints?
Sorry.
It was just so basic.
This guy...
But maybe I shouldn't be stubborn.
If I'm serious about being an exorcist,
he's been doing it longer than me.
What's in the wrapping?
Oh, it's a bow you can put together.
Sounds dangerous.
Well, last time I failed to get it,
but this time...
I'll get it in one hit.
Are you going to learn all this yourself?
Or learn from someone?
Takuma-san, perhaps?
I feel like I've got my own way of doing things.
So if I could do it on my own...
He's a nice guy,
but his techniques are limited.
You should use someone more talent—
That's not the issue!
What I should learn...
My goal is...
Who I want to be is...
Shuuichi-san,
if you don't become strong,
you can't protect anything.
Thanks for everything.
Bye.
For cast metal techniques, I have...
This is the spot, right?
It's a good chance.
If we can take out that three-horned youkai,
we'll become famous, and people will owe us.
But it's supposedly strong.
Scared, huh?
Everybody's thinking the same thing, huh?
I'll do it...
I'll do this!
What's this feeling?
They didn't notice?
Get back!
Come forth, come forth!
What passes this way is not heat,
nor thunder!
Silver bursts,
comes forth and destroy!
Did I get it?
My entrapping talisman...
Over here, Seiji!
Don't miss!
Who do you think you're talking to?
Good work.
Your incantations worked,
so it was quick.
This'll probably make us both a little more famous, huh?
Are those exorcists safe?
Hmm?
I talked to them and they ran away.
I failed to get it.
You killed it.
Yeah?
Thank you.
You saved me.
Yeah.
I'll take the glory then.
Shuuichi-san.
You need to find a better way of living,
if you're not going to get strong.
Shut up.
Just what you'd want to see from the Matoba heir...
After defeating the three-horned youkai on his own,
Matoba Seiji became famous.
He'll probably take over the clan.
I'm jealous.
The Matoba clan is in good hands.
Jealous?
I don't want my right eye getting eaten.
I've heard the current head of the clan's face
But I don't want to know about other people's problems.
is a mess after so many attacks.
I just want to become a strong and righteous exorcist,
whose heart doesn't waver.
That youkai's taken care of.
Huh?
Are you alone?
Oh no...
I talked to a shiki!
My master passed away yesterday.
He was sick.
He'd been sick for a long time, but since he had not long to live,
I let him do as he pleased.
It had been long since I'd seen him so happy.
What will you do now?
I may never find it,
no matter where I go.
A way to just keep going forward...
A way to become kind...
But still...
Seiji?
I guess even he sometimes just looks at the river.
I'm glad I'm far apart from him.
I don't want to see him.
Doesn't matter if he's smiling like he always does,
or looking down in some kind of sorrow.
Why?
I feel disappointed in something.
I can't see what he sees.
We have different paths.
I heard you took another big one down, Natori.
Did you learn your skills yourself?
Yes, I suppose.
How dangerous.
You're crazy.
I make it work.
If I follow this path,
will I be able to meet someone, someday?
Will I be able to find something, someday?
Shuuichi-san, it's been a long time.
Wait, are you asleep?
The world probably seems warped and bent
because you try to look at it with these, right?
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Following A Narrow Path
Does Shion-sama remember me?
It may be difficult, but I hope it works.
You can work for me! Follow me!
Why's this mushroom so bratty?
I'll cook you and eat you!
Sensei, calm down!