Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Gotcha!
You're Natsume, the one with the Book of Friends!
Let me go!
He can summon lots of youkai and control them.
Let's crush his throat so he can't call his servants.
Okay, open your mouth!
We won't let you go, Natsume!
Natsume!
Who are you?
It doesn't matter.
Help us out!
This is the
Natsume!
If you help, you can have a leg.
It is Natsume Reiko after all.
Reiko, come to my nest!
What is this?
I can't speak...
I can't speak?
Soundless Valley
We're here.
This valley.
The dark energy has affected you.
It got your throat.
You won't be able to speak for a while, Reiko.
Wait, Reiko.
I'll go super-find some medicine!
Got it.
Leave it to me.
I'll go super-catch some fish!
No!
Reiko-san is
gone. I'm her
grandson.
Reiko-san is
gone. I'm her
grandson.
Reiko-san is
gone. I'm her
grandson.
So this youkai can't read?
Reiko's here.
I'm super-happy!
Sorry.
I'm not Reiko-san.
That flower is pretty.
One of these will work. Probably.
I bet Touko-san is worried.
How can I get out of here?
And my voice...
If it never gets better...
Reiko, come with me.
Look.
Some kind of magic circle?
I'm getting dizzy...
Dizzy...
Reiko laughed.
I see.
He was trying to make me feel better?
Hey, what happened to the Book of Friends, Reiko?
Where is it? The Book of Friends.
I finally found you, Natsume!
Don't wander around on your own.
What are you doing out here in the middle of nowhere?
Don't think you can get away from me. You're my snack.
Got it? You—
You fool!
Idiot!
A piglet!
What? What?
More guests!
Awwah!
I love it when it's lively!
Let me go! I'm getting dizzy!
Lively?
Stop it! Hey!
I said, "Stop!"
Stop it! Let me down!
What is this guy?
Hey, Natsume.
Huh? Natsume, you...
Let me see...
Well, it's not bad.
Let it sit and it'll heal in two or three days.
Sheesh... they cast a crappy voice-sealing spell.
Touko-san asked me to
run an errand and I was
attacked by two youkai
on the way back.
Touko-san asked me to
run an errand and I was
attacked by two youkai
on the way back.
Touko-san asked me to
run an errand and I was
attacked by two youkai
on the way back.
You can't even run a single errand?
You're worthless.
Hey, big guy. Thanks for helping.
You knew Reiko?
Reiko's finally here!
Reiko?
How is this Reiko?
Look carefully. This is her grandson.
Unfortunately, Reiko's passed on.
Oh. I see.
I see.
Reiko...
...never came.
Squeeze.
Now then...
Let's go home, Natsume.
I'll come back.
I want to ask you about Reiko.
I wanted to call, but I can't talk. Sorry to worry you.
Oh no!
You can't speak?
Do you have a cold?
No fever, I guess...
Egg sake is good for colds.
Here, Takashi-kun.
Wrap these onions around your throat.
Onions are good for your throat.
Keep these around your neck
while you sleep and we'll see how you do in the morning.
You okay, Takashi?
Maybe the onions kind of stink?
The onions smell, but I'm fine. Thank you for giving me this.
It's hard not being able to speak.
I want my voice back soon. Let's go look for the youkai who put the spell on me.
So the plan is to have the youkai who cast the spell break it?
You don't need to go looking.
They'll come looking for you.
They know the size of the fish they let go.
And they're the kind of sneaky little jerks who'd steal your voice.
Then I need to get it back fast.
I don't want them coming here
and doing something to Touko-san and Shigeru-san.
Empty already?
Sensei, you're not going out drinking tonight are you?
Heck no!
And leave you here when you're such a mess?
I don't want anybody taking you.
Natsume, sleep naked tonight.
What are you planning, Sensei?!
I want to try this egg sake that Shigeru was talking about.
If you get a cold, Touko will make it for us.
Sleep naked and get a fever!
That's crazy!
There, there... sheesh.
You're such a handful.
Thank you, Sensei.
Not that you can hear me.
I haven't thanked that youkai for saving me either.
The one who saved me because he mistook me for Reiko-san...
Once my voice is back I'll go see her,
to thank her and to ask about Reiko-san.
Reiko-san is
gone. I'm her
grandson.
Reiko-san is
gone. I'm her
grandson.
Reiko-san is
gone. I'm her
grandson.
Natsume Yuujinchou
It seems it's going to take a while for my throat inflammation to get better.
Oh my. Really?
Oh, right.
Nishimura-kun just called.
He asked if he, Tanuma-kun, and your other friends
could bring over today's handouts on the way home.
I don't want them getting sick too, so I'll pass on saying hi.
You're right.
I hope you get better soon.
I made honey daikon radish syrup today.
Daikon is good for the throat too.
Here, say aah.
You got a voice-sealing spell cast on you?
You're always so stupid... I mean, poor you!
Stupid, stupid!
This guy
So this attacked you?
What an awful picture.
Oh, that's the hairy thing from the next town over!
You know them, Hinoe?
Yeah, they're bad news.
Especially when they group up.
It's tough for him not being able to talk.
Is there a way to fix him quickly?
Instead of getting rid of the spell,
first you need to get the dark energy out of there.
You need boiled summer grass, right?
Summer dewgrass, it's called.
Can you find it this time of year?
No way.
It'll heal in a week.
Just stay put until then.
A-A week!
You said it would get better in 2 or 3 days!
There's no big a difference between a week and 2 or 3 days.
You're so petty.
I can't skip school for a week!
Don't worry.
I'll take your place and go.
I did it once before.
Well?
Please no!
I hope I get chestnut rice for my lunch!
Tell Touko for me.
I can't give names back without being able to speak, right?
Like I care!
You feel a sense of duty?
How noble!
I'm in love all over again!
This is a good time, Natsume.
Give me the Book of Friends.
Then it doesn't matter if you can speak!
It does!
Past Yatsuhara there's a rocky place that gets a lot of sun.
There may still be some there.
We'll look! We'll look!
Thank you, guys.
Aww, come on, Natsume-sama.
You know you can count on us.
Count on us! Count on us!
If you want to suck up to someone, suck up to me!
Bring me some egg sake!
You're the only one who wants to drink, Madara.
Make sure that nobody plays any tricks on you when you get drunk.
Dog's Circle
If I give up the Book of Friends,
would I be attacked less often,
Shigeru-san says he'll be working late tonight.
and be able to spend my days in peace?
So bored...
Shut up, Sensei.
If I gave up the Book of Friends,
what would happen to the youkai bound to it?
Does the youkai who knows Reiko-san have his name in here, too?
You can't guard me when you're drunk.
When you know you can't drink,
it makes you really want to drink.
If you get drunk, you can't be a bodyguard, right?
A master of the art like me can get a little drunk
just by sniffing the stuff.
What's wrong, Sensei?
Excuse me.
Why did you come here?
My name is in the Book of Friends.
I came to get it back.
I knew it.
But what's in the sack?
I'm going on a journey once I get my name back.
That valley was once lively,
but for a long time now it's just been me.
One day, a visitor named Reiko came.
She said she'd gotten lost.
She was bored, so I played a game with her.
It was super-fun.
So fun I remembered what it was like when it was lively.
"Reiko might come back."
It was fun to wait.
But she didn't come.
If she's gone, I won't wait anymore.
I'll get the name I gave her back,
and search for a lively valley once more.
I can't hear you, Reiko's grandson.
Oh well.
I'll try it without speaking.
A power outage?
Sensei, where are you?
I'll go check it out.
Knowing those guys, they might try it.
Sensei, what's wrong?
Is it those youkai?
That's bad! The Book of Friends!
Takashi-kun! You okay?
Touko-san?!
Oh no.
If something happens to her...
Sensei!
Where are you, Nyanko-Sensei?
Natsume?
Sensei!
Please, protect Touko-san!
We found you, Natsume!
This time you won't get away!
We caught the weird cat-thing and the big guy off-guard
and defeated them!
So this is Natsume?
Stay put!
I'll never let them have this!
Knock it off.
You think you defeated me?
You little shrimps got me by surprise because I couldn't see.
I'll teach you what happens when I get mad.
I'm pissed off, and won't be able to hold back.
I'll let you go. Just this once.
Begone!
We'll return your voice!
Forgive us!
Oh, thank goodness.
Good, the lights are back on.
I'm glad Touko-san's safe...
My voice!
Sensei!
It's back, huh?
They were terrified of my awesomeness, huh?
That was fun.
Thanks, Sensei.
Huh?
Where's the other youkai?
Hey, you okay? Hey!
It super-hurts.
You who protects me, show your name.
Really?
There was a time when this valley was lively?
Yup!
There were birds and flowers and youkai and people!
A super-lot of them!
I love it when it's lively!
That's weird, since you're in an empty place like this.
Let's play, child of man.
That's fine.
I've got nothing.
But play a game with me.
I'll play a game.
What should we do?
I want to play a human game!
A human game, huh?
I've got it.
Dizzy...
Spin the other way.
Spin... spin... spin...
Okay, it's done.
It's stone-kicking.
How do you play?
You put a stone in the square,
and kick it to advance.
Like this.
You do that until the 12th square.
If your leg or the stone goes outside the square,
or your other leg touches the ground,
you start over.
How do you win?
I don't know either.
Is it impossible to play?
Nope.
Let me see...
Let's do this.
You kick your stone into the other player's stone to knock it out.
If your stone goes out you start over.
Got it?
Got it!
Quickly!
Let's play together!
I went super-far!
And you're out!
My leg went super-out.
I win.
I lost!
But it was fun.
It was super-lively!
Yeah.
I think I actually like it that way, too.
I'm sure...
It must be fun.
Come back and play again, child of man.
My name's Reiko.
What's yours?
Hidaka.
I return your name.
Celebration
I'm glad it worked out, Natsume-sama.
Getting Better
Celebration
So glad! So glad!
Getting Better
Celebration
Thanks for everything, Middle-Ranks, Hinoe.
It's fine.
We are the Dog's Circle!
We'll always be there when you need us!
Maybe Reiko-san liked it when it was lively, too.
You weren't even useful!
Flowers and birds, and youkai, and men...
As time passed, they disappeared.
Reiko is gone, too.
There's nothing to keep me here now.
I see.
I'm sorry I wasn't Reiko-san.
You said that before.
You said you couldn't hear me.
Reiko didn't come.
But her grandson did.
I was happy!
I super-love being happy!
Idiot.
Why?
Welcome back, Shigeru-san.
Takashi, your cold's better?
Yes.
Sorry for worrying you.
I'm glad it was nothing big.
Now I can finally go drink.
Oh, you're together?
Yeah, we just ran into each other.
Welcome back.
Yeah, I'm home.
I'm home.
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Distant Festival Lights
My first time here
was when my father wanted to watch the Festival.
It's important and kind.
The Festival's Mask?
Oh my, so many lovely young men!
Ito-san, please calm down.