Natsume
Yuujinchou
You looked vacantly at the sky
utsuro ni sora mita
I wonder if you still remember
kimi wa mada oboeteru kana
The seasons that passed by left uncertain feelings
misugoshita kisetsu mo futashika na kanjou de
That memory can occupy a soft corner in your heart
kokoro no sumikko demo kakera ni nareta nara
I hope that smile of yours
kimi no ano egao ga
remains in its rightful place
arubeki basho ni aru to ii na
If these times are going to pass us by
kono jikan ga sugiteyuku nara
Then as long as I'm with you
kimi to tomo ni irareta no nara
I think I'll get to see a brand-new world
mita koto no nai sekai mirareru you na ki ga shite
If these words reach you someday
itsuka kono kotoba mo tsutawaru no nara
In order to keep these words from falling into the sky
sora he ochite shimawanu you ni
We'll take those memories we left hidden somewhere
dokoka no ura ni nokoshita omoide mo
and store them in our treasure chest
takarabako ni shimatte
Hey, Natsume!
It's been a while, so we're stopping at Nanatsujiya for manjuu on the way back.
Turn right.
No, Sensei.
We'll be late.
You're just wasting your allowance!
You stingy boy!
If we're late, Touko-san will worry, right?
Then just buy her a manjuu, too!
It hasn't been a while, anyway.
We just—
Rain.
Sensei, we're going to run.
What?
What about the Nanatsujiya manjuu?
Natsume, turn around!
I'm back!
Takashi-kun, welcome back!
Touko-san, it's raining.
It's raining outside!
The clothes are on the line!
Takashi-kun, get those!
Okay!
We just barely made it. Whew.
Yeah.
When the windows are closed,
sometimes you don't notice until it really starts pouring.
Thanks to you, we avoided a mess.
Glad to hear it.
I heard some crows cawing and looked up at the sky,
and then it started to rain so I hurried home.
Crows?
Yup.
Actually, I remember one time...
What is it, Touko-san?
No, it's nothing.
I was just remembering the past.
Touko and Shigeru
It was back when the two of us still lived in this house alone.
Shigeru-san, your handkerchief!
Thank you.
Hey, Shigeru-san.
What do you want for dinner?
Anything's fine.
That's the worst answer you can give!
Meat? Fish?
Fish.
Shioyaki? Meunière?
Nanbandzuke, maybe?
I'll let you pick.
Bye!
You're running away again!
See you later!
This is an old house, but a big one.
Shigeru-san and I lived here alone.
When he was little, his grandparents, his parents,
and he all lived here, and it was very busy, he said.
But we had no children,
so it was a fun place, but a little quiet.
Oh dear!
Stay put.
I'll move it right away, okay?
Are you okay? You're not hurt?
I'm glad.
Looks like you're fine.
Take care on your way home, okay?
He's so cute!
Fishy! Fishy!
Yup, that's a fishy.
That's called a sea bream.
Sea bream?
And this is a horse mackerel.
Horse mackerel!
You like fishies?
Yup! I want to see them swimming!
Swimming fishies, huh?
Ken-chan, we're leaving!
Mommy, fishies!
Hey, no running in the supermarket.
If you run into someone you might hurt them!
Swimming fish... perhaps an aquarium?
I guess I'm no good.
If I had a kid who said something so cute,
I'd probably start making rice balls right away
and we could go to the aquarium and have a picnic.
An aquarium, huh?
Hey, Shigeru-san,
want to go to the aquarium?
Why?
It's silly, I know. I just kind of felt like it.
I'm too old for that.
No, it's fine. I was just thinking about it.
No, let's go on my next day off, okay?
It's been a long time, after all.
Such peaceful, happy days...
If only the two of us could live such a life forever.
Touko-san, where's my mourning clothes?
Oh, did someone die?
I'll get ready, too.
No... It's my aunt on my mother's side's in-law who's—
Well, we're practically not related at all.
But they gave me a job when I was young.
It's a little far, but I'll be going to the funeral tomorrow.
I see.
Take care.
Yeah.
Fujiwara-san, thanks for coming.
I'm sorry for your loss.
I'm sure my husband will be happy.
Thank you.
What are you thinking, bringing him here?
I told you, we're having trouble with him ourselves.
That again?
My kid's got exams this year, and my wife's getting all worked up.
So you brought him here to force someone else to take him?
You don't need to put it that way.
Well, we don't want him.
When he was with us, all he did was say weird stuff and scare everyone.
I hope Shigeru-san ate something...
That crow, it's the one from before!
Its tail's a little bent.
Did it get in a fight with a cat?
It's a rascal, huh? I wonder if it's a boy.
Once you get to know them, crows are kind of cute, huh?
Hey, do you remember me?
I'm back.
Welcome back!
Did something happen?
Thanks.
Something concerning came up...
No, it's nothing.
He said it was nothing,
but after that I would catch him lost in thought, or...
Shigeru-san?
Or cleaning the room on the second floor we hadn't been using.
He seemed kind of restless.
Are we moving!?
No, that's probably not right.
If we lived someplace smaller, closer to town,
it might be more convenient and lively, but...
But I can't see either of us leaving this home anymore.
Natsume Yuujinchou
What's wrong?
Did you get stuck in something—
Rain! Oh no!
The laundry!
Wait, wait!
Made it!
So the crow told me the rain was coming.
I'm sure it was a coincidence,
but I helped this crow once before.
So it was paying you back, huh?
Well, I'm sure it's a coincidence.
Yes, I know that!
But it's true that crows are smart.
Once they find a partner, they often stay together all the time.
They spend their whole lives with the one they love.
So a crow that's alone either hasn't found that partner yet,
or has lost them, they say.
That's what I heard once.
I see.
That crow is always by itself...
Which is it, I wonder?
Has it not met someone yet?
Or perhaps...
Hello, this is the Fujiwara residence.
Oh, Sana-chan?
It's been so long.
A trip?
And so a friend of mine from middle school invited me.
That's great.
You deserve a break once in a while.
Really?
I can go?
Of course.
I haven't been on a trip in a long time.
It's alone again, today?
I'm going on a trip, okay?
Watch the house for me.
Touko!
Sana-chan!
It's been so long!
Look at you, Touko! So thin!
I'm jealous! Are you getting enough food?
Yes, of course I am.
I know just where to take us today.
First, let's get some lunch boxes at the station.
No, I want to get hungry so dinner tastes better.
Don't be silly.
Let's eat.
Wait!
Touko, look! You can see the ocean!
It's so pretty...
Yes...
I wish Shigeru-san could see this.
I'm so full!
It's so wonderful not to have to clean up!
You're right!
The men in my household all like stuff with strong flavors,
and we eat a ton of rice.
And I hate to throw food away,
so I end up eating it, and now I'm so fat!
You've got a big family.
Is Makoto-kun doing well?
He's messing around all the time, now that exams are over.
Your family always sounds so lively.
What about you?
Is Shigeru-san doing well?
Yes.
I'm glad to hear it.
That was good.
Did Shigeru-san eat dinner?
Is he eating alone today?
I'm no good...
I guess I get lonely really easily these days.
I went through much worse things in the past...
Happiness came pouring down on us so quietly, so peacefully...
It's strange, isn't it, Shigeru-san?
I miss you so much. I can't wait to see you again.
If the day ever comes when I lose him,
will I be able to survive?
Even if he loses me someday,
will he be able to survive?
I want to get back to him as soon as I can.
I'm back!
Shigeru-san?
Shigeru-san!
Sorry. Welcome back.
I'm home.
Was it fun?
Yes, it was wonderful.
I see.
Yes.
I'm glad.
Touko-san, I want to talk to you about something.
What is it?
When I went to the funeral, there was something that concerned me...
A young boy, about 14 or 15...
Ever since he lost his parents,
he's been going from one adopted family to another.
And well... it doesn't appear he's being well-treated.
We have a room we aren't using.
It may be worse for a young boy to come out here to the countryside, perhaps,
but he was so thin,
and felt so detached from everything around him.
If you'll allow it,
I want to bring him here.
You don't have to answer immediately.
I thought about it a long time before I brought it up with you.
This house is very important to both of us, so I want you to—
T-Touko-san?
No, I'm sorry.
Yes, I'll think about it.
It just makes me so happy...
And you're so kind...
I don't know why, but I'm crying.
And so we talked to our relatives and friends,
and then with each other for a long time,
and we went to welcome Natsume Takashi.
Natsume-kun?
Are you Natsume Takashi-kun?
Um...
I'm sorry.
I heard you were living here, so I thought I'd come at least take a look, but...
I'm no good.
I got so happy when I saw you.
I'm Fujiwara Touko.
A distant relative of your father's.
Where are you going at this hour?
A walk.
You can't! It's too late! It's dangerous!
Go home.
Maybe... you don't want to?
No, that's not it.
I see.
You'll catch cold. Go home.
You talked to him?
Sorry.
I couldn't help myself.
I see.
No, perhaps it's for the best.
So, how was he?
He looked a little lonely,
but he was a very good boy.
After that, we almost got into a fight with the family he was staying with,
and some relatives weren't happy about it,
but Takashi-kun ended up coming to our house.
He was a very quiet boy,
but sometimes, they said, he was a little unstable.
And strangely, he did get hurt a lot.
I worried, but when I saw him trying to smile,
Is it good?
even if he was awkward...
Yes.
Here you are.
Shigeru-san, what do you want tonight?
Oh... meat.
Takashi is too thin.
We need to feed him more meat.
That's right.
Good morning.
The two of us want to protect him.
Oh...
Takashi-kun—
Sometimes his eyes are empty,
as if his heart isn't here,
and he's looking far, far off into the distance.
How does he see us with those eyes?
Will he ever open up to us?
Tell us what he wants to do, or wants to have?
As if he really was family.
Someday...
A kitty?
Um...
May I keep this cat?
Oh my!
Kitty has such a big head!
Sure!
Let's both ask Shigeru-san!
Thank you!
Little by little,
little by little...
I know we'll...
That crow is always alone.
Which is it, I wonder.
Has it not met its partner?
Or...
Touko-san.
I'm back.
I'll help you.
Takashi-kun, welcome back.
What are you looking at?
See that crow on the branch?
It's my friend!
Can you see it?
Yes.
Oh, there are two there.
Look. It's hard to see through the branches, but...
Wow. I've never seen a white crow before.
Is that an albino, perhaps?
I've never seen it before.
It's very pretty.
Look, they took off together!
Where?
I see... I'm glad.
You're not alone, are you?
I'm back.
I'm sure it's shining such a beautiful white
that it's hard to see, isn't it?
A dry breeze blows through a corner
kareha mau machikado wo
leaving a tornado of leaves in its wake
kakenuketeku kawaita kaze
It then slips through the town's busiest street
menukidoori hitonami nukete
and goes far away to a desolate place
dokoka tooku daremo inai basho he
I'd seen it come and go but pretended not to notice
kidzuiteita noni nanimo shiranai furi
because I realized I could do nothing alone
hitorikiri dewa nanimo dekinakatta
So I bid farewell to the passing illusion
deaeta maboroshi ni sayonara wo
and waved goodbye to the crimson sky
akane sasu kono sora ni
And the weakness I'd shown
koboreta yowasa ni tenohira wo
That petal dancing in the air
hitohira no hanabira sonna fuu ni
will come to meet many more and make a wish
deai kasane negai wo shiru
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
To The
Ephemeral Ones
The way it blooms amidst the rocks is so beautiful!
So beautiful! So beautiful!
You always get sick, don't you?
You're such a handful.
Handful!
It's far better than passing by without noticing.