Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
Oh, look.
It's going to rain, Takashi-kun.
You're right.
Those clouds are big.
Touko-san, is that a stain on that rock over there?
It has a pattern like a flower.
It's pretty, isn't it?
Huh? Which one?
I guess it's too far to see.
Maybe I just imagined it.
It was just a shadow of the clouds.
Oh, really?
Yes.
Touko-san didn't see it.
So it's probably the work of a youkai.
We should hurry home.
Yes, let's go.
It kind of felt like a shame.
It was very pretty.
I wanted Touko-san to see it.
It Blooms Tomorrow
Well, Natsume? Catch anything?
Nope. You?
Not a thing.
We came all the way upstream too.
Guess we should go home.
Huh? That's no fun.
Let's go exploring, then.
There are caves and waterfalls around here.
I guess. We haven't been here that long.
I thought I just saw something.
Which should we pick?
Either one is fine.
Nishimura, Kitamoto. Let's go home.
What?
I feel like having a hamburger.
Let's get some food.
A hamburger sounds good to me!
Let's go! Let's go!
How do you guys go fishing and then want to eat beef?
Let's just go.
I'm hungry all of a sudden.
They're pretty, but it's best to stay away from things you don't understand.
It's best for both sides not to get involved.
I'm back.
Welcome back, Natsume-sama.
Welcome back! Fill me up!
You must be a delinquent if you're staying out until sunset, Natsume.
Mid-ranks... Hinoe!
You're late, Natsume! Catch anything?
Sensei, what are you doing?
Gimme the fish!
Natsume-sama, I'm here too.
We heard rumors that the stonewasher is here,
so we're celebrating.
The stonewasher?
You're really ignorant, aren't you?
He's kind of like a hermit. Very important.
It's a name given to a youkai who can purify impure stones and rocks.
You have to train hard to become one,
so there aren't many.
Here you go.
"Washing" actually means using a brush to draw a spell on them.
It's said to resemble a flower.
Then that was...
Natsume, did you see it?
Yes, a stone with a flower pattern.
That's a sign of good luck.
Have some celebratory sake!
I've told you I can't drink!
Celebratory sake! Celebratory sake!
Give us snacks!
Hey, stop that already!
Celebratory sa—
It wasn't something bad.
But why do stones become impure?
Well,
some stones draw in impure air and purify it.
But if they take in too much,
they become impure themselves.
And the stonewasher purifies them, huh?
That's kind of wonderful.
I'd like to see those flowers.
I found several at school too.
Really? Where?
I wonder if we could see them even a little.
I wish I could.
If just hearing about them made them this happy, what would they say if they could see them?
Wow, I'm not alone anymore, am I?
I want to be with them.
I want to make them happy.
I'm sure that this is...
Huh?
It's gone.
That was the spot, right?
Yeah, the purification's finished.
So they disappear?
I was going to take a picture and send it to Natori-san.
You vulgar boy.
Besides, they might not even show up in a picture.
Good point.
They said you need to train to be a stonewasher, right?
Yeah. They come from a beautiful, pure paradise.
When they finish their training,
they go on a journey to wash stones.
I see.
Oh my, young man.
You are talking to a youkai? How interesting.
Boo!
Th-That scared me!
What was that youkai?
It just attacked me out of nowhere.
Hey, Natsume, look!
A brush?
Are you the stonewasher?!
Good, you're awake.
I'm sorry. When I'm attacked, I act on instinct.
No, that is how children should be.
Right.
Anyway, are you...
I am Nanamaki, the stonewasher.
So the stonewasher is in town!
Great!
Great, great, great!
Hey, you guys!
So the flowers we've seen lately are yours?
Indeed.
Child of man, it seems you have interesting underlings.
They aren't my underlings.
That's right. If Natsume-sama
gives the order, we'll do anything!
We're Natsume's Party of Dogs!
We do whatever it takes, without mercy!
I see.
Stop it!
I am sorry. I did not realize you were so important.
Can you help me with something?
I am on a journey, but I was having trouble because I do not know this area well.
Sorry, but I don't do favors for youkai.
Do not say that!
Stop it! Let me go!
Natsume-sama, this is your chance!
It's worth it to make somebody like a stonewasher owe you a favor!
Worth it! Totally worth it!
Then you guys can help him!
Worth it! Birth it!
Birth it! Earth it!
After washing 80,000 stones,
a stonewasher can return to Fujima village.
80,000?
I finished that and was able to return to my beautiful homeland,
but one day a starving youkai in a beat-up robe wandered into the village.
It seemed that something terrible had
happened to it outside, and it had fled.
So I decided to let it stay for a while.
When I told it I was a stonewasher, it became very interested and asked me to take it in as a student.
It listened to my words and worked hard.
It was brusque, did not talk much, and was not cute at all,
but I was alone on my long journey, and to me it seemed rather cute.
And frustratingly enough, it was good at its job.
It quickly got better and better, and before too long it had become a full-fledged stonewasher.
And then it left Fujima village.
It left?
That is what stonewashers do.
But it would have white-eye birds bring letters to me,
so I had something new to look forward to.
But six months ago, the letters suddenly stopped.
Huh?
The last letter was written near here.
I decided to come to see what I could learn.
So in other words, you want Natsume-sama to help you find your student?
Indeed.
But it was six months ago, right?
Hasn't it already left?
Maybe it just got sick of you and stopped writing lett—
Hinoe, mid-ranks, can you help?
See if anybody saw flower paintings six months ago or a traveling youkai.
I don't know if we'll find anything. It'll be difficult.
What a pain.
It might be worth it to make me owe you a favor.
I like the sound of that!
Okay, Nanamaki-sama, have some sake and tell us more.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Thanks, guys.
Okay!
Is your student's name Hachimaki-san?
I'm back.
Welcome back, Takashi-kun, kitty.
Wash your hands.
We're having fried shrimp tonight.
Okay.
Hey, Natsume, don't you think a fried shrimp's tail looks like a heart?
A heart? What?
You're really invested this time.
Huh?
It's rare for you to send the
Party of Dogs to help someone.
I'm not that invested.
They just crossed my mind.
Thoughts about myself.
One day a starving youkai in a beat-up robe wandered into the village.
So I decided to let it stay for a while.
Am I going to leave this place someday?
If I was his student, I'd probably want to send letters to keep in touch.
I'd want to go back.
I'd want to go home.
I hope he finds it.
Somebody's crying.
I want to go back...
But I can't.
Who is that? Me?
Nanamaki-sama?
Or...
Natsume-sama!
Are you awake?!
Mid-ranks!
I was totally asleep!
We've pretty much found the student.
That was fast.
You said you'd consider it a double favor,
so everybody's really into it.
I did not.
Okay, let's go!
Huh? Right now?
Everybody's together!
Go! Go!
Five, six!
Seven, eight, nine!
Nanamaki!
Let me go!
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
Oww.
You're late, Natsume-dono.
Mustache, and Misuzu too.
I heard it was a drinking party- I mean, a summons.
We had to come.
Sorry. Thanks.
So where's the student?
We asked around, and he says he saw something.
It was six months ago when a youkai in a hood whom I didn't recognize came.
It held a brush in its thin hands,
and it started to draw a beautiful flower on a rock near Uratani.
That must be my student.
But then someone that looked like an exorcist appeared.
An exorcist?
Yes, but the exorcist looked like a beginner.
They started screaming about evil youkai
making graffiti on rocks and sealed it away.
Huh?! Where?!
L-Like I said, the rocks in the forest around Uratani.
Uratani?
Nyanko-sensei, can you take me there?
What? Why me?
Natsume-dono, thank you.
If I know where they are, I can take care of the rest myself.
Please go home.
I have heard that the children of men
get sick if they do not rest at this hour.
It's fine.
If it was an exorcist,
it may be something that youkai can't touch.
Let's get them out of there as soon as possible.
Can you run?
No, I...
This way!
Out of the way! Out of the way!
The Party of Dogs is coming through!
My student's name is Azuma.
When we lived together,
I once tripped by the river and hurt my leg.
And with its frail arms it carried me like this.
And Azuma became a very good stonewasher.
I wish you could see it.
Its flowers are so beautiful.
Natsume-sama, here! This is Uratani!
Find traces left by an exorcist or places the exorcist might've sealed someone away.
Okay.
I will search too.
Sensei, why are you so sullen?
I'm not sullen.
Anyway, even if you find them, it may be too late.
Azuma!
What do you mean, Sensei?
Calm down!
They'll survive!
What? Don't scare me.
Fool!
The stonewasher power is very delicate.
A single taint, and that power...
Huh?
Being sealed by an exorcist probably tainted them.
Azuma!
I'm afraid that even if you break the seal,
they probably won't be able to keep being a stonewasher.
Azuma!
Nanamaki's aware of this, obviously.
Then we really need to find it.
Azuma!
I found something, Natsume!
I sense a spell from this rock.
And there's a little gap.
It may be a sign of something trying to come out.
Thanks, Hinoe.
It won't move.
Of course not. It's got a spell on it.
Well, that's a problem.
I don't think we can touch it.
I will try washing the rock.
It may weaken the spell.
Then my light might be able to destroy the seal.
Thank you, Nyanko-dono.
The flower design is disappearing.
Now open, seal laid by the weak!
The seal's been broken!
Azuma!
Us too!
Us too! Too! Too!
Push! Push!
Push!
It's empty!
What's going on?
Was this not the spot?
No, I sense Azuma.
It made it out on its own?
But then where is it?
Why can't we see it?
Why?
That's because...
It probably cannot be a stonewasher anymore.
So it hid itself.
It can't wash the 80,000 stones again.
It can't go back without fulfilling its duty.
And it's too ashamed to go back to the one they love.
Thank you for everything.
What will you do now?
There is no point in going home.
I will go on a journey in search of Azuma.
I shall wash the rocks as I travel.
If it sees my rocks, it may come out.
It may come after me again.
Your flowers are quite beautiful, after all.
The first big rock I saw and the tiny rocks by the river with flowers on them were so beautiful.
River?
I have not gone to the river.
Huh? But...
I have avoided rivers ever since I hurt my leg.
Then those flowers...
Nanamaki-sama, let's go!
What? Where?
This is indeed...
Azuma!
Come on out!
Your teacher Nanamaki is here for you!
Azuma!
I miss you!
I have come to see you!
Azuma!
Nanamaki-sama, I can't go back now.
I wanted to go back to that beautiful village as a full-fledged stonewasher.
But that can't happen now.
I can't wash the stones anymore.
After...
After all you taught me!
I can't...
I am so glad...
I am so glad I saw you again.
If you cannot go back, then let us go on a journey.
If we go together,
I am sure that we will find a beautiful place.
If you cannot go back,
then let us find a new place to go back to.
Fujima village is said to be beautiful.
Will they find a place that can replace it?
I hope they find one someday.
Sheesh.
Another stonewasher gone, huh?
Yeah.
Azuma's heart must hurt deeply from not being able to fulfill its dream.
Hmph!
Wounds get better with some good food and sleep.
Sensei, they're not you.
I need to thank the mid-ranks somehow.
A beautiful place.
A beautiful flower.
Takashi-kun, are you studying?
Huh? Touko-san!
How pretty!
Flowers?
No, this is...
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
Nitai-sama
Shibata?
As in that Shibata?
It becomes a spell doll called Nitai-sama.
I wish there was more I could do.
I'm sorry, Tanuma.
Natsume!
You do know something!