Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
I'm so tired.
Hey, Natsume, carry me.
No way.
It'll just make me hotter.
What?!
Don't you want to help me out?
You were the one who started talking about Nanatsujiya sweet bean jellies, so we're going to get some.
Are you okay?
Ow...
My hips.
I'm sorry. Can you help me?
Sure.
Here.
Huh?
Young man, my home is nearby. Will you take me there?
Huh? Okay, sure.
Where is it?
Over there.
It's far.
That's the next town over.
The Stump of the Suzunaru Tree
He's light.
Do elderly people's bodies get like this?
Hey, that's Natsume of the Book of Friends, right?
Eek! We'd better run away before he calls our names!
You've got something interesting, young one.
Oh no. Is he a youkai?
You finally noticed? Idiot.
Sensei, you need to point that stuff out.
His aura is on the verge of getting snuffed out,
so I was waiting to see how long it'd take you to notice.
We're almost there, young one.
See that lantern up ahead?
I live right next to it.
I'm finally back.
Sorry, young one, but could you could get me some water?
This is your home?
It's not where I live. It's who I am.
I remember hearing about this tree this morning.
The ringing tree's been cut down.
The ringing tree?
Yeah. Look.
A shrine in the next town had a tree that was hundreds of years old,
More Than
200 Year Old
"Ringing"
Gingko Tree
Cut Down
Today After
It Was
Damaged By
Lighting
but it was struck by lightning the other day.
Oh my.
That was awful.
Suddenly everything went white.
What—
I almost ended up as lumber.
I feel revived.
Hey, Natsume. How long are you going to stay here?
The jelly will sell out.
You're right.
Okay, we're leaving.
Wait.
Natsume, is there one other thing you can for this old man?
It'd better not be trouble.
It's nothing that bad.
I want you to bring water here for a few days.
Huh?
Not that long.
This tree's life will end soon, as will mine.
But there's one thing that needs to be done.
I made a promise with a certain human.
It's a very important promise,
and I cannot disappear without fulfilling it.
What is it?
Natsume, ignore him.
It is...
You see, it is...
I forget.
What?
The lightning was a big shock, you see.
But I remembered that there was a promise, so I used the last of my power to return.
It feels like if I talk with you, a human,
then I'll be able to remember something.
So bring water for a while, and if every day is
too much trouble, then you can skip rainy days.
Uh, Shigeru-san, about the ringing tree that you were talking about this morning...
It got an article in the paper,
so does that mean it was famous?
Yes.
We always saw it on our way to the shrine during festivals.
It was a big and impressive tree.
I see.
Actually, I was going for a walk nearby, so I decided to go take a look.
Oh? How'd it look?
There was just a stump.
I see.
That's kind of sad.
Why do they call it the ringing tree, Shigeru-san?
I don't know.
I think there was some kind of old legend.
You made another stupid promise.
You're the one who told me to care more for others.
And despite what he said,
you don't know when he'll disappear.
He may outlive you.
He might?
That's how the lives of trees work.
They don't just disappear once they become a seedling.
Of course, I don't know about a youkai given life by that tree.
Sensei, I didn't make it just out of sympathy.
He said it was a promise with a human, right?
I want to know what kind of promise a human and a youkai can make.
You're such a pain in the butt.
Could the person you made the promise to see you as well?
I couldn't say.
Sometimes I seemed to be human.
Mostly to young children, though.
Have you ever heard of a person named Natsume Reiko?
Reiko?
I have not.
Does she have something to do with the thing you're carrying?
Seems I shouldn't have asked.
You have your own reasons.
I won't ask more.
I'm tired, so I'll sleep for a while.
Thanks for helping me today.
For a while after, I went to the stump every day.
It felt like doing a part-time job.
Oh, so you got the same homework?
We decided to go to Tanuma's place to do it.
I'm in!
How about you, Natsume?
Sorry, but I have something to do.
I see.
Bye.
Yeah.
Bye, Natsume.
See you later, Natsume.
A way to get memories back, huh?
If lightning did it, why not have him get struck by lightning again, and maybe he'll get better?
Lightning! Blightning!
No way.
I'll look for a good medicine.
Thanks, Hinoe.
You could simply order us to water it.
Yeah.
On days I can't go, please do.
Of course.
You can just leave it to the Party of Dogs!
You sure can!
Thanks.
Nobody ever comes this way, huh?
They made a new trail to the shrine.
See?
It's close to the path traveled by something called a "bus."
So that's the main trail now.
They used to walk by here.
I watched the people go up and back from above the trees.
They looked so happy.
Don't worry.
The time is coming for me to
return to the ground, that's all.
As long as I'm here, the other trees can't receive the power I must give them.
I feel bad for them.
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
Oh, right. I found out where the name "ringing tree" came from.
The ginkgo tree on the road to the shrine?
Yeah, I got curious, so I asked a friend.
It has that name because sometimes the rustling of the leaves made a sound like ringing bells.
I see.
But not everyone could hear it.
Hey, it's almost time for the festival.
It's a shame the tree's gone, but why don't we go see it?
Sounds great.
How about it, Takashi?
I'd love to go.
What are you looking at, Natsume?
You don't have to go today, right?
Yeah.
With all this rain, he'll be fine for a day or two.
Yeah, you're right.
I'll go take a look, Sensei.
Sheesh.
My leaves sounded like bells?
Oh, that was my specialty.
When I had many leaves here, as I swung my staff,
all the leaves would ring at once.
Especially during the festival, I'd swing it as hard as I could.
I remember. That promise was...
It was a child's hand.
It was the last year the festival passed by here.
Are you sure?
I remember being sad thinking it was the last time.
It was after that.
I can't remember...
The sun's setting.
It's time for the children of men to go home, right?
Yeah.
See you tomorrow.
Natsume, thanks for coming today.
According to Shigeru-san, the festival passed by the ginkgo tree until 20 years ago.
If they were a child then, they must be around 30 or so?
You're not planning on finding them and asking what their promise was, right?
It's been 20 years. They probably forgot.
They won't remember a promise with a youkai.
Then the day of the festival came...
We're almost there.
It's near the lamps.
Yeah.
No one uses this path anymore, huh?
Is this it?
Yeah, it must be this.
What a shame...
It feels like losing an old friend.
Yeah, definitely!
You remembered?
It must be because of the festival.
The events of that night have come back to me.
The night of the festival,
there was a single child who didn't go with the others and just stood alone on the path.
God?
It's been so long since a human could see me.
That makes me happy.
You smell good.
Huh?
Because we own a bakery, maybe?
It's the shop in front of the station three stops from here.
It's the best around here!
I asked why she seemed so upset.
I was supposed to come with Sac-chan.
But we got in a fight.
Sac-chan was the florist's daughter
from next door and her best friend.
You could just make up.
But I can't see her now.
She's in the hospital.
And she can't come to the festival because it'll spread.
Please, God! Heal her!
I'm not a god, so I can't do that.
And I can't move from here.
I know. In exchange...
When she gets better, come here.
I'll show you something more amazing, and I'm sure you two will make up.
It's a promise.
Yeah, definitely!
I promise!
What's this?
You don't know about pinkie swearing?
Pinkie swearing?
Yep.
It's a spell that makes promises come true.
It was the only time I did this pinkie swear thing.
And what happened to her?
She was just a child.
She probably thought it was a dream
after she went home and calmed down.
I waited every day for her to come.
Did her friend get better?
Did something happen to her?
I worried, but I couldn't leave this place.
There was no way to check.
Why are you searching for the girl he made the promise with?
Excuse me.
Yes?
Is there a bakery around here?
What? A bakery?
Do you mean the one next door?
They moved years ago, though.
Huh? Next door?
Did a girl live there 20 years ago?
Notice of Closure
I see. An elderly man you know made a promise.
He says he just now remembered.
He can't move, so I came in his stead.
I got in a fight with Ai-chan over something silly and was hospitalized before we could make up.
In the end, I couldn't go to the festival.
And then...
she was gone.
Huh?
It was a car accident.
He must've regretted saying he'd show her the leaves of the ginkgo tree sounding like bells.
He made a promise he couldn't fulfill.
But isn't the ringing tree gone anyway?
I see.
So she didn't forget the promise.
Yes.
Then there's no need to wait anymore.
You promised to come until I remembered, right?
You don't have to come tomorrow.
I remembered because someone was here to talk to me.
Thank you, Natsume.
Oh my.
This was the tree Ai-chan wanted me to see, right?
Oh, I know.
I looked for it after I saw you yesterday.
She made it to give to me.
Her mother gave it to me instead.
Ai-chan...
I'm sorry I couldn't keep our promise.
Okay, I'll be going.
Say hi to your elderly friend, okay?
Thank him for remembering the past.
I will.
What is it?
The ginkgo tree youkai was cheerful for a while after that.
I kept bringing him water, until one day...
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana