Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
Dang it.
We're holding our study session on the mountain this year?
I wish we could've gone to the sea.
They're making us study, so who cares either way?
I care!
The best moments of youth come in the gaps between studying!
Right, Natsume?
You'd rather go to the beach and set off fireworks, right?
I heard we can set off fireworks if we get permission.
That's not the problem!
Hey! Wait!
The water's so clear, huh?
Every year, the school holds a three day long study camp for volunteers.
Even if it's mostly studying,
we clean not just the school building,
but we go out and clean the riverside and mountain itself.
It's fun and relaxing.
This year, we've been assigned a small shrine on the other side of the river.
What do they worship here?
Oh, I've heard about this.
Take a look.
Let me see.
You too, Natsume and Tanuma.
Huh?
You okay, Natsume?
Yeah.
It seems to be in good shape.
You don't really feel anything either, do you?
Nope.
Hurry.
Excuse me.
Masks?
What Flows
See those masks?
This is called Four Mask Hill.
I see.
So that's why there are four masks.
Four Mask Hill?
Even though there's only three?
Huh?
That's right.
It's Four Mask Hill, but there are only three masks.
Everyone else only sees three?
So one of them is a youkai?
I heard this from my brothers, so I don't know reliable it is,
but they say the god of the mountain once lived here.
Then he moved up the mountain, and four of his followers stayed here to protect the mountain and god.
That's the story.
That's kind of romantic.
How?
Huh?
They don't seem evil or anything,
but masks are always kind of creepy, huh?
Yeah.
Let's finish cleaning up.
They are a little creepy,
but if they're youkai that protect the mountain god,
we should be fine as long as we don't make contact with them.
No way, Nomiya-sensei!
We're eating meals separate from the girls? Seriously?
The girls are eating in the new building up the mountain, and the boys are eating in the old building here.
The cafeterias are cramped, you see.
Why did we even come here?
The boys and girls are taking turns with the baths.
What?!
Nomiya-sensei, the boys are being perverted.
Sasada, why you—
What?
Mind your own business!
It's true, right?
It's started to rain.
Wow, the river's overflowing.
It's a flood.
This building might flood too.
Hey, don't say that.
Maybe it really will...
Hey, stop making a fuss.
Get ready to sleep.
We'll be okay here, right?
The new building's on high ground.
If we have to, we can evacuate—
So we'll be with the girls?!
You idiot!
There's not a trace left of that rain from yesterday.
The water's gone down, but stay away from the river.
Okay.
All right, time for morning self-study.
I'll be in the night watch room.
Okay.
N-Nyanko-sensei?!
What's wrong, Natsume?
I-I'm going to the bathroom.
Hey, Nyanko-sensei!
What are you doing here?
How'd you even get here?
I snuck into your bag, of course.
No wonder it felt heavy!
I heard there's a sake spring around here,
so I'm looking for it.
But after that big rain, I can't find it.
Help me.
I'm here to study!
Jeez. Make sure nobody sees you, Sensei.
How embarrassing would it be if they
saw me taking my cat to a study camp?
It's a little late for that.
You always worry about little things like—
What's wrong, Sensei?
A boat.
After a rain like that?
Idiot! Don't look at her!
That woman kept her face under the water as she slowly passed by in her boat.
I don't think she was human.
There you are, Natsume.
You were in the bathroom a long time,
so we came to look for you.
You slacking off?
Wait, Natsume. That cat...
Huh?
Oh, this is...
What a pain.
Just this once.
Huh? It's not a cat.
I saw a stray cat...
Is that a boar piglet?
That's right. It's a boar piglet.
Huh? A boar piglet?
Hey, you kids!
It's study time!
Oh crap!
You can laugh if you want, Tanuma.
I'll have to tell Taki about Nyanko-sensei's boar piglet version.
Please don't.
It'd turn into a mess.
Yummy Nyanko-sensei!
Stop it...
Yeah, you're right.
Anyway, what was with that boat?
It seemed like it was just going down the river.
I don't have to worry about it, do I?
Natsume, are you done with the worksheet?
Yes, I'm—
Natsume?
Huh?
Tanuma doesn't see it.
What's wrong? Are you okay?
Yeah...
I'm pretty sure that's one of the masks from Four Masks Hill.
Okay, you're done.
Um, Nomiya-sensei.
Are you feeling sick at all?
Like you have a headache, or you're feeling drowsy?
No, not really.
Nomiya-sensei, it's not fair that we're the only ones who have to do this!
Why are you complaining when you skipped study hall?
We were looking for Natsume!
And Natsume finished already.
Huh? He did?
So I guess I'm the only one who can see that mask?
Seriously?
If Tanuma can't see it, then it's probably a wimp.
Leave it alone.
But would it attach itself to someone's face for no reason?
It's a little creepy.
Sure it's creepy, but it doesn't have the power to control him, so it may as well not exist, right?
Well, whatever.
If you're that worried, I'll take a look at this mask.
Thanks...
That's pretty kind for you, Sensei.
I'm more bored than I thought I would be.
Where's Nomiya-sensei?
Sensei, can you hear the sound of water?
What is this feeling?
I hear something like a river.
Like the river that thing was flowing down.
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
Is that because of the rain yesterday?
But why now?
I have to tell the teachers.
Natsume?
Tanuma.
Hey, is that a leak, or did the river level rise?
Huh?
Where?
Tanuma!
Do you see something, Natsume?
Yeah.
Water coming from down the hall.
Water?
No, it looks more like a river than just water.
The river's getting closer and closer to me.
Is this something scary?
Or is it okay?
Oh, I know.
It's this feeling.
The fear of the unknown.
Natsume, you should stay away from that river.
If you can't see it, it won't swallow you up,
but if you can, it may drag you along with its flow.
That's how a flow works.
Yeah.
I understand.
Then you might get dragged along, right, Sensei?
Come on, Natsume. We should get away too.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Huh?
No, I'm sorry.
Hey, it's time for class.
What is that mask thinking?
And it's right there!
Does it have something to do with the water and the woman in the boat?
Natsume?
Are you okay?
You look pale.
Thanks, but I'm fine.
Even when I'm worried like this,
there are people who are watching out for me.
I can see when things aren't right.
I have to be careful not to involve my friends in anything weird.
I'm starving.
Why is that mask going from one person to another?
It was on Four Masks Hill.
So why?
Natsume, what do you think we're having for dinner?
Good question.
Hey!
Go away!
Natsume!
If you do anything to my friend, I'll make you pay!
What's wrong, Natsume?
I apologize.
Did it move to someone else?
Natsume? Are you okay?
Hey, Natsume!
The river's closer than before!
Where are you going, Natsume?
Four Masks Hill!
It looks like that mask isn't doing anything bad!
You're a student staying at the inn across the hill?
Do you know this area well?
I'm a priest nearby.
I'm in charge of this shrine, as well.
I was worried after the rain yesterday, so I came to check on it.
Is there anything wrong with it?
Oh, are you talking about how there are only three masks?
A strange name, isn't it?
But I kind of like it.
Um, do you know any details about the masks?
I'm kind of interested in them.
Like why are there only three?
Well...
In the distant past, a mountain goddess lived here,
protected by four followers.
One day, she fell in love with a human.
But the man's life came to an end, and he left this world.
The goddess was heartbroken,
and, taking with her a single hair ornament given to her by the man, she hid herself on top of the mountain.
The four followers stayed here to protect the goddess and the mountain.
As the years passed, the four all lost their powers and disappeared.
They thought the goddess would be sad if she learned they disappeared as well,
so before they disappeared, they first crafted masks of themselves and put them up in the shrine.
Then these three masks...
It means three of them have disappeared.
But it's still only three.
If there are only three masks on Four Masks Hill,
that means there's still one hope.
There's still one out there,
protecting the mountain and its goddess.
The four followers who protected the mountain goddess...
Three are gone, but one remains.
Somehow, I understand.
The boat in the river,
and the head poked into the water, never looking up.
They were looking for something.
Where were you?
Nishimura...
I'm sorry for being weird back there.
Jeez, don't get so scared by a bug.
Huh?
But that means you were worried about me, right?
Thanks.
Washed away...
It was washed away...
I'm sorry...
It was washed away somewhere...
The goddess'...
I'm sorry...
It was washed away somewhere...
The goddess' treasured...
I know.
Oh...
I hear the sound of a drifting boat somewhere.
Hey, Natsume. It's not even dawn yet.
You look too.
Look? For what?
I'm not exactly sure.
What?
I think that during the flood something very
important to the goddess was washed away.
I think that mask was going from Nomiya-sensei to the other students looking for it.
The goddess'...
The heartbroken goddess' treasure.
Hmph.
I can see more this way.
You look under there.
Sensei...
I want to finish this up and get some sleep.
There it is.
A hairpin.
This is what that mask wanted to find.
He wanted to help the goddess who lost her treasured hairpin and wouldn't raise her head above the water
as she searched high and low.
Is this what you're looking for?
The one who protects you was looking for it.
He was still there for me?
Did the mountain goddess return to the top of the mountain?
Probably.
But I'm sure she realized that there's still
someone here who believes in and protects her.
Yeah.
As the years passed, they lost their power,
and three disappeared.
The last one probably has little power left.
It clung to people's faces, but it didn't control them.
It just went from one to another,
appearing in dreams, with its words so soft.
But even so, it's still there.
I'm sure it's still there.
Nyanko-sensei boar piglet version!
So soft and fluffy!
Wait!
We can finally go home!
Hey, where's that piglet?
Taki's saying goodbye.
Soft and fluffy!
Hey, Tanuma, how many masks do you see?
Three.
I see.
Stay well.
Natsume-kun, Tanuma-kun, the bus is leaving!
Right!
Four Masks Hill is a strange place.
I'm sure there will always be only three masks there.
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
The Sealed Room
Maybe I'll learn something about Reiko-san.
Will you help me?
Even if somebody denies me, I'm not as scared as I used to be.
I'm in a place where I can feel that way now.
Have you ever heard of the "Book of Friends"?