Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
97. 98. 99.
100.
101. 102.
103.
One, two, three.
Hey, isn't that Tamami?
You're right.
She's up to something again.
28, 29...
Tamami!
What are you doing?
Nothing important!
Go home before it gets too late!
Bye!
Got it!
Guess I'll have to start over.
38, 39, 40.
41, 42, 43.
61, 62, 63.
Turn south.
One, two, three.
A Fragment of Fantasy
Oh no!
I fell asleep eating my lunch!
If my friends saw me like this,
I'm sure they'd laugh at me again.
It's because of that dream I had.
I'm a little behind on sleep.
I'm sure of it. This way.
I knew it.
Right on the other side of these bushes!
Somebody's coming.
But why?
Why do I smell...
fried shrimp here in the forest?
A-A-A talking cat!
Oops!
She heard me so clearly that there's no getting out of this!
Th-This is impossible.
Am I dreaming again?
Yeah, that's it!
You're dreaming.
Why is a cat talking?
Is that even a cat?
I'm definitely a cute, little cat!
Calm down, me! Calm down, calm down!
Calm down!
Have you calmed down, girl?
Y-Yes...
Listen.
This is a dream.
So there's nothing odd about a talking cat.
I see!
I'm glad you understand.
This feeling...
It's like Alice in Wonderland!
Ice? Ice cream?
Alice!
Alice?
Can you eat that?
You're a silly kitty.
It's Nyanko-sensei!
Sensei?
That was so good.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So what are you doing here, Nyanko-sensei?
I'm a great youkai, you see?
And I have a human boy as a servant.
That escalated quickly...
But he's so wimpy and frail,
has a mean look, and always runs off.
Have you seen him?
No.
I see.
Anyway, what are you doing here?
Well...
Over there!
Wh-What was that scream?
Bye, girl!
This isn't a normal forest.
Go home, now.
Nyanko-sensei!
Wait!
Where are you, Nyanko-sensei?
Did I just imagine it?
I guess this really isn't a normal forest.
Calm down.
Don't get scared.
I have something I need to do.
Somebody's there!
Excuse me!
Um...
Um, I want to ask about this forest.
Stop! Don't get any closer!
Um...
I'm sorry.
You're... human?
Huh?
Of course.
What's a human doing here?
Um, uh...
You're human too, right?
You're still here, girl?
Nyanko-sensei!
Wh—
Why are you talking around her, Sensei?
She seems to think it's a dream.
It'll work out.
Don't pinch the kitty!
What if it doesn't work out?
Don't worry.
When she does leave this forest...
Huh?
Well, it's not your problem.
Um...
Sorry for startling you.
I was following the kit— Nyanko-sensei,
and I thought I saw something
weird that looked like a monster.
I got scared and...
Huh? You saw it?
Yes.
This forest is its own little world.
There may be moments when you
can see things you normally couldn't.
Sensei...
Is there really something here?
This is called the Forest of the Gospel,
and it's ruled by a divine protector-class youkai.
Don't worry. Nobody here is that weird.
Nobody?
I was almost attacked.
You're special.
I don't understand, but this place is amazing.
I'll take you to the exit.
What?
You shouldn't stay too long in a place you don't understand.
Let's go.
I-I'm sorry, I um...
I can't go back yet.
Huh?
Hey, have you see a white owl in this forest?
A white owl asked me to come here.
An owl asked you to come?
Oh, um... Sorry for saying something so absurd.
No, I'm curious.
Huh?
Can you tell me more?
No. You'll just laugh at me.
I won't.
I promise.
It started a few days ago...
On the way home from school,
as I was walking under a big tree...
You said you wouldn't laugh!
I'm not laughing.
I just don't get what's going on.
Basically, there was a white owl tangled up in a fishing line and hanging from a branch.
I thought I should help it, so...
Ow...
J-Just wait, okay?
I managed to get the line off the branch.
Whew...
Just wait.
I'll get it off your leg.
This is what it got tangled on, huh?
Got it!
That's good.
Now there's the wound on your forehead.
What do I do?
There's no vet near...
Can you fly?
Huh?
This is the ring.
The owl flew off before I could attach it again.
It's got this pretty red stone on it,
so I kept it so I could give it back if I saw the owl again.
And then last night...
It's the owl.
It's saying something.
A hundred and three steps to the west from that tree.
Forty to the north.
Sixty-three to the east.
Clap your hands in prayer,
then take three steps to the south.
When you turn around, you will find the entrance.
I live in that forest.
I cannot leave for a while.
Please come to return my stone.
I know it was just a dream,
but when I think about how the owl might be in trouble because of me...
So today I brought the ring, made a lunch, did what it said, and came here.
I see.
Where's the owl?
I looked, but I can't find it.
So I took a break, and that's when I met Nyanko-sensei.
Those fried shrimp were delicious.
Huh?
Were those from your lunch?
I have to give this back, so...
I'll look for the ruler of this forest.
I'll help you find the owl while I'm at it.
Huh?!
You what?!
Thank you!
Um, I'm Tamami!
What's your name?
I'm...
Sorry.
I won't say.
If we meet again in the future,
it'd be bad if you knew my name.
Will we meet again?
I'll ask you again if we do.
Okay.
Let's go look.
Jeez, you're buying me one of those new bean-jam dumplings from Nanatsujiya when we get back.
Hey, their new bean-jam dumpling!
C'mon! Answer me!
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
He was a strange boy.
He talked to trees with nothing on them.
I see.
Thank you.
He looked up at the sky and nodded.
He suddenly grabbed my hand and started running.
Everything he did was strange.
But it was fun and exciting!
It was like...
I was Alice in Wonderland!
I'm tired.
Look.
Over there.
Huh?
In the gap between the roots of that big tree.
Sorry.
I found what I'm looking for first.
Huh?
I'll be right back.
Isn't that great?
Got it.
Good luck.
It's so pretty.
Reiko's grandson?
Yes.
I heard that the entrance to this forest,
which is usually closed, had finally opened,
so I came to return your name.
Thank you for coming.
I'm sorry for binding your name for so long.
You who protect me, show me your name.
Hakuhi.
Please accept this.
It feels good, huh?
Truly.
I knew it.
You're no ordinary owl.
How could you tell?
No owl carries something like that on their ankle in the human world.
Let me guess.
If you're an owl, does that make you the protector of a forest?
Something like that.
Knew it.
What's an amazing youkai like you doing in a place like this?
Sometimes I go to purify myself in
the lakes on the youkai mountain in order to remove the evil aura of the forest.
Hey, you don't have to head back immediately, right?
Want to play a game with me?
You are lonely too, are you not?
When you are alone for so long, you want to talk to someone.
Here we go...
A white owl?
Yes.
When I leave the forest, I take the form of a white owl.
That wound...
Are you the owl who summoned a girl into this forest?
How do you know about that?
She came to this forest to return the stone.
Really?
That is great.
Are you sure about this?
If a youkai starts talking to a normal girl in her dreams, showing itself to her, calling her places,
and she tells somebody,
the people around her will think she's strange.
It is fine.
As long as I have the stone, it is fine.
Huh?
I have the power to erase her memories of saving me in my owl form
and of coming to the forest where
those who live in the shadows dwell.
You need not worry, grandson of Reiko.
That means...
You'll erase her memories?
Please don't!
You can't steal even a single second
from someone without their permission!
She came here to give it back to you because she wanted to help you!
As the guardian of the forest,
anyone who sees me,
except for priests or priestesses,
or those like you who can see us,
must forget or not be allowed to return alive.
Allowed to return alive?
This was my own failure.
I cannot leave the forest now,
so I asked her to bring the stone here to me.
I will erase her memories and send her back.
It's the best exception I can make.
But—
Some laws can't be broken, Natsume.
I must take that stone.
Please lead me there.
My eyes are not that good.
When I flew in the world of men for the first time in ages,
it was filled with new shapes and colors.
It must have blinded me.
I failed.
I failed greatly.
Welcome... back.
The owl!
Thank you!
You found it for me?
I'm so glad I met you again.
It's like a dream!
Is your wound okay?
I'm sorry.
I brought your ring.
Here.
Stick your leg out.
I'll put it on.
Can I take this fragment?
I'll treasure it.
Thank you.
See you later.
I'm sure we'll meet—
It is a shame to be forgotten.
It was a voice I thought I knew, but I didn't.
What was that?
It was such a wonderful dream.
Oh no!
What happened?!
I was sleeping on a park bench?
Goodbye.
What was that?
It was warm and fuzzy.
Like I was dreaming.
A stone?
It's pretty.
It's so pretty, isn't it?
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana