Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
Takashi-kun, can you get that?
Oh, sure!
This is the Fujiwara residence.
Oh, it's you, Natsume. How've you been?
Um, who is this?
You can't tell? Shibata!
Shibata?
Shibata... You mean that Shibata?
What's with the "that"?
Shibata was an old classmate of mine.
He fell in love with a youkai.
And then, he also found out that I could see youkai.
Hey, want to meet up? It's been forever.
Come here tomorrow.
You don't have any weekend plans, right?
He's not a bad guy, but he's inconsiderate and we don't really get along.
I've got plans with a friend tomorrow, sorry.
Bye.
A friend? You?
Yeah.
Does he know that you can see them?
Shibata!
It's starting!
Let's go!
Yeah, I'm on my way.
Bring him too.
I'll get you at the station at noon.
Bye.
Huh? Wait—
Shibata!
Nitai-sama
Sorry, Tanuma. I was planning on going to your house.
Don't worry about it.
As long as we're back by dark, it's okay.
The guy we're about to meet, Shibata...
If he weirds you out even a little, tell me and we'll go home.
It's fine.
And you too, Sensei.
Shibata thinks you're just a cat, so don't act weird.
Don't worry.
As long as I can hit up the cake shops in this town,
I don't care about you.
Oh, Natsume!
I thought you were gonna blow me off for sure.
What?!
You've still got that ugly cat with you, huh?
So? This is your friend?
Yeah, this is Tanuma.
Hello. I'm Tanuma Kaname.
I'm Shibata Katsumi. Nice to meet you.
But you know, you look like a beanpole.
Natsume doesn't look like a beanpole!
Tanuma doesn't look like a beanpole!
Okay, I'll treat you to someplace good.
Follow me!
Wait, what?
Shibata!
Great, huh?
Yeah.
This is...
Why are you spacing out, Natsume?
Oh, no reason.
I'm paying for this. Chew thoroughly.
Right, right.
Shibata is still as forceful as ever,
but I'm a little relieved to see he's doing well.
So your dad's a priest, Tanuma?
So can you see ghosts?
Shibata!
Unfortunately, I can't.
But my dad tells me scary stories and rumors all the time.
Huh? He does?
Then have you ever heard of the Doll Mansion of Sotogi?
The Doll Mansion...
...of Sotogi?
Just forget I said anything.
What? Tell me.
This isn't what we're here for today.
But now I'm interested.
Tell me, Shibata.
I come to this park all the time.
You know how girls love me, right?
Get to the point.
There's an elementary school girl who comes here.
She's kind of a brat, but lately she hasn't been doing well.
I asked her why.
Several days ago, lightning struck the house next to hers.
And ever since then,
she hears weird sounds from that house at night.
She said she's too scared to sleep.
Weird sounds?
Apparently, it sounds like something rolling around.
But nobody's lived in that house for a long time.
An empty house, huh?
That's weird.
Is that the Doll Mansion of Sotogi?
Yeah.
Is there some reason they call it the Doll Mansion?
Well, just like the name suggests,
the last owner collected dolls and stuff.
This is it.
I think a cat or a dog might've moved in.
What's wrong, Natsume?!
Huh? Oh, nothing.
Th-There was a big bug.
A bug?
Don't scare me.
This is bad.
I met the gaze of something strange.
Huh?
Then you're going to stay at Tanuma's place tonight?
Yeah.
Tanuma's dad's going to be away tonight because of a meeting, so we're watching the place.
Sounds like you're actually having some fun, huh, Natsume?
Seriously, if you really had something to do, you could've just told me to go away.
I tried!
I'm gonna hit the bathroom.
What? We're still talking!
Hey, Natsume.
You saw something, didn't you?
Yeah.
So, sorry, but I don't think I'm going to stay over tonight.
It might follow me.
If you wanna fight off something like that, you're better off at a temple, Natsume.
What do you mean, "fight off"?!
You're sure they're going to follow me?!
I don't mind, Natsume.
But...
You don't want Touko and Shigeru involved, right?
Yeah, but...
Don't worry.
My place is better equipped to deal with youkai, right?
Huh?
Tanuma...
Hey, what does he mean by "deal with youkai"?!
Shibata.
Damn it, Natsume!
You really did see something, didn't you?!
Why are you coming with me?
I got you caught up in this.
If a ghost is following you, I'll fight it too.
You just met Tanuma today.
You can't just stay at his place!
I don't care.
We're not playing around here!
Of course!
I'm the one who didn't keep my mouth shut even though I knew what you can see.
Let me do something too.
I'm back.
Come in.
Thanks for having me.
Wow, this place is huge.
I'm just living in a condo.
I bet hide and seek here must be great.
I always wanted to do that.
Hey, what do we do for dinner?
We make it, of course.
You help too, Shibata.
Why?
What are you making?
Isn't it obvious?
Rice omelettes?
Fried rice.
I'm the master of rice omelettes.
He just said we're making fried rice!
This is good fried rice.
Yeah, it's pretty good.
What's wrong, Shibata? Not hungry?
Hey, have you ever heard of the twin dolls?
The twin dolls?
No.
I didn't mention it because I didn't want to scare you for nothing,
but the reason the person who lived in that house was collecting dolls...
was to make dolls they could use for spells.
Spells?
Yeah.
I don't really know much about it,
but I guess you can put snakes and bugs in a box and make them eat each other,
and then use the last thing that survives in a curse.
He was doing the same thing with dolls.
He'd pack a room with all kinds of dolls that met some set of conditions,
and then he'd leave the house for a specific number of days.
When he came back, all the dolls were broken somehow.
But if two of the dolls were unharmed, the ritual had succeeded.
And they become enchanted dolls called "the twin dolls."
Supposedly, the person who was
living there told everyone about it.
Everyone just called him a weirdo, though.
But one day, he started screaming,
"The twins are here! The twins are here!"
He ran out of the house and never came back.
All that was left was the rumor about the Doll Mansion.
What do you think?
What do I think?
That feels too real to be just a rumor.
It's just a scary story the girls told me, though.
But they have to be mistaken, right?
Dolls, huh?
I see.
Huh?
What I saw in the window
was the faces of two dolls.
Why are you telling us this now?!
I'll be too scared to shower alone!
It's your fault for bringing it up!
It's just the wind, Shibata.
I-I know.
I'll go lock the doors.
Though I don't know if the twin dolls are coming.
Wait, Tanuma!
Where are you going?!
It'll be scary with even one less person here!
Shibata, calm down!
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
The doors are locked,
and Shibata finally went to take his shower.
I never thought he was such a scaredy-cat.
But he came with us anyway, huh?
Yeah.
Still, I don't want him getting any deeper into this.
Tanuma, if the twin dolls do come,
Nyanko-sensei and I will deal with them.
So can you keep him far away?
Got it.
Sorry for always dragging you into this stuff.
It makes me happy.
Huh?
Sometimes it's scary,
but I'd be more scared if you
insisted on keeping me in the dark.
I'd actually prefer to help you more,
but just hearing you tell me what to do makes me think maybe you're counting on me.
It makes me kind of happy.
It's not an "if."
They're definitely coming.
They'll follow your scent.
Sensei.
And for youkai that were created by ritual magic, someone with strong power like you is a feast.
You'll help of course, right, Sensei?
Yes, if you're willing to give me this melon I found in the fridge.
Sure.
Then negotiations are successful!
Natsume, you too.
Next time it's fried shrimp for dinner, you have give them all to me!
That's very greedy, Sensei.
What's that sound?
What's wrong, Natsume?
Natsume?
What happened?
I just saw a doll's legs.
It went toward the kitchen.
So that's what gave me that headache.
Huh?
You okay, Tanuma?
Yeah. More importantly, was that...
That was probably one of the twin dolls.
It's got my name on it now.
So they did come.
That girl was talking about lightning hitting the house.
That probably broke the door on the room the dolls were in and set them free.
Even with a vessel, the thing inside still isn't very powerful.
Draw it out from its vessel, and I'll get rid of it for you.
How do we do that?
Hey, Tanuma. You've got a protective talisman or two in this house, right?
A talisman?
Yeah.
I'll find the ones we can use,
and you can put it on the doll's forehead.
Got it.
I'll go check on Shibata.
This is my fault, isn't it?
I think something just went by the window.
Shibata, stay away from the window.
So the dolls are here?
Is there something I can do?
I don't know all that's going on,
but this is because I told you that weird story, right?
Let me take responsibility!
If there's something I can do, let me do it!
Yeah.
Thanks.
I searched all the rooms and only found this one.
I see.
We need another, right?
The only other place I haven't checked is...
the attic.
Shibata, can you go with Tanuma to look for another one of these?
Okay, leave it to me.
We'll come back right away if we find one.
Yeah.
I'll make sure nothing gets in.
The twin dolls won't come in from the roof, will they?
It should be fine.
They'll be drawn to your presence.
You look unhappy.
Why did the person who owned
that house want to cast that spell?
Why did he leave something he wanted in the first place?
Who cares about the reason?
He probably thought he was just playing.
He got scared.
That was...
They came in.
It's coming!
Take this!
One more left...
I need to keep the second doll pinned down
until they can bring back the other talisman.
Oh no! That's...
Damn, it's not coming off.
Make sure you don't break it, Shibata.
I know.
Jeez, this twin dolls thing is such a pain in the ass.
Why would you make something like that?
Did they have that much hate in their hearts? Or...
Humans are scary, aren't they?
Yeah.
If we hadn't noticed those things, we could've ignored them.
But now that we did, we can't ignore it.
Natsume is always dealing with this stuff, isn't he?
Yeah.
I wish there was more I could do.
Just having somebody like you at his side will change a lot.
Got it!
Natsume!
Wait, Shibata!
Something's on top of Natsume!
A youkai?
Shibata, the talisman!
Throw it at Natsume!
Natsume!
Sensei!
Natsume?
Natsume!
Are you okay, Natsume?
What just happened?
Shibata?
Tanuma?
Shibata, it's okay—
I'm sorry, Natsume.
I just wanted to see you again, since it'd been so long.
And I told you that story and got you involved in this...
Oh, now I get what Tanuma told me.
I was happy, Shibata.
Huh?
Even though you lived far away, you remembered me.
You tried to reconnect with me.
You kept talking to me, even though you knew what I am.
It made me happy.
It also made me want to help a friend who'd come to me with a problem.
Several days later, Shibata came to visit me instead.
I thought I should give you an update.
An update?
Yeah.
I went back to the park like always.
That girl said the scary noises stopped coming from the house next door.
She was doing much better.
I guess she has you to thank.
That's just how it ended up.
Well, maybe it's okay for us to think we were responsible as long as we keep it secret.
Yeah.
But you really do have it rough.
Being able to see youkai isn't all fun and games.
Shibata met the youkai many times in that park.
The girl was the spirit of a dying tree,
and Shibata's heart was broken.
I felt a little bad that he might still be going there.
And at the same time, I was happy.
Oh, right.
This is a present.
Give some to Tanuma too.
What's inside?
Rice cakes wrapped in oak leaves.
The ugly cat just started talking like an old...
Natsume, watch out!
This cat's possessed by something!
Nyanko-sensei!
Meow!
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
Lying Eyes
Are you the famous Natsume of the Book of Friends?
Natsume always tells me exactly how he's feeling.
What happened to the familiars that my father commanded?
How would Natori-san feel if I told him?