Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
See us?
You can see us?
Open it. Open it.
I get stuck and can't get in.
Let me in. Let me in.
Let me in, damn it.
Damn it!
The Bound Ones
Get your hands off my prey!
It hurts! It hurts!
Damn it! Damn it!
Stop it. You're an embarrassment.
Give up and begone.
Traitor!
Curse you! Curse you!
Shut up.
Begone!
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I wasn't doing it to help you.
If I let a child of man be hurt on the property,
it would be a problem for my master and the lady.
I told you not to interfere.
You need to leave too!
I'm not here to exorcise you.
What was that thing?
If you know what's going on in this house, tell me.
You're Takuma-san's familiar, right?
Wait!
Sheesh. What a pain.
Thanks, Sensei.
I just drove it off.
Looks like the thing outside can't get in.
It's probably because of those talismans all over the place.
That woman was probably inside before they were put up.
There are still some things I want to ask that ayakashi.
Let's search for her.
Hey! Wait, Natsume!
Light?
Where's it coming from?
A hole?
Natsume?
Are you okay?
Sorry. There was something on the other side of the wall.
The way these talismans are put up makes no sense.
I'll go outside to take a look.
Let me in!
Let's go together.
Be careful.
There's another one.
It's gone.
Urihime, did you see anything?
Hiiragi sensed something around the house and is following it.
Something in this area was looking inside the house.
Find it.
And there's apparently one more around here.
Yes, sir.
Natori-san, when did you start doing things like this?
You mean being an exorcist?
I went to my first meeting in my second year of high school.
That's where I met Takuma-san.
When I was just getting started, he helped me out a lot.
Before that, I would go through the stuff in the storeroom at our house.
Where's this coming from?
Oh, it's nothing.
I really enjoyed seeing you in that movie.
Thanks.
But when I see you doing this stuff,
sometimes I get really worried.
I'm sorry.
I know this isn't my place to talk.
Thank you. I think I understand.
At this point, given how crazy you are, if you started working as an exorcist,
I'd be so worried my heart would burst.
You should be normal.
You should live a normal life.
Natori-san—
Now that he can't see them anymore,
Takuma-san is trying to live a normal life with Tsukiko-san.
Anyone who tries to interfere with that will have me to deal with.
See? I knew it.
They're trying to destroy this wall and bring disaster into the house.
Those aren't human nail marks.
I'll search the outside with my familiars.
You and Sensei go back to Tsukiko-san.
Right.
Natori-san said that Takuma-san had three familiars.
One of them was that woman, and the other two are probably the ones outside the house now.
Do they really hate Takuma-san?
That's strange.
Tsukiko, are you home?
W-Wait!
I'm back.
Don't open—
Who are you—
Get inside, now!
Who are you?
What are you doing in my house?
"I'm not telling you. You failure of an exorcist," huh?
Master, there's no need to trouble yourself over the words of a rude ayakashi.
No.
That's not what's bothering me.
Who are you?
What are you doing in my house?
Um... uh...
Father, he's my guest!
You're home early.
What happened with the play?
I didn't feel like it, so I came home.
Tsukiko, what are you doing behind my back?
I-I'm not...
She called me.
It's been a long time, Takuma-san.
Shuuichi?
Shuuichi.
Tsukiko-san, if this is the work of one of his old familiars, you should tell Takuma-san.
Old familiars?
Yes.
It looks like one of the familiars is inside, and the other two are outside.
I see.
Sometimes, when I was at home or leaving,
I felt like I'd sensed them.
But at this point, I'm not even sure I really did.
I lack the power to release them.
It's natural they'd want me to pass away soon.
So, what do you think I should do, Shuuichi-kun?
If they seem dangerous, I don't think this will stop unless you seal or exorcise them.
Even though I'm the one at fault for abandoning them after I couldn't see them anymore?
Are you going to underestimate them and involve your family in your own fate?
Natori-san!
I'm sure you have your attachment to your familiars,
but I don't want to have regrets if something happens to you.
As Natori-san cautioned,
it's dangerous to underestimate them.
But just because they're close doesn't mean they hate you.
The two outside seem to be out of control, but I think you could talk to the one inside.
You can see them too?
Yes.
Natori-san has helped me a lot.
I see.
Natsume.
Natsume!
Wait!
What should I do?
How can I protect them?
Please tell me if you know.
At this rate, we'll have no choice but to exorcise the ones outside.
I don't want to make Natori-san or Takuma-san do that.
Can you help me?
Oh dear.
When I talk to you, I remember things I don't want to.
Until just a little while ago,
I talked with my master just like this.
If the two outside had tried to hurt my master, I was going to handle them myself.
But if they want freedom, I want you to free them.
Someone with your power may be able to do the ritual of release.
The ritual of release?
Natsume?
Natori-san.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I was right. The ayakashi in the house was trying to protect Takuma-san.
Could I let them see each other again with Taki's circle?
No, but that's...
Natori-san, um...
Is there any kind of spell that can let someone who was once able to see youkai see their own familiars again?
Natsume, like I told you before, those spells are forbidden.
Even for an exorcist and his familiars.
Some of the most dangerous can even curse people who aren't involved.
If you bind their real name, even your normal speech becomes words that they must obey.
There are also cruel spells that allow you to crush their name and take their life.
Well, that's another technique that takes a lot of power and may not actually...
Natsume?
No, it's nothing.
Enough wasting time.
If the sun sets, you'll have a mess on your hands.
Yeah, you're right.
They've started to shatter the roof tiles.
They want in, no matter what.
Before, they were saying...
Open it. Open it.
Let me in!
Why can't they get in, anyway?
That's good question.
It's probably because...
The roof's creaking so much.
Is that the youkai again?
Tsukiko, I'm sorry.
I finally quit being an exorcist after so many years,
and yet I'm still scaring you.
No, if I could see them too...
I could've followed in your footsteps and protected you.
I could've told you what they're saying.
I'm sorry, Father.
I'm sorry...
Tsukiko...
Keep quiet and listen.
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
We told each other that even if he could no longer see us, we would protect our master.
The reason they can't come inside is
because the mistress put up talismans.
It was when they were outside.
They were put up in a crude way.
The little pig and those girl youkai can pass through,
but they block our way.
They aren't very smart.
They believe that our master has
put up a barrier to be rid of them.
That their master has stolen their home.
And so they want to bring disaster here out of revenge?
Will they stop if the talismans are taken down?
Natori-san.
It's too late.
Their hearts have been changed.
There's no telling what they'll do if they come inside.
But if they're released,
then perhaps to some small degree...
Please, do not let the mistress learn of this.
Shuuichi-kun,
is there someone there?
There is.
She's worried about you.
Just like how Tsukiko-san is trying her best to protect you,
that ayakashi is trying to protect this home.
Takuma-san, the ayakashi outside have
their reasons for what they're doing.
Do you know the ritual of release?
It seems I'm capable of doing it.
I made these wooden talismans when I began the contract.
They have the name of the familiars on them.
After covering the name with the blood of the contractor,
you draw a large magic circle.
When the youkai enters,
you chant the spell and break the talisman.
It seems simple, but if your power
is weak the talisman will not break,
and if one of you leaves the circle without it breaking,
it's said that it can be fatal.
A little contract like this will be easy for someone with your power.
Sensei?
But if the youkai tries to leave the circle before the talisman breaks, I'll eat it, even if it makes you complain.
If you want this to have a happy ending, don't screw up.
Right, Sensei.
Natsume.
I'll have my familiars strengthen the area around the circle.
Listen.
If I think it's even a little dangerous, I'll take over breaking the talismans.
Right.
Open up! Open up!
Let me in! Let me in!
Damn it! Damn it!
Hey!
Can you let me do the ritual of release?
That's what Takuma-san wants.
You're the one who can see me?
Is it you? Is it you?
The one who won't let me in!
Listen to me.
It's Takuma!
Takuma! Takuma!
Takuma-san!
It's dangerous! You have to stay inside!
At least let me be here for this.
Takuma!
If they wanted to attack me when I was outside, they could have done it a long time ago.
Listen to me!
A terrible disaster will befall this house soon!
It's a terrifying, terrible disaster!
When the spell is complete, this house will be doomed!
Natori-san!
That day... that day...
You took advantage of the fact
that I left and sealed the house.
But that ends today.
A terrifying, terrible disaster is coming!
It's coming!
It's a terrifying, terrible disaster!
One you can never, ever exorcise.
I'll get rid of it for you!
I'll show you my power!
And then you can let me in again, okay?
I promise...
I promise I'll be useful again.
Takuma...
Takuma.
If I'm useful,
I can be with you again, right?
Natsume, I'll...
I'm fine.
Jinbe, get inside the circle.
Takuma-san wants you to be free.
It's his last wish for you.
Please.
Takuma's... wish?
Benihimo, right?
Takuma-san didn't abandon you.
Even if you could get inside again,
he can't see you or hear your voices.
Takuma! Takuma!
Enter the circle.
Be free.
I break the spell that binds you and release your false names.
Return to whence you came.
I witness the ties that bind you as they break here!
Jinbe, Benihimo, Ginro, are you here?
Jinbe and Benihimo showed me a tiny sliver of memories.
Get some rest.
We'll talk about our next job tomorrow.
The same words, the same time.
It looks a little tough, but with you guys at my side, I'm sure it'll work out.
Once it's over, we can all go see a movie.
It's been a while.
That was probably the last time
that Takuma-san saw the three of them.
Lie down a little more.
What happened to the ayakashi? The ritual of release?
It worked.
The two of them apparently said it'd be sad if they couldn't talk to me and left.
Thank you.
He's a good kid, but he always does the craziest things.
What should I do?
I couldn't say.
You've changed a little too, huh?
Have I?
I don't know about that.
Oh, Natsume-kun! You're awake?
I'm so glad.
Hey, have dinner before you go, as my way of saying thanks.
Um...
Hey, Tsukiko!
This was the end of the story of the exorcist and his former familiars.
Seems like that Ginro woman is staying here for the rest of Takuma's life.
Weird woman.
I see.
Natsume.
We're leaving.
Right.
It's time to put these away, huh?
Jinbe, Benihimo, Ginro.
The time I spent with you was a lot of fun.
You too, Natsume.
If you're ever in trouble, you can always give me a call.
We can help each other out, huh?
You can call me too, Natori-san.
Yeah.
Promise, okay?
Urihime.
Yes?
You've seen Natsume act like he's carrying something important sometimes, right?
Find out what it is.
Yes, sir.
Master?
According to Ginro, it's so dangerous that mere exorcists can't be allowed to find out what it is.
Perhaps it's something that the gentle,
reckless Natsume can't be allowed to possess.
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
Nishimura and Kitamoto
Someone you just met?
Next thing you know, he's always either not there or asleep, right?
For some reason, his eyes seemed like they were made of glass.
You sounded so happy when you said it, Natsume, so I also...
Let's walk home together, Natsume.