Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
Ever since I was little, I've seen strange things every now and then.
Other people can't see them.
They're probably what people call youkai.
Run, Sensei!
Wait, Natsume!
It's too hard to run after eating!
It's your own fault!
You ate all the dumplings that were for the guests!
If they're sitting next to you,
I'm going to think they're a snack.
Touko-san bought them for me because she said they were really good.
Your "guests" are just that Tanuma kid and that Taki girl, right?
Give them lollipops or caramel or something.
Jeez... I hope the store still has some.
What's that?
I hear what sounds like two things colliding.
The Days Eater
A pot?
Why's he hitting his head against a wall?
How should I know?
That's a youkai, right?
Let's get out of here before we get involved.
Yeah.
I cannot get this pot off.
Nor can I break it.
Can you take it off?
What do you think, Sensei?
I want to help, but he's not a sealed youkai, is he?
I don't think I sense any kind of spell from that pot, but...
I found an old pot and looked inside, and I guess I got stuck.
As you can see, I'm not anyone suspicious.
Please help me.
Anybody who says they're not suspicious is extremely suspicious!
Right, Natsu—
I'll take it off you,
but if you try anything,
Nyanko-sensei will exorcise you, okay?
What?
Are you trying to make me work for free?
I'm going to pull.
Three, two, one...
Got it!
I am the Days Eater, and I am on a journey.
The Days Eater?
I must repay you for this.
No need.
Take care.
Bye.
As thanks, I will restore your youth.
Huh?
Hey, wait! Wait right there!
Listen, don't try anything!
You'd better not!
Sheesh.
What the?!
Natsume became tiny!
A weird-looking cat's talking!
Hey, Natsume!
How do you know my name?
What are you?
A raccoon dog monster?
I'm so mad that I don't even know where to begin!
Damn it. So he got younger and lost his memories, huh?
Hey, Natsume!
Please stay away, raccoon dog monster.
I'm not a raccoon dog!
I'm Nyanko-sensei!
Calm down!
Think about it.
Do you know where you are now?
Forget about me. Do you know where you are or what today's date is?
How old are you?
No...
What happened to me?
I don't really know...
Right now, I'm...
It seems less like he went back to being a kid and his memories are confused.
Listen carefully, okay?
I am Nyanko-sensei!
I saved your life, and you are my servant!
You are presently a high school student with completely average grades,
no girlfriend at all,
freeloading at the Fujiwara household!
You can look at me like that all you want, but it's the truth.
Anyway, we're going home so we can figure out what to do.
Going home?
To this Fujiwara household?
But if what you're saying is true, raccoon dog,
will they be okay with me coming back like this?
It's true that not only can we not explain this to them,
but if Natsume's memories come back, he might rip the hair out of my tail.
You're going to pay for frightening
Touko-san and Shigeru-san, Sensei!
Maybe I'll take him to Natori, then.
A child?
What should I feed him?
Milk?
I don't think he'd be of much help.
You're so rude.
The Party of Dogs then!
You're so cute, Natsume-sama!
We, the Party of Dogs, will take care of you forever!
Forever! Forever!
Shut up!
No, if I'm not careful, he'll be reported as missing.
R-Raccoon dog, it's okay.
I'll figure things out on my own.
I can't stay with a youkai I don't really know that well.
I'm sorry.
It's Nyanko-sensei!
Huh? Sensei? What are you...
Who's that?
Great timing, you guys!
Do something!
Is it okay for you to be so loud?
By the way, where's Natsume?
Look carefully at that kid!
Huh?
Natsume's... little brother?
Close!
That's him!
What?
I'm sure it's hard to believe,
but a youkai turned him back into a kid.
A kid?
But...
Can he be turned back?
No idea.
For now, I want to go someplace else.
Tanuma, let's go to your place.
Sure.
Natsume-kun!
Wait, Natsume!
Where are you going?
You know me?
Yeah.
We're your friends.
Come to my house for now.
You might be scared because you don't know what's going on,
but we know that you can see youkai.
What?
We're close enough for you to tell us that.
Is that enough for you to trust us?
Let's go, Natsume-kun.
Thank you.
Look, over there.
You can see a temple, right?
That's my place.
Really?
Wow.
You live in a temple, Tanuma-san?
Just call me Tanuma.
Call me Taki.
Okay.
You don't have to force yourself.
Yeah, you can call me Taki-san if you want. It's totally fine.
I feel like I know this path for some reason.
Huh?
That field...
Do a lot of lotus flowers bloom there?
That's right, Natsume-kun.
We once made a wreath of flowers there.
Look, Natsume.
We went to the shrine up those steps for a festival.
And, if you follow that path between the fields,
you'll come to a river where we go
fishing with Nishimura and the gang.
A festival?
Yep.
Fishing?
Yeah.
It's like a fairy tale.
No, Natsume-kun. It's true.
It's all true.
Excuse us.
So what do you remember now, Natsume?
I don't know.
It's like my head's gone blank,
but I feel lighter all of a sudden.
It feels really weird, but I don't know why.
That raccoon—cat monster tells me that I'm really in high school,
but I can't believe that.
How did this happen, Sensei?
It's the work of the Days Eater.
The Days Eater?
Yeah.
I thought I'd heard of him somewhere.
If I recall correctly, he travels around, staying in old houses and storerooms,
and when he leaves, as thanks he takes one of the old things there and makes it new again.
He has the power to make even man or beast young again,
and supposedly certain shamans
were desperately looking for him.
Natsume just helped him and got "thanked."
So if we find this Days Eater again and ask him for help,
I might be able to go back to normal.
Yep.
Then I have to go back to where I was.
I'm leaving now.
Natsume!
Sorry, but I want to see for myself.
We'll go with—
What's the point of going along if one of you can't see it and the other one doesn't know what it looks like?!
It'll be annoying if the youkai around here find out that Natsume became a kid.
You stay here and babysit him.
I'll find him.
Why is a youkai doing this for me?
Because if you don't get back to normal, I can't go home and eat Touko's dinner!
Thank you, Nyanko-sensei!
Leave Natsume-kun to us!
I love you!
Stop it!
It's strange.
It's so hard to believe,
but the way his face tenses up from time to time makes you realize it really is Natsume-kun.
Yeah.
I'm glad, though.
If we hadn't run into them,
where would Sensei have taken Natsume-kun?
What happens if he doesn't turn back?
Sorry. Nyanko-sensei will take care of it, won't he?
There isn't much we can do in these situations.
Yeah.
Let's make curry or something.
Huh?
Natsume might stay here tonight,
and Sensei might come back hungry.
You're right.
Can I stay for dinner too?
Of course.
Natsume-kun?
Yes?
I'm going to make curry, so give me a hand.
Okay...
Hey, little guys.
Have you seen a youkai with a face like a wood knot around here?
Hey, you guys! You seen a youkai with a face like a wood knot?
Sheesh, what a pain.
Where did the Days Eater go?
Hey, did anybody see a youkai with a face like a wood knot?
Dang it.
Maybe I'll just leave Natsume as a little brat.
He attracts too many youkai to begin with.
If he'd left that pot-head alone, this never would've happened.
Please stay away, raccoon dog monster.
Oh, I know!
The Book of Friends is mine now, if I want it.
That makes me feel a little better.
Looks like I can find you, Days Eater.
Sheesh.
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
Tanuma-kun, where's the ladle?
Other side of that drawer.
Um, where's the pot?
Can you make the rice, Natsume-kun?
Huh? Um...
Oh no, this is the kind of onion that stings your eyes.
Everyone, run!
It's too late. It got me already.
Natsume, you can use a peeler.
You're scaring me, so let's use a peeler.
Nice, Natsume.
Yeah. You did well.
Are you okay, Tanuma-kun?
I'm fine.
Where's the towel?
I'll get it.
Here it is.
Huh? How did I know where it was?
I've never been here before.
Is all that stuff they said true?
The festival, and the fishing...
Are they really my friends?
Open the door.
I won't.
Get lost.
Tanuma-san and Taki-san are here.
I won't let any youkai in.
No, I won't come inside.
Open the door and I'll take you away.
They're very scary and cunning youkai.
They were talking about tricking you and eating you.
You're lying.
They won't do that.
And if that was true,
that cat monster wouldn't leave me here.
No, the cat just didn't want to get eaten himself.
So he tricked you and ran away himself.
What?
Think about it. He hasn't come back, has he?
Poor thing.
He's being deceived!
Open the door and we'll save you.
We'll take you away.
Hurry, hurry.
Those two and the cat are laughing as they trick you.
Hey, Natsume.
You're lying!
Get lost!
Natsume?
Natsume, what's wrong?
Natsume!
Natsume-kun?
Natsume-kun, what's wrong?
Taki, something's wrong.
It's dangerous, so grab him.
Got it.
Wait, Natsume-kun!
Natsume!
Natsume-kun!
G-Gotcha...
What's wrong, Natsume?
Did you see something?
Well? Feel a little better?
Yes. I'm sorry.
I see.
Sorry.
When I was young, my parents were pretty strict, so I've never played tag in someone else's house.
I know it's not a good time, but it was kind of fun.
Me too.
Until I came here, I'd never played tag indoors.
Actually...
there were monsters outside the window.
And...
th-they said that you were...
Natsume-kun, are you hungry?
I know! I almost forgot!
Here, cupcakes.
Eat all you want!
The curry still needs to stew a while, so it's perfect timing.
I brought them so we could all eat them while we hung out at your house.
Huh?
You were going to hang out at my house?
Yep.
The home of those Fujiwara people the cat was talking about?
Yeah.
What are they like?
Huh?
Are they nice?
They don't hate me?
They're very nice people.
They don't hate you.
They care about you very much.
They care about you and Nyanko-sensei.
I feel like I can remember a lot of things.
But if I try, a lot of scary and painful
memories are going to come back too.
Are you my friends?
Yep.
Both of you and that cat monster are youkai, and you're all playing a prank on me.
I know that if I don't think of things that way, I'm going to be disappointed.
But it would be nice if it were true.
If it were true, I'd like to go back to normal soon.
If I could go back,
would I remember how we played together?
We'll remember.
So come back soon, Natsume.
Hey, Days Eater.
I finally found you.
What the heck do you think you're doing?
Oh, the one from before.
What is wrong?
Everything's wrong!
Turn Natsume back.
You can do it, right?
I can, but why?
Both humans and objects have short lives, so are they not happy to become younger?
Some people want to become older,
and some people want to become younger.
Do you know which Natsume prefers?
I'm tired.
Where is Tanuma and Taki?
They're finishing the curry.
I felt tired for some reason, so I'm taking a nap.
I asked him to undo the spell.
That's probably why.
It'll be gone by the time the sun sets.
I'm tired, so I'm going to sleep.
You're paying me back double for this eventually, got it?
Yeah. Thanks.
Nyanko-sensei, are you and I friends?
Nope.
Huh?
We're kinda just stuck together.
Natsume, the curry's ready...
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
It Blooms Tomorrow
The Stone-Washer?
Once you wash 80,000 stones, you can return to Fujima village.
It was such a beautiful sight.
He draws the most beautiful flowers.