Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
You're going to bed already, Natsume?
I had a rough day yesterday.
Where were you, Nyanko-sensei?
At a drinking party, of course.
I figured it was something like that.
What happened?
I heard a weird sound from the roof in the middle of the night...
Sensei?
Are you there, Natsume Reiko? Are you there?
If you're there, come out.
If you don't, I'll crush you and this house.
He's huge!
Hey, don't touch the house!
I'll hear you out, so follow me.
Reiko!
Wait, wait!
I'm going to eat you and become famous!
I managed to lose him somehow.
Natsume-sama.
Natsume Reiko-sama.
Are you there?
That's not the voice I heard yesterday.
How many youkai did Reiko anger?
Sorry. My grandmother Reiko died.
Died?
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Did you need something from Reiko?
I'm her grandson, Natsume Takashi.
I can give back your name if you need it.
My name?
No. Reiko-sama helped me out with something.
I wanted to thank her.
Thank her?
Thank Reiko?
Not eat her?
Gomochi's Benefactor
I am Gomochi.
I came here to thank her and to give her an update.
To tell the truth, I did not have that much contact with Reiko-sama, but I owe her a great deal.
You owe her?
Yes.
I live in Nanafusa forest, which is a ways away from here.
One day, a human girl started coming to the forest.
She wouldn't do anything.
She just wandered around or took naps on grassy hills.
I heard that her name was Reiko...
Look!
The child of man is back!
Her again?
Why's she coming this deep into the mountains?
To take a nap.
Can you keep it quiet?
She looked at us!
Can she us?
We little ones who lived in the forest were in an uproar.
We're sorry!
That's self-defense.
More like an overreaction.
So yes, she was a strange child of man who didn't fear us.
Hey, did you hear?
That Reiko girl is incredibly powerful.
She can force even god-like beings to obey her.
Really?
Scary.
But if that's true, why don't we talk to her about our problem?
Don't be stupid.
What can a human do?
Hey, don't chatter like that when I'm trying to sleep.
Can you cut it out?
This is our forest!
If you've got a problem, you can leave!
Huh?
Well, that's true, but...
What?
It's coming from over there.
A big tree like that just fell over?
How awful.
It doesn't look like lightning caused this.
This must be Senki-sama and Hyakko-sama again.
Senki and Hyakko?
You don't know them?
They're the strongest pair in the forest!
I see.
But lately, they've been having a terrible fight.
They're going around breaking things, and we don't know what to do.
A fight? How stupid!
What?!
Reiko, right?
I'm told you're strong.
Can you tell them to stop their fight?
Huh?
Oh, that's a great idea.
Child of man, please!
They're too scary for us to do anything!
Please, Reiko!
Please!
This is your problem, right?
I don't want any trouble.
What could a child of man do?
However strong you are, you're still just a child of man.
What's the point in talking to someone so useless?
Hey, stop it!
She might help us!
Like she could.
Hey, cut it out—
What?
J-Just come with us, Reiko!
Wait!
Shut up, Senki!
I'm stronger and better suited!
Nonsense, Hyakko!
I am stronger!
The one with the red band is Senki-sama,
and the one with the blue band is Hyakko-sama.
I'm telling you, it's not my problem.
Hey, what's that?
Beautiful, isn't she?
Her name is Kibune.
Senki-sama and Hyakko-sama captured her.
They say whichever of them is superior will get to wed her.
What the heck?
It's a shame, but there's nothing we can do.
None of us can stand against them.
Oh, wait!
Hey, you.
Are you okay with this?
Do you want to marry one of them?
No.
I am honored by their request,
but I want to go home.
Hey, you!
Who said you could approach my bride?
Who are you?
This smell...
It's the foul scent of a human!
I do not know who you are, but run!
Hey, you two.
Let her go.
You're going to tell us what to do, girl?
Know your place, fool!
Or I'll eat you right now!
It seems you're arguing over something really stupid.
Stupid?
That's right.
You want to know which of you is worthy to marry her?
If you have to lock her up so she won't run away, then neither of you are worthy.
Idiots.
What?
Well, whatever.
Whoever's the strongest gets her, right?
Then I'll join the fight.
I'm taking the bride.
What—
If I lose, you can eat me.
It's not about wanting to protect the forest or helping her.
I just want to see your arrogant faces in tears after I beat you.
That's Reiko for you.
Maybe it'll work out.
No, it's just a bluff.
The child of man will lose.
Silence, girl!
We refuse to accept this!
What, you're scared?
I guess I win by default, then.
What?
Anyway...
Oh, it's dusk!
If I'm late, I'll get yelled at.
Jeez...
I'll come back.
We can fight then.
W-Wait, girl!
You're running away?!
See ya!
Crazy.
Yes, she was a crazy person.
We were sure she would run away, but the next day, she came back.
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
That girl is making me so mad!
Where is she? I'll make her pay!
I'm back.
You're, uh... Senki, right?
Okay, fight me.
As if you could take me!
Fine. I'll go get Hyakko.
What, you're too scared to fight me alone?
Fine. Let's get everyone together.
Senki says he can't fight me alone.
Very well, girl.
Yeah?
Then I'll decide how we fight.
Your arms are very strong.
Since mine are so frail, you don't mind, right?
That's true.
Thanks.
Okay, let's see...
Look.
You see that fruit on top of the tall tree?
How about the first to get it wins?
Hey, don't do that!
He may look slow, but Senki-sama is...
Very well. Let's do this.
Then let the match begin!
I won't lose!
Sorry, but rules are rules.
I win.
She won!
It wasn't fair, but she...
It wasn't fair, but a win's a win!
It's true that she didn't say we had to climb the tree.
Here.
As an apology, I'll give you this fruit.
My plan worked because you fight fair.
But please keep your promise and leave Kibune alone, okay?
A strange girl.
Senki-sama had a short-temper,
but he was so shocked that it calmed him down.
Hyakko!
Come on out!
Fight me!
Reiko!
I heard you beat Senki!
Yeah, I guess.
It's your turn.
I'll decide how we—
About that, it would be childish of me to just crush you,
so I have a good idea.
Huh?
Now that Senki lost, if I win,
I'm the strongest in the forest.
I'm gathering food for my wedding feast with Kibune.
In this forest, chestnuts with three nuts in the bur are considered lucky.
Whoever gathers the most wins.
Bring them to base of that tree by dawn.
Wait a second!
What a great idea I had!
It's fine, right?
Then let us begin!
Wait—
Wh-What will you do, Reiko?
Do you have a plan?
Nope. I let my guard down.
I guess I'll have to go look for them.
Hey, it doesn't look like she can win the next match.
What do we do?
If Hyakko-sama wins,
he's going to start bossing everybody in the forest!
Oh no!
We never should've counted on a human!
Hey! She's doing this for us!
Shut up, you wimpy youkai!
Don't you understand that this is your chance?
This might be your only chance to use somebody as powerful as Natsume Reiko to defeat Hyakko!
If I don't beat him now, you're going to have trouble, right?
Now, help me win!
Gather burs and bring them to me.
Take them to that tree by dawn.
There are so many of you!
You can't lose!
Okay, let's get started!
Hurry!
Where are the chestnuts?
You there.
Go to that tree and hold the chestnuts for me.
Huh?
Betray me and I'll rip the hair off your tail.
Got it?
Okay!
What will you do?
I'm going to gather chestnuts.
What else would I do?
I hate losing.
Hey, you.
Will you take me somewhere with lots of chestnut trees?
Ow...
[ Note: Persimmon is a type of fruit. They look similar to tomatoes, but are orange colored ]
I should've had him pick persimmons instead.
No good. This one's got four nuts too.
This one is...
Ow!
Are you okay?
You should take a break.
I'm fine.
This is a pain, though.
Yeah. Hyakko-sama knows the forest so well.
He'll gather a mountain of chestnuts in no time.
I'm out.
It was stupid to think about helping a child of man.
Hey!
Leave them.
Anybody who doesn't want to help doesn't have to.
That's how this works, right?
It's natural for connections you make to break quickly.
I'm doing this because I want to try it.
Regardless of whether it succeeds or fails.
I don't like losing,
but I just want to see what I decided to do through to the end.
And I probably got Kibune's hopes up.
I went to Kibune and told her what Reiko-sama was doing.
Hey, it's nighttime!
Isn't it bad for children of men if they don't go home?
You said you'd be scolded, right?
Huh? Oh.
The people I'm living with will be home late tonight. So if I go home right after sunrise, it'll work out.
But I pity them.
They have to deal with extra baggage like me.
I wonder if I'll be able to go home tomorrow.
It was then that I realized it.
She was more afraid of losing than she was of not being able to go home.
It's almost dawn.
Let's go to the tree.
Right.
Oh, you got a bunch, huh?
I don't know if it's enough, though...
Fewer people brought them than I thought.
It's fine.
I'll wait for Hyakko.
You guys can go home.
I...
Look. I found one on the way too!
Oh, thanks.
I-It's not for your sake!
Bye!
But can you win?
It seems like it will be really close.
Hey!
Hyakko-sama...
What a shame.
I lose, huh?
And so the battle ended,
and Hyakko-sama and Senki-sama realized how the forest dwellers felt and changed their ways.
As promised, Kibune was taken by Reiko-sama, but...
Reiko-sama...
Kibune, you're free now.
If there's somewhere you want to go back to, then go.
It's so wonderful having a place
you want to go home to, isn't it?
I have to go.
The people at home will be waking up soon.
R-Reiko, you'll be coming to this forest again, right?
Huh?
It was fun, but I can't feel relaxed in a forest where I know the inhabitants.
This is goodbye!
And she never came back.
The forest dwellers sometimes started to think
that maybe she'd come back, but she never did.
Maybe Reiko could've forged a connection.
She probably didn't realize, though.
She'd kept her distance from too many things.
Or maybe she didn't want to notice.
She really was a no-good woman.
Shut up, Sensei.
We still owe her so much.
I don't get many chances to hear about my grandmother.
Thanks for telling me, Gomochi.
Oh, what was your update?
Oh, this is a personal matter...
After that, as Kibune and I waited and searched for Reiko-sama,
we came to love one another.
We're having a wedding soon, and I wanted to invite her.
Oh, a wedding—
Huh?!
Sensei was enticed by the offer of sake, so he and I went.
It seemed like everyone was having fun and reliving old memories.
Kibune, the youkai Reiko had saved on a whim, was beautiful.
I was a little upset that she didn't get a chance to see this wonderful sight.
And I was a little proud too.
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
A Day That Will
Someday Come
I've seen many youkai entranced by humans.
This is probably my last bet.
You have a place where you should live.
I want to be with Aoi-chan forever!
I'm sure it'll go well.