Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
Then you must have the Book of Friends.
You can steal countless names and bind them to your will,
or even crush their lives with it.
The terrifying and enticing Book of Friends...
You...
It is not a thing for a mere child of man to possess.
Give it to me.
And you're just a youkai.
Get your hands off him.
Natori-san.
When did he get here?
No, he...
He heard me!
What Matters
He heard about the Book of Friends.
So...
I can't talk about it with so many youkai here right now, but once this is over...
will you hear me out?
Of course.
The grounds were filled with exorcists and their families.
Well, find anything?
No, not a thing.
They say the owner of this mansion, Hakozaki-san, stayed alone in his study researching youkai.
The one who finds it will be given what's inside!
I'm not letting anyone else get it!
His family grew distant from him, and after his death,
they didn't know where the study was.
Find it no matter what!
This is the best chance one could hope for to make it big as an exorcist!
The Matoba Clan is here?
And it's Nanase-san.
We need to find the study before things get complicated.
That's right.
But don't underestimate this place, guys.
You're up against a weirdo spell researcher.
What if the room is filled with youkai he captured and did mad scientist experiments on?!
It's a cursed place, filled with evil...
Stop.
Well, I think there's fifty-fifty odds.
Huh?!
It's filled with research notes, right?
Huh?
Yeah, but it's not like anybody knows for sure.
Natori-san!
Now, now, calm down Natsume.
Oh, I wondered who that voice was.
Natori, you're joining in the fun too?
Oh, hello there.
Is that a new familiar?
I thought I heard the name "Natsume."
Th-That's right.
I'm figuring out if he's useful. His name is N... Nutmeg!
Huh?
Nutmeg, huh? A classy name.
Well...
So, did you find anything?
No, not a thing.
It's hidden with some kind of spell or something.
Yes, most likely.
I looked for anything that might provide a clue,
but while the place is big and filled with stuff,
there's barely anything he used as part of his daily life or stuff that he cared about.
It seems he lived a lonely life.
I'm done here.
Good luck, Natori.
Thanks.
What's wrong, Nutmeg?
Is something wrong, Nutmeg?
Is something bothering you, Nutmeg?
Isn't that name a little bit random?!
Sorry.
So?
I thought there might be a photo or diary somewhere.
I tried to look for it in rooms he used often,
but there are so many that I didn't even know where to start.
Yeah.
But when I heard that man say that he didn't see anything that Hakozaki-san cared about, I remembered something.
Beniko-san said that her grandfather planted a maple tree for her.
I don't know about him, but if it were me,
I'd want to be in a room where I could see that maple tree.
And so, as we didn't have any better ideas,
we decided to search rooms where the maple tree was visible from.
That's the tree, huh?
Yeah.
I'll check the rooms this way one by one.
Okay. We'll check the ones over here.
Any luck, Hiiragi?
I can see the maple tree, but there's nothing to indicate he actually used the room.
I see.
Maybe I was wrong.
This room's a mess too.
You can see the maple tree from here, but the last person in here searched this hard and found nothing, huh?
A small box with a maple design.
Natsume?
I'm going to open this, okay?
A photo?
Is that...
Yes, I think it's a photo of his family.
Natori-san, is there anyone in this photo you know?
Unfortunately not.
But the guy with that awkward smile might be the owner of this mansion.
Yeah, you might be right.
I thought it was the design of the wallpaper, but there are two dragons there, right?
Huh?
Wow, they just look like blurs to me.
These might be his familiars.
It looks like they're protecting him.
One is light blue, and the other looks yellow.
Dragons, huh?
That at least gives us a place to start looking.
Some youkai hide themselves in photos and other small objects.
Let's look for things in the shape of dragon.
Perhaps they're the familiars.
Yeah.
Natsume, I said it was fifty-fifty back there...
Huh?
But Hakozaki-san was a sort of last resort for some.
I think he was a nice person.
Yeah.
Part of me hoped that was so,
while part of me wondered if someone like that was all alone in this huge mansion, staring at that maple tree.
Find anything, Hiiragi?
No, nothing.
I see.
Hiiragi, Natsume said he'd tell me when this was over,
but is it okay for me to hear it?
I believe it's far better than trying to find out in secret.
Yeah, you're probably right.
I wish I were stronger...
Hey, Sensei, are you looking?
Shaddup! All that talk of Nutmeg you were doing made me want Salisbury steak!
Finish it up!
It wasn't my idea!
Hey, Nanase's on the north side!
Maybe she found something!
Nanase-san?
Should we go too?
You felt it too, Sensei?
Like some kind of presence changed.
A door?
Natsume?
A dragon relief.
You found me, huh?
Coward!
You have something with my master's smell, don't you?
It drew me to you.
Huh?
Yeah.
This photo, maybe?
I'm sorry for taking it out of its room.
Since I found it, I was going to give it to his granddaughter.
Master...
Are you Hakozaki's familiar?
Indeed.
I'm looking for a study where Hakozaki-san was said to keep his research notes.
Can you tell me where it is?
After ignoring him for so long,
you would come and reap the benefits of his work?
I won't let you have it!
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
We won't do anything bad with it.
Tell us where it is.
Why would I tell you?
You said, "After ignoring him for so long."
Does that mean Hakozaki-san was lonely here?
Don't be stupid.
Night and day, he would gather us youkai and celebrate.
He would summon the most powerful youkai,
cheat them in games,
and force them to give him incredible amounts of sake.
He would use new techniques to summon funny and entertaining youkai and dance with them.
Sometimes he would fill the mansion with cherry blossoms
and make us familiars clean them up while he laughed heartily.
It was fun.
It was fun... for us.
But no matter the noise we made,
and no matter the fun we youkai thought we had,
whenever there was a noise at the front door,
he would fly to it immediately.
He would crouch low and stare from the window toward the gate,
and when no one was there, he would sigh and stand up.
He would stare at the leaves as they changed color,
say, "She's not coming this year, either?" laugh, and then close his eyes.
After all that...
I won't let you pass.
Is this the door to the study, then?
This home will be sold before long.
I want to give what was important to Hakozaki-san to someone who will care for it.
Will you let me into the study?
I'm sorry.
I was just taking my anger out on you.
It's been a while since I've talked to a human.
But there are both good and bad things inside.
It is the master's wish that it remain sealed.
I see.
Matoba and the other exorcists won't give up!
If you fear they'll be misused, then give them to us!
Natori-san!
We just wish to sleep here,
with the memories of our master.
If anyone were to try to steal it, we wouldn't have any regrets.
We will take it all with us.
But as a reward for being the first to find me,
the front entrance,
if anything happens to remain,
you may use it however you like.
You heard him.
Let's go.
B-But...
If nothing else, I think he knows his master's wishes better than anyone.
Let's leave him in charge.
It wasn't my imagination that I was reminded of old times.
Child, I have seen your face before.
That was probably my grandmother.
You knew Reiko-san?
No, it was a man.
I think I once met a man a long time ago who looked much like you.
Huh?
A man?
A long time ago?
What's that sound?
It's that way.
They're doing something on the north side.
That's where Nanase is!
I am the front entrance.
It seems they found Kanegumo, who protects the rear entrance.
They are trying to open it by force.
If they try to steal it, we shall take it with us first!
Farewell!
Natsume!
The north wing is burning!
What?!
I've failed.
A fire!
We need to put it out!
No, it will disappear soon.
The color of the fire is wrong.
This is the fire of a youkai.
The building isn't burning.
What's burning is...
Cursed youkai!
They took it all with them!
Farewell, dragons of Hakozaki-san.
Guess we're done here.
Aimiya-san.
Guess so.
Oh, did you see Nanase-san?
Yeah, she went home looking really pissed.
What a shame.
I'm going too.
What will you do?
Since I've come this far, I'll watch it burn out before I go.
I see.
Bye.
Natsume?
I picked these up.
They look pretty useful.
Wind Water Circle
It's okay for us to take them, right?
Hiiragi, Urihime, Sasago!
Pick those up!
Right!
We got quite a few, huh?
Several of these look useful.
It's all thanks to you, Natsume.
It's because we were able to do it together.
My grandmother's name was Natsume Reiko.
They say she was really powerful.
But she wasn't easy to get along with,
and she picked fights with youkai all the time.
Eventually, she began to challenge them,
and she would write down the names of the youkai she defeated onto pieces of paper.
I somehow kept myself calm as I told Natori-san
about my grandmother and the Book of Friends.
And that, whether deliberately or by chance,
it was forbidden magic.
And that I was the only one who could return the names.
I see.
The Book of Friends.
An interesting name, huh?
You were carrying a terrible burden by yourself, weren't you?
No, that's not actually true.
Something that dangerous...
should just be burned.
Huh?
Did you say something?
No.
Sensei, don't play with the papers!
It's about to burn out.
Good.
And so our search of the Hakozaki residence ended.
The strange flames that surrounded the mansion burned out without damaging it all,
likely burning only the study that no one ever got to see.
I'm glad.
About what?
I thought we'd get into more of an
argument over the Book of Friends.
I don't know.
Just make sure his shady-looking smile doesn't trick you.
What do you mean?
But there's one more thing that I'm curious about.
I thought that every time I heard about someone "similar to me," it was Reiko-san.
I think I once met a man a long time ago who looked much like you.
My father?
No, probably...
my grandfather?
That dragon was the familiar of an exorcist.
How did he know my grandfather?
Natsume!
I'm starving! Let's race home!
What? Run yourself, Sensei.
I'm exhausted, thanks to you!
You didn't do a thing, Sensei!
Enough!
Let's go, Natsume! Race you to the fried shrimp!
You don't know if we're having that for dinner!
Wait, Sensei!
I'm back!
I found myself exchanging smiles with others.
Welcome back.
Did Natori-san like the jam?
Oh, yeah.
Reiko-san...
Sensei, you need to wipe off your feet first!
In the memories in the Book of Friends, you were always alone, standing tall.
Oh, Nyangoro, you must be hungry.
Hey, Sensei!
Did you ever get to exchange smiles with someone?
With the people you cared about?
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana