Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
Curse you, exorcist!
Where did you go?!
Y-You! Tell me where your master is!
I'll eat him and you!
Right here.
And we're done.
Splendidly done, Master.
Hey, it's an exorcist!
How terrifying!
Let's get out of here!
Don't worry.
If I went around exorcising little ones like you,
I'd die of exhaustion!
He found us!
Forgive us! We'll do anything!
Sheesh.
I said I...
No, wait.
Have you ever heard of the "Book of Friends"?
The Book...
...of Friends?
N-No!
We've never heard of it!
W-Wait!
Bye!
The Sealed Room
Good grief.
Why do we have go to that Natori brat's place again?
We don't have a choice.
Touko-san made a lot of jam,
and she wanted me to give some to him.
You know what your problem is?
Oh, right. I was watching a TV show this afternoon, and your friend...
Natori-san, was it? He was in it.
Is he doing well?
I think so.
What, is this Natori-san famous?
Yes, I think so.
I just went to Natori-san's condo, actually.
It was pretty big, but there wasn't much furniture.
He also had a large fridge, but there was nothing inside.
I guess that's how it is for men who live alone.
Oh my...
That's what it's like when you're young, right?
After what you said, she probably got worried, right?
I don't know if Natori-san likes sweet things.
You called him and told him you're bringing jam, right?
Yeah.
He sounded happy, but the way he laughs...
It always sounds kinda shady, right?
Who knows if he really means it?
Natori-san is a friend, but he's an exorcist.
I still can't tell him about the Book of Friends.
I just hope he likes the jam.
Um, I think it's this way.
Natsume.
Hey, thanks for coming.
I came to get you.
Hey, isn't that...
No way! It must just be a look-alike.
Natori-san, you didn't need to come find me!
Are you sure?
I don't have any male friends, so I don't know these things.
That's really embarrassing for me, so please don't say it!
Let's just go!
You're in such a hurry, Natsume.
Somebody's standing in front of your condo.
Aimiya-san.
Natori?
I'm glad I caught you.
I need you to come with me.
Who are you?
A friend.
What is it that's brought you all the way out here?
Is that the oddly strong boy who they say you're sometimes seen with?
Huh?
Who is "they"?
He's just a friend—
Okay, with his help, maybe we can win.
Would you come too?
Wait, Aimiya-san!
Natori, it's the Hakozaki residence.
What?
We may be able to get our hands on the belongings of the Hakozaki residence.
Belongings?
You mean that Hakozaki-san?
Yeah.
You're interested too, aren't you?
Other exorcists are coming.
If they're going to take it...
Um, what are you talking about?
Oh, Hakozaki-san was a researcher who studied youkai and exorcist spells.
He died the other day,
but it's said he left many papers behind.
Every exorcist in Japan wants their hands on his papers.
That's how much his belongings are worth.
He studied spells?
Maybe I could learn something about the Book of Friends.
If you can see youkai too,
those papers will surely be of use to you.
Do you want in on this?
Aimiya-san, I'm telling you, he's just...
Natori-san, I'd like to check it out.
Huh?
If my joining can help, please let me go with you.
Natsume...
If I learned more about youkai and exorcist spells,
I think I could be more active
instead of simply being afraid.
I see.
Then it's settled.
Let's get going!
I'm seeing less and less houses.
Yeah, we're almost to the mansion.
That's right.
It's not just the Book of Friends.
I might learn something about Reiko.
Wow.
What a big house, huh?
I've heard the inside is like a maze.
Hakozaki-san lived here alone.
Alone?
He may've been a talented exorcist and researcher,
but he was very strange.
It seems he had few friends.
But there are a lot of people here.
Sure, but they're all in the same business we are.
Oh, Hakozaki-san.
It sounds like you're having a rough time.
Aimiya-san.
Thank you.
I know I'm asking for a lot from you.
Natori-san, thank you for coming too.
That's Beniko-san, Hakozaki-san's granddaughter.
I see.
So, what's the situation?
We don't know yet.
As you know, my grandfather had a huge amount of research documents on youkai and magic.
When he was alive, he said they were all inside his study.
His study?
You couldn't find them?
No, not exactly.
We searched the mansion, but we didn't find any room
that looked like a study.
Huh?
You couldn't find it?
I know it's big, but...
Knowing Hakozaki, he probably used magic to hide it or something.
Yes.
But those of us left lack the power to see it,
and we want to rid our lives of youkai.
We want to be rid of this mansion as soon as possible.
However, we don't want to sell it with the study still inside.
So we'll give the contents to whoever finds it.
Please find the study.
That's why we've brought all you famous exorcists here.
That's amazing.
Right?
You don't get a chance like this often.
Natsume, to be honest, I don't want you getting too involved with exorcists,
but this is a rare opportunity.
Will you help me?
Yes.
There's something I want to find out too.
Yeah. Like about the Book of Friends, for instance.
And...
a way to get rid of the lizard mark on Natori-san's body.
Feel free to search anywhere in or on the grounds.
The main building, the annex, the storehouses, the sheds.
Use and move what you find inside as you see fit.
Good luck, all of you.
Strange woman, huh?
She could've just come to us.
Instead, there's this big crowd.
She wants to finish this up as soon as possible.
She doesn't care who gets the documents.
I know it's out of her control,
but this is her grandfather's house and the things he left behind.
It's kind of sad.
Is something wrong, Natsume?
No, I was just getting a little sentimental.
That's just like you.
But if she doesn't need them, then let's take them.
It's better if the papers are in the hands of someone who'll take care of them than someone who'll use them for evil.
We just need to find them first.
Right.
Urihime, Sasago, you search the sheds.
I'll take my familiar and search the eastern annex.
I'll take my calico cat thing and search the western annex.
Oh, Natsume, wait a second.
You heard, right?
Matoba's people are here, so wear this.
And I'll send Hiiragi with you.
Go ask the youkai in the mansion about the study.
I'll go see what the exorcists have to say.
I'm counting on you, Hiiragi.
Right.
See you later.
It's huge!
Well? Find anything?
No.
Find it!
With Hakozaki's papers, I can become famous overnight!
Wow.
We can ask them, but I don't think
his rivals are going to tell us anything.
I don't know about that.
Many of these youkai don't look very smart,
and some of them were forced to become familiars.
Study...
Also, many youkai here seem to have nothing to do with this.
This place just feels pleasant, though.
Huh?
It's a bit like...
when you're busy studying,
and I'm sunbathing on the roof.
Or when you're busy with that "homework" stuff, and I'm relaxing on a warm and fluffy pillow.
That's infuriating, but it does sound pleasant.
Is it the same for you, Hiiragi?
Yes.
I can't come up with a good comparison, but...
It's fine. You don't need to compare it to anything.
It's true that there are far fewer barriers than the usual exorcist home.
Perhaps he allowed youkai in here,
like the way one might build a birdhouse to watch birds.
I see...
Your smell... This presence...
I think we met a long time ago.
If it was a long time ago,
it was probably my grandmother Reiko.
She's passed away.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
That looks rough.
Is it because of something you possess?
It's not just because you can see the youkai that they take such an interest in you.
Is it something you can't tell Natori about?
Hiiragi...
I want to tell you, but I guess it's something that exorcists shouldn't be allowed to know about.
If he finds out, I might get him caught up in some trouble.
And he's so kind.
He looks like he worries a lot about other people.
I think that if I tell him, he'll be worried about me.
That's true.
But not telling him may cause him to worry, as well.
What's that?
Let's go!
It's that way!
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
Jeez.
If somebody with the level of skill Hakozaki-san is
supposed to have is hiding a room with magic,
who knows if we can even find it?
But perhaps Natsume...
Oh, if it isn't Natori?
I see your sense for finding a
good deal is as strong as ever.
Nanase-san.
It's been a long time.
Why don't we don't team up and split it sixty-forty?
No, thank you.
No matter what you say, the Matoba clan is planning on taking it all in the end, right?
But if you can't find it, you get nothing.
So? Find anything?
No, not a thing.
Just look at the size of this place.
It may take days.
We asked Hakozaki-shi to join our clan several times,
but he was a stubborn old man.
He rarely dealt with anyone.
In fact, it was rare for anyone to even meet him.
I'm sure he won't let us find it that easily.
That probably means his power was the real deal.
Not that we care.
Huh?
Even if we can't find the study now, if Matoba simply buys the whole house, we can take our time looking later.
So inelegant. Just like always.
Call it "efficient."
It would be worse to sell it to a normal person, right?
You're not here to stop the other exorcists from finding the study, are you?
You're overthinking things.
We're just taking a look around.
Oh, come to think of it...
How's the young Natsume boy?
I couldn't say.
I haven't seen him recently.
I see.
He could enjoy himself a lot more if he came with us, though.
Bye.
I didn't think Nanase-san would be here.
I need to tell Natsume so that he doesn't run into her.
Wow.
It's like a thief ransacked the place.
Even if you're looking for something, this is overdoing it.
It doesn't matter.
Huh?
We're planning on getting rid of the furniture eventually.
Are you sure about this?
It has to be done.
There may be a creepy room in here, but we can't find it.
When I think about what would happen if we let it go,
and if something inside were to want revenge on us...
We need you to find it and take what's inside,
or we won't feel safe.
I know it's cold, but I don't even feel like pretending that I feel otherwise.
Look at that maple tree.
When I was young, I told my grandfather I liked maples,
so he planted it immediately.
I was so happy.
But whenever I met him,
all he did was happily talk about youkai.
Even though I couldn't see them.
And he was the only one having fun.
So I started wanting to avoid him.
The rest of our relatives began to avoid him in the same way.
And then he started to stay inside this house, devoting himself to strange research.
I hate this mansion.
Huh?
I'm sure I'll be glad when it's gone.
Are you okay, Natsume?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
It's just been a while since I came across someone
who hates the fact that some people can see youkai.
Being able to see them sometimes
means that others won't accept you.
That's all it is.
Even when someone says something like that, it doesn't make me as scared as it once did.
I was able to come to a place where I can feel that way.
There are things that I can do.
Hiiragi, I thought of something when I was talking to her.
If he was an exorcist, he must've had familiars, right?
If they're still in this mansion,
maybe we can find the study by talking to them.
Have you ever heard what kind of familiars he had?
No.
I would imagine most exorcists don't know,
but that may be a good idea.
Okay, we'll split up.
We can either ask the youkai who didn't come with the exorcists,
or we can look for notes or diaries about the familiars.
What is this?
I've never seen them.
I see.
Do you know?
No!
He was strange and always alone,
so there's no information about him.
He's just like Reiko.
No, the only thing Reiko left was the Book of Friends.
But there are still things left here that were important to Hakozaki.
I should be able to find something.
There must be a place...
where Reiko lived.
Somewhere she left many of her memories.
My relatives don't want to tell me,
but someday I'll be able to go there.
I heard you talking.
You're Reiko's grandson?
He knows Reiko?
Then you must have the Book of Friends.
You can steal countless names and bind them to your will,
or even crush their lives with it.
The terrifying and enticing Book of Friends...
You...
It is not a thing for a mere child of man to possess.
Give it to me.
And you're just a youkai.
Get your hands off him.
If you refuse to do so, then be ready.
Natori-san.
An exorcist?
When did he get here?
No, he...
Now, let's not hold back.
He heard me!
I can handle this wimp.
Get lost, kiddo!
Nyanko-sensei!
Begone!
He heard about the Book of Friends.
Something I didn't tell anyone about.
Are you okay, Natsume?
Um...
It's okay.
Everything is fine.
I'll pretend I didn't hear anything.
It's okay.
No.
Will you hear me out?
I can't talk about it with so many youkai here right now, but once this is over...
will you hear me out?
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
What Matters
It looks as if it's protecting this man.
Let's search for something in the shape of a dragon.
I think it's a photo of his family.
Is it okay for me to hear this?
My grandmother's name was Natsume Reiko.
I want salisbury steak now!