Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Things I want are beyond my reach
jibun ni wa nai mono bakari
Wishes I pray for won't ever come true
kanai mo shinai mono bakari
I hate myself for having these depressing and envious thoughts
urayande kusumu kokoro ni mata iya ni naru keredo
But everyone else is the same way
demo sore wa minna onaji
And I believe that there's a bud
sakanai tsubomi mo areba
That won't turn into a beautiful flower unless I make it bloom
boku dake ni shika sakanai hana ga aru tte shinjiteru
I'll accept all the regrets and worries that I've had until now
kyou made no koukai mo tomadoi mo zenbu uketomete
And water the bud in my heart
mizu wo ageyou
I'm sure there's a meaning to all the tears I've shed
itsuka nagashita namida ni datte imi ga aru kara
I've always been searching for what bloomed from them
furooria zutto sagashiteta
And realized it's been beside me all along
mono nara sugu soba ni attanda
If only I can love myself the way I am
boku ga boku wo aisetara
It'll become my own beautiful flower
itsuka boku dake no hana ni naru
I won't hesitate anymore and make it bloom
mou mayowanaide sakihokore
On the way home from school,
I went to a town a little ways away to buy a study book.
Good.
I made it in time.
Um, did you drop this?
Whew!
If you hadn't found this, I would've just left it there.
Glad to help.
You in high school?
Yes.
What grade?
Sophomore.
So you're a year younger...
Can you take me to your school?
What?
I want to see the person who this letter belongs to,
but I don't know what school they're at.
If you take me there, I'll find them myself.
Can you help me out?
A Day That Will Someday Come
What is it?
I was just thinking you're a really nice guy.
What's your relationship to the letter's owner?
Childhood friend.
Is that true?
It is.
I don't lie.
I'm Aoi.
Who are you?
Natsume.
You're honest.
Is that a problem?
No, just...
I was thinking about how my
childhood friend was really stubborn.
Aoi-san had kind of a strange air about him.
Okay, see you tomorrow!
Yeah, bye!
Listen, if you cause trouble with any of the students, I'll knock you flat.
With those matchstick arms of yours?
No way.
I'm pretty strong.
So am I.
Don't worry.
I'm just looking for my friend. That's all.
Of course,
even if I do find my friend, at this point...
Huh?
Am I stupid? What am I doing?
Is your childhood friend a girl?
Yeah.
Is that a problem?
No.
Natsume.
Hey, Nishimura.
You just leaving?
Yeah.
Almost time for practice exams.
Anyway, why are grinning out here all by yourself?
Huh?
Nishimura can't see him?
So he's a youkai, huh?
You finally noticed?
You're a little dense.
Shut up!
What's wrong, Natsume?!
No, um, uh...
When someone mistakes you for a human, tell them.
It makes them a bit sad to realize it after the fact.
I see.
I'm sorry.
What's your friend's name?
Sonokawa Kaoru.
I think she should be a junior.
I don't know any juniors.
I don't think she went to your school.
Huh?
If someone at your level went to the same school, she would've made contact with you.
Kaoru can see youkai too.
But she can only sometimes see youkai who match her wavelength.
Maybe she matches mine very well, because she could see me easily.
But something happened, and we broke things off.
What happened?
Well...
Natsume.
Thanks for talking to me.
Yeah.
We broke things off.
That letter freaked me out so much that I almost went to see her.
I guess I'm leaving.
Wait. What did the letter say?
This?
This isn't a letter.
Huh?
Inside it is...
Hey, Natsume!
They say that the new Nanatsujiya pastry has white bean jam filling!
Whoa! A giant raccoon dog!
Nyanko-sensei!
Sensei?
Hm? Who's that crow-looking boy?
You know him?
Huh?
Yeah.
My brothers said white raccoon dogs are near the level of divine beings.
Aoi-san, calm down!
And look more carefully at this creature!
I am training to be a forest protector at Kagome Peak.
I've heard that Kagome Peak has a spring of delicious sake.
The task of protecting the spring lies with my master, Doutaka-sama, and his students.
I like you!
Come have some tea at our place!
Right.
One of Doutaka's kids.
He's not with his flock, so this is a great chance!
I'll get even with you for all the misery you've caused!
Get back, Natsume.
Wimp.
Busy day.
Well, forest protectors probably get a lot of people hating them.
So that was the white raccoon dog's true form?!
Call me Nyanko-sensei.
Thank you very much for driving it off!
Please, let me thank you somehow.
Aoi-san, don't trust him!
I'm a bird-like youkai that used to live in the forest around Mount Kakeiwa.
That's the mountain on the other side of the next town over, right?
Yes.
I grew up in a flock, but I hurt my wings.
I left the flock and was alone.
And that was when I met Kaoru.
You're always up in the trees. Are you from around here?
She didn't seem to realize that I was a youkai at first.
I see.
You're a youkai, huh?
I'm glad.
I'm so glad I have the power to see youkai.
After that she kept coming to the forest and telling me about the world of man.
Several years later, I went to town, just once.
I wanted to see the town where she lived.
And I realized...
Even in middle school,
she was still coming to the forest all the time.
She was prioritizing me over her friends and relationships.
To everyone around her, she was a strange girl.
And then I realized it.
We should separate.
But I kept putting it off, and by the time she was in her second year of middle school,
she started to fall in love with me.
And so you ran?
Yes, as embarrassed as I am to say it.
We couldn't live together.
At some point, our times would start to diverge.
As long as she was in love with a youkai,
she probably couldn't fall in love with a human.
And that would be a waste.
That was enough to convince me.
I ended my relationship with her
and became a student of Doutaka.
I'm pretty powerful,
and my older brothers have a high opinion of me.
I see.
Yeah.
I was so busy with my training that I
forgot about Kaoru until just recently.
He said that,
but it looked to me like he was saying he'd put so much effort into his training in order to forget about Kaoru.
What's that envelope?
Let me see what's inside!
Congratulations
Congratulations?!
An invitation to a wedding?
And it's in three days?
Kaoru's getting married?
But I'm pretty sure high schoolers don't usually get married.
What?
I'm too smart to have messed up the math...
I'm too smart...
Sensei, is it possible that Kaoru is a lot older than we think?
Yeah, who knows when this letter was even sent?
It was in the mailbox at an abandoned house.
Mailbox?
I used it to communicate with Kaoru.
I hadn't gone to see it since I cut things off with her.
But there was a lull in my training, so I went to take a look.
I didn't want to read them,
but the envelope on top caught my eye.
So I opened it.
You can read human language?
Yeah.
She...
Can I read it?
Aoi-chan, are you doing well?
I'm okay now.
I was lucky enough to meet someone who really cares about me.
So I won't wait for you anymore.
This is my last letter.
If you can really forget about me,
then at least come to say congratulations.
You can laugh if you want.
I didn't come for Kaoru's sake.
I came for myself.
I want to say congratulations,
and then really forget about her.
Sorry, Natsume.
You were a big help.
Let's look for her, Aoi-san.
No, I...
Not for your sake.
I want to meet her.
Yeah.
This is the end.
Natsume Yuujinchou 6
Sonokawa Kaoru?
There's someone by that name at my cram school.
She's a year older than me and goes to a different school,
so I've never really talked to her.
Nishimura, is she getting married soon?
What? Married?
Nishimura was heading to his cram school later that day,
so I decided to tag along and meet Kaoru-san.
That's her.
Thanks, Nishimura. That's a big help.
Sure.
So that's her, huh?
Yeah.
S-Sensei?!
What are you doing here?
I saw you going.
Please don't say anything, okay?
Um, are you Sonokawa-san?
Excuse me?
She looks like a normal teenage girl.
I'm Natsume.
Do you know a guy named Aoi...
Where did you meet Aoi-chan?!
Are you a youkai?!
Is he somewhere nearby?!
Tell me!
He's not here.
I had to make sure you were the right person.
R-Really?
He really...
Did you put a wedding invitation into
the mailbox of an abandoned building?
That means he read it, right?
Yes.
Good. He fell for it!
Huh?
That invitation was a trap.
So I could see him again.
No.
A trap to catch him.
I was really little when I first met Aoi-chan.
Hey, hey!
Want to play?
I'll give you some candy.
Candy?
Yeah, it's sweet!
No thanks.
There are snakes and dogs down there,
so everybody said not to go down unless I need to.
Everybody?
Who's everybody?
You're always alone!
After that, no matter how often I talked to him,
he wouldn't respond.
I must've said something to upset him.
Today I'll apologize, and then we can be friends!
What? Wings?
They're so pretty...
No!
What are you doing?!
What? You again?
It's dangerous! Come down here!
You can't fly with those toy wings!
Did you insult my wings, you stupid girl?!
Fine!
Let's have a duel!
I was just worried about you.
Come get me, then!
Take these off already!
Oh no.
What have I done?
I'm so sorry.
Does it hurt?
I'm sorry!
I just wanted to be friends!
You're so kind.
You could've just left me alone.
I already hurt them.
It's not your fault.
And everybody says that all wounds heal eventually.
After that, he started to play with me more and more.
And he stopped talking about "everyone."
Hey, where've you been this last week?
I wanted to see the fireworks with you.
I could see them a little from the mountain.
You're really irritating sometimes, you know?
I even put a note in the mailbox! Jeez.
Kaoru.
It doesn't have to be me that you do that stuff with.
Huh?
You have your own life to live.
Wh-What are you saying?
You know what I'm saying, Kaoru.
This stuff isn't...
Do you not like me, Aoi-chan?
I know I can't control your feelings...
How do you not get it?
I want to be with you forever.
Because...
Because I've always... I've always...
And then he disappeared without a word.
Isn't that awful?
Natsume-kun, I want to see him again.
Please don't tell him the invitation was a trap.
I think this is my last chance.
I'm going to catch him and either
beat him up or try to persuade him.
If I see him again, and if he still cares about me...
I won't let him go ever again!
Kaoru-san is amazing.
Scary girl.
I've seen lots of youkai drawn to humans, but they all disappeared.
Sensei, will Kaoru-san's plan work?
Who knows?
Huh? One of Doutaka's students?
Yeah.
My brothers got worried in the afternoon and came to check on me.
They told me to come back once I was done.
They said they'll be waiting.
I see.
Natsume,
can you come with me for a bit?
I'll never come back here.
Since I can't answer them, I can't read these.
But I can't just leave them, either.
Aoi-chan, where are you?
Are you mad?
Coward. Are you
running away?
You dummy.
Contact me already.
I'll never forgive you.
Come back soon.
Do you hate me now?
Why won't you meet with me?
What are you doing?
Why did you stop coming?
I wanna see you.
I wanted to see the
fireworks together.
Aoi-chan...
Aoi-chan,
where are you?
Are you mad?
Coward. Are you running away?
You dummy. Contact me already.
I'll never forgive you. Come back soon.
Aoi-chan.
Aoi-chan...
I want to live my life with you.
I'm sure...
I'm sure it'll work out just fine, Kaoru-san.
It's at the building on the right at the end of the street.
Hurry up.
Are you hiding something?
I was just thinking you should be honest with yourself.
What the hell are you talking about?
As long as I can see her smiling and looking happy,
that's enough for me.
Then I'm sure I'll be able to go somewhere else.
There you are!
We'll get you for what you did before.
Not now...
Get back, Natsume.
You get back too, Aoi.
I guess that doesn't really work on birds.
You little wimps.
Natsume!
We'll handle them.
You get going!
If you can't go back to the way things were,
then say goodbye for real!
And if you really can't forget her, then tell her that!
I'm sure if he goes, he'll understand.
If he sees her, I'm sure Aoi-san will understand how he really feels.
Am I at the wrong spot?
Kaoru? What about your marriage?
Let me go, idiot!
I won't!
I refuse to ever let you go again!
Stop running, and let's talk!
Let me go! I'm...
I don't care that you're a youkai!
Aoi-chan... Aoi-chan...
Don't leave me.
There'll be even more tears later.
That's not true.
If that day comes, I'll drive it away.
You don't understand, Kaoru.
That's the problem.
That's why...
I'm sorry, Aoi-san.
I actually knew the invitation was...
It's fine.
You can laugh at me if you want.
Tell me I'm someone who can't stick to my decision.
I know you probably don't want to hear it,
but I'm happy for you.
This is from Kaoru. It's to thank you.
Oh, that's a limited edition box of sweet bean rice balls from Nanatsujiya!
Yeah.
We youkai can be a bit of a pain if we get used to human food.
You've got a handful of trouble on your hands with Nyanko-sensei.
Fool.
You've still got the tastes of a kid.
I'm just entertaining myself and killing time.
Okay, I'll be going.
I have to say goodbye to Doutaka-sama.
Live the way you want.
Once you've met that special person...
Yes.
Natsume, see you around.
When Aoi-san said there would be more tears later,
whose tears did he mean?
Will I someday also be able to care more about being with someone than the fear of saying goodbye?
Yeah.
See you around.
While I was waiting for dawn to come
yoake wo machinagara
I closed my eyes in silence
shizuka ni me wo tojite
As I wait for a new wind to blow
atarashii kaze matteta dake no
A ray of light shines into my heart
kokoro ni hikari sashiteku
Goodnight, my first star of the evening
oyasumi watashi no ichiban boshi
Shine brightly for all eternity
zutto kagayaki tsudzukete
I won't ask you to grant my wishes
negai wa kanae tte nante
Since you're already watching over me
iwanai sotto mimamotteiru dakara
Don't give an answer, just hear me out
kotae nante iranai kara tada kiitehoshii
It's not a farewell, but these are my last words
sayonara janai saigo no kotoba
In this town you disappeared from, I'll keep singing your lullaby
kimi no uta wo kimi ga inai machi de uta itsudzukeru
Like an eternal flower in my dreams
yume no naka karenai hana
Natsume Yuujinchou  6
Next
Time on
What Flows
It's called Four Mask Hill even though there's only three masks.
It flowed away somewhere.
I'm sorry.
The one who protects you found this for you.
They were still there for me?