Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Midterm Exams
Last Day: Math
It's finally over!
How did you do, Natsume?
Come on, cheer up!
I didn't get enough sleep, my mind was a complete blank...
You're an idiot.
Cramming at the last minute is so silly.
I can't tell him I spent the whole night returning youkai their names, can I...
Moving on, now that the test is over. Why don't we find some place to unwind?
Perfect Day for a Walk
The Ideal Place
Tada!
Perfect Day for a Walk
The Ideal Place
What, what? You guys going somewhere again?
What is this? You again...
Oh, come on...
Ah, I want to go to this art gallery!
That's out of the question...
Natsume's Book of Play
How about going fishing again?
You're so dull...
Since it's autumn. How about grape picking?
No!
We should go to places where we can enrich our knowledge.
How is that any fun?
Hey, time to go home!
Perfect.
Where would you want to go?
What's going on?
Probably planning for an outing.
How about the beach?
The weather is too cold for the beach. Isn't it?
You seem different nowadays, Tanuma-kun.
Though we're in different classes and I don't really know you, I thought you were rather cool.
I never imagined you would join them in this stupid boys talk.
You mean we have been talking stupid all this time?!
Oh, not Natsume-kun...
No... he's just like us.
That's right!
It's the same for Tanuma as well!
Natsume-kun and Tanuma-kun were both fairly quiet when they transferred here.
You bet!
Like they were off-bound or something.
But after talking to them, they are really just like us.
Furthermore, these two faint rather easily.
That...
Well...
Jeez, this is giving me a headache...
Should we just go fishing?
Didn't you say that was kind of dull?
I guess it means we have grown up now...
Huh?
It's like this, isn't it?
When we were kids, as long as we could go out and play we would have a great time. Right?
Ah... so that's what you mean.
As we grow older, we should learn to find entertainment that is suitable for our age.
Soon, we'll be venturing into the world of adult entertainment.
Adult entertainment?
How about this!
No, not that...
I was trying to say...
If we were kids, it'd be easy to have a good time,
and we wouldn't have such a headache.
Yeah, you're right.
We had a blast everyday.
What were the games you guys played?
I played house, marbles...
We played explorers.
Explorers?
Yeah.
Once, I took a bunch of kids from the neighborhood to the reservoir
and got a real good scolding after that.
We played games like that too.
We played hide and seek in the temple grounds.
One time, I hid inside this shrine that stored the cultural relics.
Got me a good beating when my dad found out.
Tags and hide-and-seeks are the best!
Shadow tag!
We played shadow tag all the time.
If your shadow is stepped on, you're tagged.
I know that one.
So does everyone!
Yeah.
I couldn't join them, I just watched them from afar...
In the end, we still haven't decided on a place to go.
You shot down everything.
Natsume-kun, if it's up to you. Where would you want to go?
Honestly... where we go is not important.
As long as we all go together, I'll be happy.
Oh, yeah!
Say, "cheese!"
What was that for?
This is the camera the teacher lend me for the cultural fair.
He told me to take some pictures for the yearbook as well.
Yearbook?
Isn't that kind of early?
Not at all. It won't be long...
Tanuma, are you going to take over the temple after you graduate?
I haven't really thought about it.
Sasada, you are going to further your studies. Right?
What am I to do...
Yeah, but I haven't decided on the school yet.
Plan ahead?
For Touko-san and Shigeru-san, I really should think about it...
But, what kind of work am I suited for?
No, no, no...
Let's enjoy our high school lives a little more before we decide.
Yeah, that sounds good.
I'm home.
Good to have you back, Takashi-kun.
How's your test?
Okay... I guess...
I see. Good.
I'm making tempura today.
Change and come down.
Yeah.
Oh, wait!
I need you to taste this.
Sure...
Come on...
Well?
It's delicious.
It'd be better still if the coating is a little thinner.
Potato
Shigeru-san!
You can't eat that!
But why?
Takashi can eat it, why can't I?
It's shrimp!
I only bought so many!
It's just one shrimp...
No way. You get one less later...
I'll go get change.
Welcome back, Natsume-sama.
Welcome back.
Why is everybody here?
Sensei called for a meeting?
Why would I do that?
They have something to tell you.
What's this about?
If it's troublesome, forget it.
No, not at all!
[ Note: The day the moon emanates "demonic light" ]
Truth is... tomorrow is the Demon Moon.
Sake becomes especially tasty that night.
Tasty, tasty...
Demon Moon?
Indeed...
Not to mention that the stars are especially well aligned today,
the sake will definitely be several times better than usual.
We will gather around and drink for the whole day tomorrow.
Drink, drink...
Coincidentally, you already know all the youkai that will be there.
This party to honor Natsume-sama will be held in that old dilapidate shrine near Yatsuhara.
Dilapidated, dilapidated...
It is a party for us youkai who help Natsume-sama with his problems
and for us who were ordered around like dogs.
A.K.A. the "Natsume's Dog Club"!
Woof!
What kind of naming is that...
We'll pick you up tomorrow.
But let us first give you the run down.
Sorry, I'm not going.
I don't like it.
Don't be such a stranger.
It's us! No need to be shy!
No need, no need...
That's right.
Natsume-sama, please join us.
Stop it, you guys!
Takashi-kun, hurry down.
Yeah!
Listen, that is all for today!
Yes...
Nyanko-sensei, you're my bodyguard. Right?
Do something about it.
It's not that bad. Just go!
Who knows, it might be fun!
Sensei, that's the sake talking.
Taki!
Natsume-kun!
Recording...
Kitty!
Stop!
Stop it! Stop it!
Natsume, do something!
What's going on, Taki?
You didn't get cursed again, did you?
No... I've decided...
I'm going to memorize all the research material my grandfather did on youkai.
Rest assure, I won't do anything that is dangerous.
When I draw circles, I don't complete them and I would also erase them thereafter.
But I would still practice sketching them once in a while.
When the need arises, I might even be able to help you.
Me...
Not just that...
I don't wish to see my grandfather's belief to just disappear like that.
Taki...
Although I haven't decided on what I want to do in life, this is what I can do now. Right?
Natsume-sama...
Please return my name.
Sensei.
Jeez.
I'll come with you.
Taki.
Sorry, I have errands to run.
Go on without me.
Okay. See you!
That which shields me, reveal thy name.
I return your name.
Natsume
Yuujinchou
What's this?
We met this morning...
He's here! Grab him!
What are you trying to do?
Stop it!
Wait...
You're late, Natsume.
Sensei?!
The
Dog Club
We waited long...
Welcome!
You're so slow...
Let's start drinking!
Over here, over here...
Sit next to me?
Here you go, Natsume-sama.
Your 3-cup "punishment".
No, I'm a minor.
You're always so stiff...
That tickles. Stop!
Natsume...
Benio-san?
Long time no see...
I came to check out the free drinks. You?
Hey, Benio!
Madara-sama.
You are still in that miserable tiny form.
What do you know?
People adore me.
Especially human girls!
What?!
Natsume-sama is awesome, you know so many powerful youkai.
Really?
Hey, Natsume!
You dance too!
No, I can't.
Natsume-sama, what do humans do when they gather around like this?
I want to know too.
What do humans do?
Let's see...
Cards?
And for outdoor games...
Probably kicking cans or playing shadow tag.
Shadow tag? That sounds interesting.
That's right!
Since Natsume-sama can't drink, we'll play this "shadow tag" game with him instead!
Play... play...
Who says anything about–
Natsume-sama, how do we play this game?
You guys know the game of "tag", right?
The idea is the same, except that when your shadow is stepped on, you become the "ghost" for the next round.
"Ghost"? That is so interesting...
You can eat the people you catch, right?
No, that's against the rules.
Basically, it is a game where you hide from the "ghost", so that it don't step on your shadow.
Just find a shady place then.
According to the rules, you can't stay in the shade for more than five seconds.
Alright.
I'll be the "ghost" first.
The area is confined to the temple grounds.
Here we go!
This is how it's done... right?
Stay away!
Don't come here!
Natsume's a liar!
Get lost!
Let's take a rest here.
Ghost! ghost!
Shoot!
Got you, Chobi!
Why am I so careless?
That one has short legs.
Your shadow is mine!
You're the "ghost" now!
Damn!
I'm so pissed!
The beast blood within is boiling!
No good...
I'm so happy!
I step... on your shadow!
Natsume, prepare yourself!
What are you doing?
You're not the "ghost" anymore!
Shut up!
Damn you, Natsume...
No use darting in and out!
Cut it out, Nyanko-sensei.
To think you're my bodyguard...
You think I'm going to let you off easy?!
Madara-sama, get him!
Get him!
It's a disgrace to be fighting humans...
Shut up!
Didn't I say physical attacks are against the rules?!
That was close...
Natsume, are you not breaking the rules as well?
In that case, since Madara-sama stepped on me first. I'll be the next "ghost".
Misuzu?
It's been a while, Natsume-dono.
You have some guts calling us "dogs."
The
Dog Club
I didn't approve that...
Got you!
You're the "ghost" now, Misuzu-sama.
Oh, I'm the "ghost"?
Let's try this out!
Wait!
You're only supposed to step on the shadows of those running away!
I see...
This is such an interesting game!
Run, lesser beings... run!
Sorry Misuzu, would you mind being the referee?
One... two... three...
If I step on your shadow, I can do whatever I want with you. Right?
No, you can't.
That's right! We should just run with our shadows in front of us!
Run! Run!
What is this game?
It's never ending...
Who could imagine that the humans came up with a game like this?!
Natsume, how do we end this?
To be honest, I only watched from a distance.
That's why... I don't know.
What?!
You're playing this for the first time too?
Yeah.
I finally understand why kids love playing this so much.
No, not me!
I have so many youkai friends now...
I wonder if Reiko-san ever felt this way...
You're the next "ghost", Madara-sama?
This is how we would play the last game...
Once your shadow is stepped on, you're eliminated.
And when everyone is eliminated, the "ghost" wins.
Just a minute!
Doesn't that mean I've to run a lot?!
Excellent idea.
Those that were eliminated will go inside here.
Graveyard
I don't want to go in there...
Listen to me!
Let the game begin!
No!
Damn it! Wait!
I got one!
I'm dead!
Another one!
Dead!
Next?!
Oww... I've fallen into a pit?
I guess nobody is gonna step on my shadow here...
Wait! Don't run!
I'm not that stupid to listen to you.
Come on! Wait up, okay?!
Hello there...
You're Natsume, right? Come!
Whenever I move to a new place,
some of the kids would always come over and talk to me.
But then, I started to say weird things.
Who wouldn't hate a liar...
Natsume is a liar!
Scram, Natsume!
Hey, Natsume!
The new kid, come join us!
It's so nice that you can keep moving houses, Natsume...
You have been to many places and have met many people.
See you!
Bye-bye!
Later!
Natsume!
Nyanko-sensei.
You're so clumsy.
Get up here now.
You're the last one.
When you step on my shadow, it'll be all over.
So you're gonna hide down there forever?
No... I can't get up.
Give me a hand!
What?
You're such a nuisance.
Oh, Natsume-dono...
Natsume-sama!
He got you too?
I say, humans are weak.
What is this?
Isn't it the same with you guys?
The "ghost" wins!
Let's drink up to celebrate!
Celebrate! Celebrate!
Sorry for being this weak...
We'll protect you.
If you call out to us, we can't just forsake you. Right?
Can't ignore...
Because we see something in you.
Hey, Natsume!
So you're out here!
We're going over to Tanuma's place to continue with yesterday's discussion.
You should come too.
What are you doing, Natsume?
Is there something there?
No...
Go, Natsume.
I'll stay here for a bit more.
Sensei...
Natsume!
See you!
I used to hate being able to see youkai.
But it's also because of that, that I meet so many people.
That is really how I see it now.
They're my friends.
Right now, humans and youkai are equally...
...irreplaceable to me.