Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
The Cultural Fair is fast approaching.
What's your class doing?
We'll be deciding tomorrow.
Personally, I'd go for the Bunny Girl Cafe.
Bunny girls won't do.
Why not fairies?
Fairies?
Hey, that's...
Natsume...
What's he doing?
Standing up there... It's danger–
Natsume!
Hey, you okay?
Jeez...
What are you doing, Natsume?
Sorry.
Nishimura.
Kitamoto.
I can't tell them a youkai was messing with me...
Don't swim in your school uniform!
At least put your bag down...
I'm really sorry.
Thanks.
Umm... we'll catch a cold like this.
Why not come to my place first?
Welcome ho–
Oh! My my...
Hello ma'am.
Sorry to intrude.
Excuse us.
It's okay. Quickly, come in and take a bath!
Sorry for the trouble.
I haven't been here in ages!
Umm, Touko-san.
They were drenched because of me.
I didn't know you could be so mischievous.
The people of this town are all good people.
Bye!
I mustn't let them know I can see youkai...
Through the Autumn Wind
Sleeping again?
It's dull when it's all so quiet.
Get well soon, Sensei.
A rock?
Did it get washed into the bag when I fell into the river?
What's with that rock?
I see you're still attracting all sorts of youkai, Natsume.
Hinoe...
I'm grateful, but you're wearing clogs...
[ Note: The "tumbler (toy)" is used to describe Nyanko-sensei because he is fat and round, and he never falls (until now) -- just like a tumbler (weebles). ]
I came to see how the tumbler cat was doing.
How is he?
He's always sleeping.
That's a good sign.
If he's really in pain, he wouldn't even be able to sleep.
He's slowly recovering.
I'm relieved then.
Natsume-sama!
We came again to see him.
Again?!
You're not going to drink all night this time!
I still have school tomorrow!
Don't be such a stranger.
Stranger... Stranger...
You reek of alcohol!
Haven't you drink enough already?
[ Sake: A rice-based alcohol. ]
A little sake won't hurt...
When did you get here, Chobi?!
Let's have a good time protecting you tonight.
Protecting you...
Listen, I've a bad feeling about that rock.
Try to be careful for the time being, Natsume.
It was an all nighter...
Cultural Fair
So, any ideas for the Cultural Fair?
A cross-dressing cafe!
How's that any good for the guys? No way!
I've got one! Bunny! Bunny girls!
A cafe is hard to operate...
I like to walk about, why not just display the things we sell.
Didn't we agree to run a bazaar?!
It's very lively in here too.
Quiet down please.
One at a time, raise your hand to voice your opinion.
Me.
We could take the things we don't want at home...
I didn't really like noisy environment.
Lately though, listening to these voices gives me a sense of calmness.
What's she staring at?
Did she drop something?
Natsume-kun, what's distracting you?
Were you listening?
It's decided, Natsume will tend the stall.
Wait a second!
That's great.
I'll lose all the customers...
Natsume-kun is watching the stall?
Don't tease me, Taki.
I'm sorry.
So, Class 2 is running a bazaar...
What's your class doing, Tanuma-kun?
We're doing a play.
A play? That's amazing!
Tanuma-kun, will you be acting then?
I'm in charge of the lighting.
And Taki's class?
A cross-dressing cafe.
I couldn't talk to anyone last year, remember?
Yeah, that was tough.
You were cursed by a youkai.
I am going to enjoy this Cultural Fair.
I know the three of us haven't been to many fairs, but let's all do our best!
Yeah.
There's the lead of our play.
Lead...
Kitamoto?
Hey, Natsume.
Come with me.
What's with you, Nishimura?
Natsume, you've been really close with Taki-san lately.
That's not fair! It's not fair at all!
They seem like good friends.
But Natsume-kun can't even tell his close friends about youkai, right?
He keeps things from us too.
Taki-san is mine!
You got it all wrong.
Kitamoto, you're the lead of the play?
We draw lots.
What kind of play?
Shakespeare's.
You'll be wearing white tights?
I'm not gonna wear that.
I must see it for myself.
Natsume is tending a stall, right?
All the best!
Make sure you put on a smile, 'kay?
Blood?!
This isn't youkai's blood, is it?
Natsume...
What's going on?
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Someone knocked over a tin of paint.
Careful not to step on it.
Oh... it's just paint.
What's wrong, Natsume?
You look pale.
I'm fine.
Really?
Yeah.
That class has already started to work.
They're so impatient.
What if that was youkai's blood?
What should I had done then?
Here, in the school...
Natsume-kun?
Who's there?
Who is she?
She's the girl from before, who was staring at the ground.
You dropped this.
What did I...
Bye!
Supply Room
Was the stone controlling her?
It has such power...
What should I do?
Dump it? What if it harms someone?
Now that I have the chance, should I smash it or tie it up?
Are you saying something?
What?
What are you trying to do?
Tell me your secret.
That voice...
Tell me your secr–
Natsume-kun!
What happened to you, Natsume-kun?
Sasada... I'm fine.
Are you sick?
Should we go to the nurse's office?
No, it's nothing.
If you want to go home, I'll come with you.
Sasada, sorry to worry you.
I'm okay now.
Really?
You scared me.
Oh... crap!
It changed back to a normal rock.
Where did the youkai go?
Natsume
Yuujinchou
It got to you?
Seems like a quite powerful youkai is sealed in it.
What is he after?
I'm guessing he can possess things.
He probably wants to possess someone powerful, someone such as you.
If he's only after me, he won't harm other people, right?
Well... he possessed that girl earlier probably just to get to you.
Or maybe, there are some other persons or objects in your school that interests him.
Interests him?
After lying at the bottom of the river for so long,
of course he would want to know everything now.
When he's close to you, not only is he stealing your spiritual energy,
he is also peeking into your heart.
My heart?
Tell me your secret.
My... secret?
Listen, Natsume.
Don't let your guard down or let him see your weaknesses.
Yeah.
It won't be long till your tumbler cat bodyguard recovers.
Just hold out until then.
Thank you, Hinoe.
Is the rock youkai trying to find the Book of Friends?
Nyanko-sensei, rest well.
Sensei, our school is holding a Cultural Fair.
I'd be assisting in a bazaar.
I am going to enjoy this Cultural Fair.
Let's all do our best!
There'll be all kinds of things and all sorts of stalls.
I'm sure it'd be fun.
You can find lots of delicious food too.
I hope it goes well.
I have to find that youkai.
I don't want my classmates to get hurt because of me.
Natsume!
Nishimura? Kitamoto?
What's up guys?
Well...
What is it?
He possessed that girl earlier probably just to get to you.
What's wrong?
Why are you staring at us like that?
It's nothing...
Natsume, do you not want to tend the stall?
Huh?
Because you look really pale today.
No...
You're always being polite to other people.
But you can be frank with us.
We just want you to have fun.
If you really don't want to do it, tell us.
I'll do it instead.
Thank you.
But I'm really...
I'm really looking forward to it.
I'm so fortunate...
What should I do about this?
I'll be tending the stall too.
This is yours, Natsume-kun.
And yours, Tsuji-kun.
I'll be tending the stall too?
An apron?
Yeah.
All personnel tending the stall must wear one.
Be sure to also stitch this ribbon on yourself.
Nothing seems to be off.
Don't let your guard down or let him see your weaknesses.
Hey, Natsume!
Help me out here.
Sure!
Is this not a dagger I see before me?
Oww!
I have thee not, and yet...
I can't do it!
How do you expect me to remember such a long line!
You guys sure look gloomy...
52nd Annual Cultural Festival
Okay, put it there!
Be careful guys.
Days passed by as I continued to stay on the lookout.
But that youkai was nowhere to be seen.
Finally, it's the day of the Cultural Festival.
That looks perfect on you!
Please come in!
Feel free to look around.
Flower Bazaar Room
Thank you for coming.
Natsume-kun, can I take a picture with you?
Picture?
Excuse me. Can I get this free along with this?
Umm, well...
Hey, handsome!
Taki!
That's a guy's suit?!
Natsume, how much is this?
Natsume!
Umm...
This is harder than I thought.
Natsume-kun, good work.
Go and take a break.
Thanks.
Come on, girls.
What's the secret?
Why are you keeping secrets from your friends?
What do you want to know?
It has nothing to do with that girl, right?
Wait!
You came for me, right?
Watch out...
I have to catch her...
It's all because of me...
Isn't that...
Natsume?
Stop!
Give her back!
Watch out!
Secret...
Jeez...
I came for the delicious food you talked about.
Get lost, rock.
Weakling!
Natsume!
What's the secret?
Even though I can't tell them, they're still my friends.
What are you protecting?
Yes... will I be able to protect them?
Natsume!
Hey, new guy.
Don't you think it's about time you ask for a bicycle from them?
We can't hang out together otherwise.
I'm sorry, you guys just go without me.
I can't ride a bike.
Why?
You can't learn how to ride a bike without someone assisting you, right?
Very good! You're doing fine!
I want to protect the seemingly peaceful days and the friends whom I share my life.
You're fine, you're doing just fine!
This is the first time I actually have friends to hang out with.
They're important to me. What should I do?
The more people who are important to me, the more worried I become...
...of what might happen.
Nyanko-sensei?
Oh, you saved me.
Youkai like him don't even need to be sealed.
I drove him away.
Nyanko-sensei...
I'm glad that you're back in good health.
I can't do anything.
I can't do anything by myself.
Humans are like that...
But I think I've seen something...
...something that gives me courage.
Natsume, you're up!
What were you doing?
Doing something that dangerous!
Each and every time!
What were you thinking, idiot?!
I heard Natsume-kun fell?! Is he okay?
Oh, good.
Natsume, you look well.
Natsume-kun!
Everybody's here already.
Seeing the people I want to protect, so protective over me...
I will continue to learn from the new experiences and keep moving forward.
The Cultural Fair is finally over.
Hey!
Want to go to fishing?
Ride your bike over!
Sure!
Even if it's small, take a step forward.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
The Broken Mirror
Lately, I think Tanuma's been avoiding me.
You worry too much about other people.
He's my friend.
If something had happened, I want to be there for him.
I'm sorry, Natsume.
I didn't mean to hide it from you.
But...
I've found you.
Return me my mirror!