Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Ever since I was a child,
I've sometimes seen strange things.
My my, we didn't catch a thing today.
I'm hungry.
[ Akebi: An edible fruit found in shrubs. ]
Maybe I'll go pick some akebi.
You there.
Did you see a human child just now?
The grandchild of Natsume Reiko,
the one with the Book of Friends,
should have run this way.
Lie to me and I'll eat you, too.
We don't know anything!
That's right!
Where did he run?
He looked yummy too.
He's gone.
A human child.
The things I see are probably what other people
call "youkai", or monsters.
The Name of a Monster
My grandmother left me a book: "The Book of Friends".
My grandmother possessed strong spiritual powers
and challenged every youkai she met to a battle.
When she defeated them, she had them
write their names in this book
to prove that they would obey her.
The Book of Friends is a set of contracts.
Call the names within
and the name holder cannot disobey.
Ever since I got it, I've spent my days running from youkai.
I have to catch my breath first before I go in.
A teacup?
What's it doing in a place like this?
Hey, come out here!
Don't go hiding under people's houses!
Takashi-kun?
Yes?
Oww...
T-Touko-san?
I'm back.
Shopping took longer than I thought.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
What's wrong?
Um, I thought I saw a rat. Probably just my imagination.
No problem.
We have a cat at home.
Yes, yes we do.
My, you've dirt all over...
[ Sukiyaki: A Japanese hotpot/steamboat dish. ]
Oh right, we're having sukiyaki today, Takashi-kun.
That's great!
That was close.
I need to be careful
not to do anything that might seem weird.
If that was indeed a rat, we should buy some rat traps.
No, I've made a mistake, it was something else.
Maybe it was just one of our neighbor's puppies.
Takashi-kun, a second round perhaps?
Sure.
I lost my parents when I was young,
and my relatives passed me around until finally
the Fujiwaras took me in.
This home is very dear to me.
Here you go.
It's called a Kagejawan (shadow cup).
It's lived below the house for about two weeks.
It's been there two weeks?!
Sensei, you're supposed to be guarding the house!
Calm down, idiot.
Ooh, I won!
Go get me another, Natsume.
Sensei!
When an exceptionally well-made teacup
breaks and is thrown out,
sometimes it absorbs the power of the Earth
and becomes a youkai.
Then it takes up residence
under old houses so it can be near people.
So it can be near people?
I hear that sometimes when a disaster
is about to visit the house,
it will run around to warn people,
and sometimes on a whim
it will sacrifice itself to prevent it.
So, it's harmless?
That's right.
Once it gets bored, it'll leave.
Let it be.
I see.
And I'm not a "guard",
it's just that I get the Book of Friends after you die,
so I'm protecting you from youkai that come to take it.
Good evening.
Natsume-sama, yes?
I've come to ask for my name back.
Ever since I inherited the Book of Friends,
I've returned the names of the youkai within it.
First I bring up an image of them in my mind,
and recite...
"That which shields me, reveal thy name."
To release their names, you need the saliva
and breath of someone of the same
bloodline as Reiko.
Thank you.
When I return their names, I get really tired.
You idiot!
There goes another page out of the book!
They come without asking,
and then they leave just the same.
Will I ever become strong enough
to not have my life ruled by them?
What's that sound?
It sounds like footsteps.
I hear that sometimes when a disaster
is about to visit the house,
it will run around to warn people
It's running around already!
Careful!
Sensei!
It's nothing to do with me!
Year 2
Class 2
In other words,
some kind of disaster is going to visit the house?
What's wrong, Natsume?
Finally having troubles with love?
No, it's nothing like that.
Just didn't get enough sleep.
You must be up reading those "H" books, I guess?
No.
What? What?
What's going on with Natsume?
It has nothing to do with girls.
What? That's no fun.
Come on, you can tell me!
I've made friends since I came to this town.
Are you okay?
I heard that my grandmother, Reiko,
didn't have many human friends.
I think that's why she picked fights
with all the youkai she met.
Oww...
My staff, my staff.
Are you all right?
Your staff is right here.
Can you stand?
Oh my, you're so kind.
You can see me, can't you, child?
This is bad, she's a youkai!
What strong power you have, child!
Let go of me!
Perfect timing.
I can't see well, child.
Help this old woman out.
I borrowed a mirror from a powerful youkai a long time ago.
I don't know her name,
but the other youkai feared her
and said she brought with her great disasters.
Someone of your power should be able to find her!
Let go of me!
I can't do that!
I'm sorry, but I can't help you!
Oh my, that's no good.
Since you can see youkai,
then you should also know the consequences of refusing one.
Regardless, I don't want to be in any part of this...
If I get involved with a youkai that brings disaster...
I might bring disaster to the Fujiwara family...
My poor child, a word of advice...
If you don't help me,
I'll curse you.
No!
I'll be waiting here tomorrow.
If you don't come, I'll kill you!
Nyanko-sensei!
What's wrong, Natsume?
Trouble. Some weird youkai-
You've been cursed, haven't you?
Who dares lay a hand on my prey?!
An old lady...
An old lady?
Sounds scary.
Hey, wake up.
Natsume!
Hey, Natsume!
What is it?
Something the old lady said bothered me...
The Kagejawan is running...
Did I bring in the disaster?
It's not going to bloom this year either?
If it withers away,
I'll be sad and have nothing to look forward to.
Don't worry, I'll save you.
Just wait.
A dream.
Or was it that youkai's doing?
I came.
Why?
You said you'd wait till tomorrow.
I couldn't wait.
I finally met somebody who could find her.
It would be a waste if you ran away.
I'm an impatient old lady.
Will you help me?
Or will you not help me?
Fine.
I'll help you.
So don't come into this house!
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Is that old lady somebody so powerful
even you couldn't get rid of her?
My guess is that she's a divine being
that once had a shrine.
I'd be all right,
but if somebody less powerful touched her
they'd probably be cursed.
She's that strong?
How annoying.
In this age most gods like that are sick or weakened.
She looks like she can barely see.
Go with her for a bit and just take care of it.
So someone with less power can't even get close.
Is that why she's so glad
she found a human who can see youkai?
A god who can be with neither youkai nor humans.
Reiko-san...
This smell...
This way, child.
Thank you for coming!
I don't have a choice, do I?
A flower?
It smells good, doesn't it?
I put it in my hair to show off.
It does smell good.
I see... it does, it does.
This way, child.
I met her in the forest up ahead.
Stop calling me "child," please.
I see.
Since she doesn't spend much of her time with youkai,
she doesn't know I'm the one with the Book of Friends.
It's easy to get lost in here...
Over here! Over here!
It's somewhere over here that I met her.
What kind of youkai was her?
She, who was known to bring disaster.
I couldn't see well, but she was quite small.
Small...
If we go all out,
maybe Sensei and I could take her.
Huh?
Didn't the old lady said she borrowed a mirror from her?
Even though it was so dangerous?
I see... so that's what bothered me.
I don't have many friends.
There was an old cherry blossom tree near me,
but it was possessed by a stubborn evil spirit.
An old tree...
so that's what that dream was.
So it started to wither,
and to get rid of it I needed a mirror.
I was looking for a mirror and
I came upon somebody holding one.
I thought I would steal it.
But I was defeated and knocked away.
Some god, huh?
But when I said I really needed the mirror,
she gave it to me.
Even though everyone avoided her in fear?
I guess she wasn't that bad.
That's right.
But the other youkai were terrified of her and kept their distance.
She said so herself, that she would bring disaster.
She said she didn't like humans much either.
After I got the mirror, I tried to get rid of the spirit, but was unsuccessful.
So I went back to return the mirror.
But she said she didn't want to see the mirror, and didn't take it.
From then on, we would meet occasionally and chat.
When I looked at her this close,
she had a scar somewhere here.
Though the youkai disliked her,
that scar seemed to be the result of an attack by humans.
I found her kind of cute, and invited her to my home.
But when she saw my shrine,
she seemed a little disappointed.
Not long after, I told her my story,
and she got rid of the spirit in the tree for me.
See, this flower is from that tree.
Now that I think about it, why is it that you smell so much like her?
And when I look at you up close, you look kind of like her too.
Please show me that mirror.
I've been sensing the heat emanating from the Book of Friends for a while now.
Old lady, the person you're looking for...
I've finally found you,
Natsume, of the Book of Friends!
This time you won't get away!
Dinnertime!
He's the one from before!
My left shoulder...
Sensei!
Get lost!
Natsume!
Pull yourself together, wimp!
Child...
Thank goodness, your shoulder's fine.
I thought it ate you...
Yes, it doesn't seem to be broken.
Here I thought that lump of fur there
was supposed to be your bodyguard.
Useless, isn't he?
What?! Wasn't it I who got rid of him?!
Moreover, it's all because Natsume was careless!
He's right.
I need to be more careful.
It's different now...
at least to me...
Honestly, I don't care if he loses
an arm or a leg or two,
as long as the Book of Friends is safe.
Hey, Natsume, the Book of Friends is safe, right?
Yeah.
Old lady...
Your name is in the Book of Friends, isn't it?
The Book of Friends...
Come to think of it,
I did write my name on something.
Ever since then, she stopped coming for some reason.
Old lady, there is no point to still be looking for her.
She was probably my grandmother, Natsume Reiko -- a human.
That which shields me, reveal thy name.
I return your name.
Please take it,
Aokuchinashi.
How infuriating.
The flowers of that tree were my one pleasure.
A mirror...
If only I had a mirror...
A mirror?
Hey, look, over there.
I heard she brings disaster.
She's said to be more terrible than a demon god.
We should stay away.
Let's do that.
Lets.
What? The one who smells like a child of man...
I'm going to take it anyway!
No!
I've failed.
My staff... my staff.
Are you okay?
Your staff is here.
Can you stand?
Would you give me your mirror?
Huh?
The one friend I have needs a mirror!
They sell mirrors at the store up the road.
I just need to borrow it for a while.
Here you are.
Really?
But...
It's fine.
Just looking at it through the mirror isn't going to cure my wound.
What? You're hurt?
Hmm... Let me see...
That tickles.
You're a strange person.
I'm glad you're here today.
Here's your mirror back.
I don't need it anymore.
You can keep it.
But...
I hate looking into the mirror.
You've been coming here often lately.
I want to go further away, actually.
Far, far away.
A place nobody knows.
Would you come to my place?
Can I?
Yes, there's a tree, though almost withered away,
it has very beautiful flowers.
Come see it.
Here it is.
A shrine...
And there's the tree.
Yeah... right...
I thought it was strange...
Somebody who would actually talk to me...
You're a youkai, aren't you?
That's right.
What's your name?
Do you want to know it?
Then have a match with me.
If you win, I'll do anything you say.
You can even eat me if you want.
But if I win, you'll write your name...
I remember now.
After losing the match, I wrote my name on a piece of paper.
She never did give me her name.
I see... so it's Reiko.
Her name was Natsume Reiko.
So, Reiko is no longer in this world.
Yes.
Please keep that mirror.
I'm going home.
You've helped me greatly, grandson of Reiko.
Go down that path and you'll return back to civilization.
Yes.
Straight down that path!
Farewell!
Just like the old lady thought Reiko was a youkai,
Reiko thought the old lady was human.
How happy she must've been when she thought
she had a human friend.
I thought it was strange...
This incident couldn't be the reason why Reiko started to hate youkai.
Hey, Natsume?
Look!
The flowers the old lady talked about...
Yeah, this is the tree Reiko banished the spirit from.
Crazy woman, she was just a human.
Yeah, that's right.
She got rid of the evil spirit from the tree
after she learned that the old lady was a youkai.
I'm back.
Touko-san, what's wrong?
Look, Takashi-kun.
There's a broken tea cup I've never seen before here.
See, whose is this?
...and sometimes on a whim
it will sacrifice itself to prevent it.
It's mine.
It's very important to me.
They come without asking,
and then they leave just the same.
But once you meet them,
even if nobody ever knows it,
that encounter will change your life for the better.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Ukihara Village
The village of Ukihara?
It's a legendary village that's not part of this world.
Then how did they get here?
You don't think the smell of ikayaki
and the sound of festival music brought them here?
I want to return.
Together, if possible.