Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Tanuma was possessed by a youkai.
And until we find all the broken pieces of the mirror, it's not going to leave.
I was worried that something might happen to him,
so I decided to stay at his house for the time being.
The Reverend is not around?
My father is out on a job again.
I see.
Hey, kid.
Give me a chestnut.
Right, right.
How much of the mirror did we find this afternoon?
Just this. You see it?
Natsume, you're amazing...
I can barely see it.
Oh.
Hey, kid.
Don't touch it for no reason!
And you don't take over Tanuma for no reason!
Exactly. That's my chestnut, give it back!
That's my chestnut, you hear me!
I'd be so much easier if I was the one being possessed.
The mirror went into my eye!
Didn't I tell you, the mirror wants to return to its former self.
That's why the pieces resonate and make the host find them.
Just find them all and be done with it.
What the Mirror Shows
Does this sometimes happen to you too, Natsume?
What do you mean?
Youkai asking you to do something?
Not "sometimes", it's all the time.
All the time?
Nyanko-sensei!
He's too nice.
Whenever youkai ask for something, he can't bring himself to ignore them.
How difficult is it to refuse them?
I can't help it, okay.
I see.
Tanuma...
No, it isn't.
Farewell. Don't come back anymore.
This is the dream of the youkai possessing Tanuma.
Don't come back?
Did I do something?
Just don't come back...
Why?
Farewell.
Farewell...
You peeked into my dream, didn't you, kid?
Was that the friend you're looking for?
That youkai is sick or something...
Can you heal him with that mirror?
That's a difficult illness to treat...
Is there... Is there anything that can treat him?
You wish to cure him?
Yes.
There's still hope for him.
Really?!
Yes.
However, it isn't something you can easily get your hands on.
You must be tired.
You must be cold.
Take a rest.
We'll warm you up.
We'll give you a hot drink.
You can rest in our arms.
Why do you persevere?
You're not here for our mirror, are you?
We won't let you.
We won't let you...
Stupid fool.
It's not there.
You've been tricked.
Oh no!
No good!
The abominable sun is up!
It will reveal our mirror!
Damn it!
Where are you?
Where have you gone?
I found the thing to cure you!
Huh?
Natsume?
Tanuma, how are you feeling?
Did I... again...
That sound came from the temple.
A thief... guess not...
It's been broken from the outside.
The raccoons in the forest tend to get mischievous at this time of the year.
Natsume?
That way.
Hey!
If only I knew what he could see,
I wouldn't be so clueless on what he's doing...
You want to see?
Can I?
As a token of my appreciation for borrowing your body, I can lend you my eyes.
So do you want to see?
Yeah.
What is this?
Natsume can see even things like this?
Natsume?
That youkai with the hammer who was wandering around at school is here.
He's... he's the one loitering?
So this is the world Natsume sees...
Tanuma, you see him too?
She lent her eyes to me.
I found... the mirror.
I'll break you, and retrieve it.
I will not let a rogue like you take my mirror.
Don't get in the way.
Begone!
T-Tanuma?
You all right?
Tanuma!
Don't go overboard – letting Tanuma see youkai like this.
Though you saved me, you made Tanuma go though all that!
You want the mirror, right?
You have close friends, right?
It's the same for me, Tanuma is my close friend.
I won't let you off if you try this again!
Would you take me instead?
I'll help you look for the mirror.
You can let Tanuma go.
He wishes to see youkai;
You never talk about youkai.
There is no reason to, right?
You're just too kind.
Yes, I know that.
But if you don't tell him, how do you expect him to know?
It's something important, yet he knows nothing of it...
He's right there with you, yet he knows nothing of it...
Same with my friend, he didn't tell me anything...
He didn't tell me anything!
He didn't tell me he was seriously ill.
And he didn't tell me when he left.
All I heard were the whispers of the wind...
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Why bother telling me, what difference would I make...
Thereafter, I went all out searching and eventually obtained the mirror that could dispel illnesses.
All I have to do now is find him...
Ahh... If I don't find the fragments quickly...
He'll...
I must hurry before it's too late...
I'm sorry, human child.
In my current state, even staying in this body is a struggle.
Just a little longer...
It has to be Yatsuhara.
Even those lowly youkai could get into temple grounds.
Nyanko-sensei.
Where have you been?
It got really bad here.
I was watching, trying to figure out what that "hammer" youkai is.
She got rid of it before I could make my move.
You should get some sleep too, Natsume.
I'll stay watch.
Why do you keep wasting your time on stupid things?
End this by tomorrow.
Yes, Sensei.
Before that, carry Tanuma back to his futon.
W-What?
I've to clear away the broken glass.
You owe me big time for this.
I'm not gonna settle for anything less than the buns from 7th Street Shop.
I still have to pay for the windows...
Heavy!
He's too heavy.
Go on a diet!
Get slim... like me!
Morning.
Are you two okay?
Morning...
I guess not.
Though my memory is a little foggy,
I remembered something blasting out of my mouth.
What did you eat?
No, it's not like that.
Oh, yeah. Natsume-kun, for you.
It's a talisman I made following the notes I found at home.
I don't know if it'll work, but I felt bad not doing anything.
It'll give me a peace of mind, I want you to have it.
Thank you, Taki.
Did you stay up all night to make this?
N-No, it wasn't that difficult.
Then I guess you get puffy eyes easily.
If only my fingers were more nimble...
Seems more to me like bad taste than bad needle-work.
If that's how you feel, I'm not going to give you your talisman.
I'm sorry... You made one for me, too?
Yes. Here.
Thank–
It's scary looking.
I can't help it.
That's how it should look.
You know what's more scary, making it in the middle of the night!
Thank you.
Okay, let's end this today.
Where's Nyanko-sensei, by the way?
He said he'd look around the school compound by himself.
Catnip
Hey, you guys.
Hurry up and find those youkai mirror fragments, understand?
Yes...
Where?
She said that the fragments would hide in shinny objects, didn't she?
Where is it?
Is this it?
The pain's gone now.
We'll have to check all the mirrors.
We'll continue after school.
Hey...
What?
Are there youkai here, too?
Yeah, small ones.
You want to see them?
Okay.
So this is what Natsume sees everyday.
Natsume?
Sorry for the wait.
Natsume, do you see...
Nevermind.
Alright, let's get started.
I don't see anything.
It's gotta be there.
What're you guys up to?
What a fine mirror!
That is some excellent craftsmanship!
Yeah, I wonder where it was made?
What a terrible cooked up story...
We've checked all the mirrors.
What else reflects light?
There is something glittering!
No doubt...
It's glittering...
It's around here.
Okay.
Around here?
You okay?
Yeah.
It still hurts.
There's more.
Nothing in it?
Wait!
Thank you, Taki.
It doesn't hurt now.
Wait here, I'll get the towels.
'Kay.
Thank you, Tanuma.
I'm the one being possessed.
I'm doing this for myself, too.
Do you encounter this a lot?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, I couldn't find a good chance to tell you.
It's difficult to express your fears and insecurities.
You're right.
It's difficult.
Hey, kiddos.
A raccoon... no... it's Ponta.
Natsume?
Sensei, are you carrying something with you?
Yes, I am.
Behold!
With my capabilities, you can even find the needle in a haystack! It's that easy!
Madara-sama!
Don't joke around with me!
Needle in a haystack...
Sounds really impressive, but you didn't actually do anything. Did you?
Watch what you say, kid!
Alright, take this and go.
Thank you.
Mirror... I want it!
This is bad!
I want that power!
Natsume!
Give it to me.
Give me the mirror.
Too bad, you can't have the mirror.
Seeing how it works, I guess it could dispel illnesses too.
Natsume, you okay?!
Are you leaving?
Yes.
I must find my friend.
Get rid of his illness and really talk to him.
Yeah.
Will she ever find him?
It's a serious illness.
Her friend might already be...
You don't have to worry about me.
I just need to find him...
No matter what awaits me.
I'll make sure he hears what I have to say.
Farewell, human child.
Don't be afraid to speak your heart out when you have the chance.
Though that can be difficult.
That's why it's all the more precious... because it doesn't always pan out.
Just like this, this incident with Tanuma is finally over.
Oh really? She's gone...
Let's tell Taki about it.
Yeah.
I feel bad that you guys were worried about me, but it's actually quite fun.
Huh?
I saw what you see.
And that youkai and I had quite a conversation.
What did you two talk about?
Not anything weird, I hope?
It's been hard Natsume, hasn't it?
Hard?
Not really, it's not all bad.
Right?
Yeah.
You're right.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
A Place to Go Home To
If that person hadn't appear before me back then, I'd...
I like the lonely ones. They are interesting to watch.
Hey Natsume, where are you going?
That's the first time anyone ever invited me.
Stay away from strangers!