Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
BBQ Squid
BBQ Octopus
Hey, Natsume!
BBQ Squid
BBQ Octopus
Squid! They've got ikayaki!
BBQ Squid
BBQ Octopus
Summer festival is coming.
BBQ Squid
What are you looking at?
Buy it! Quick!
Keep quiet, will you?
Kitties aren't supposed to eat squid.
Idiot, I'm not a kitty!
Are you gonna deprive a middle-age cat of his love for squid?
Don't say things that totally make me feel like dropping you.
Jeez... Chew your food first, Sensei.
The most tasty part is without a doubt the tentacles.
Wait, squid!
Squid, wait!
You are the star of my middle-age!
What star?
Oh my, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Blood!
She's gone.
Was that a youkai?
[ Note: Parasol is a waxed paper umbrella, for shielding the sun and the rain. ]
Her parasol...
That Which is Not Human
What is this?
Are you all right?
What are you doing?
Run!
Thank you for saving me.
Same to you. I came out of it because of you.
You helped me, I helped you.
This is so embarrassing, having a woman carry me like this...
No, she's a youkai, strictly speaking...
You're really quite heavy.
And it's odd, your body's so warm.
Perhaps, a human?!
You didn't know?
Natsume?
I've got you! I've got you!
I'm sorry.
I wasn't expecting a human, you caught me by surprise.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I fortunately landed on a very soft cushion.
Listen, Natsume! I'm not a cushion!
Natsume?
Are you perhaps, the one with the Book of Friends...
I was expecting someone more awesome...
Bow before me and give me your name!
Wrong, that was my grandmother.
I see.
But no matter how frail you look, Natsume is still Natsume.
Natsume-sama, I have a request.
Will you lend us your strength?
Recently, youkai here have been gravely injured and had their blood drawn in random attacks.
So to find out who the attacker was, I went into the forest to investigate...
For my friends, I wanted to know who or what he really is.
If you can help us...
Idiot, stop your nonsense!
We've no reason to help her, Natsume!
Somebody who draws blood from his victims...
Say I get involved, what if I implicate Touko-san and everyone...
What should I do...
Natsume-sama, I didn't mean to trouble you.
In truth, you have every right not to get involved.
I'm sorry.
Just forget it.
Wait. How are your friends doing now?
After the attack, are they okay now?
My friends are like family to me.
I must protect the few I have left.
Farewell.
Sensei...
Didn't you decide not to get involved?
To help or not to help, you looked just as gloomy either way.
That's so different from Reiko, who's always playing a fool.
That's right.
Takashi-kun, it's about time for dinner.
Yeah! Coming right away.
Now that it's decided, although this is not gonna keep you from sulking,
you made the right decision on this.
She said that the blood of the youkai were taken, right?
That means the culprit might not be a youkai.
I've heard of humans who use youkai's blood in their spells.
Humans?
When I scratched him, it certainly didn't feel like a youkai...
What's more important to you, humans or youkai?
You decide.
But...
Hey, Natsume!
You idiot, stop this!
Didn't you finally made the right decision not to get involved?
Sorry, that's how I'm like.
Give it up.
To think that a human is possibly killing and taking the blood from youkai,
I just couldn't turn a blind eye.
Thank you, master Natsume.
I didn't know it would be so hot.
I wondered off from the river.
You've to be careful!
If I hadn't pass by, you'd be toasted.
Anyway, back to what we were talking about...
I've seen a youkai's blood being taken.
Really?
A tremendously huge shadow attacked the youkai.
Another guy, in a kimono just watched on.
A guy in a kimono?
Could he be a human?
I didn't see his face. But yes, possibly.
There's no doubt...
It's a human that's attacking the youkai.
Why would anyone do that?
Sensei, that person has a scar on his arm.
Coincidence?
That's where I scratched him yesterday.
Sensei?
Who the hell is he?
I sense something really bad.
I'm going after him!
Wait, Natsume!
Stop it!
You're so much trouble!
Scram!
You can see youkai, can't you?
And you have something very interesting with you.
What are you?
My apologies.
My name is Matoba Seiji.
Matoba...
It's the Matoba Exorcists.
They use youkai as bait to exterminate other youkai.
And they will use all sorts of despicable techniques.
Back then... the Matoba clan!
He is one of them?
Natsume
Yuujinchou
He's one of the Matoba.
You're that guy that came to our temple that time.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were one of those remaining youkai.
What's your name?
It isn't a good idea to tell him.
Are you taking the youkai's blood?
How much do you know?
Chat with me for a little.
Are you okay?
Just throw away that sandbag-like thing.
What did you say?
Who are you calling a sandbag?!
Hey, you! Where are we going?
A paper doll?
This is...
She must be hurt badly.
I must let her rest for a while.
Leave, servants of Matoba.
He is a friend of Natori.
You're forbidden to touch him.
Natori-san?
Go back and tell this to your master!
Thank you, Hiiragi.
Although she is quite badly wounded, give her a good rest and she will recover very quickly.
Anyway, I'm glad we're all fine.
You idiot!
It's all your fault and your paper dolls!
How many times do you think I've been squashed lately?!
But, why are you here?
I got news that Matoba was here,
As an exorcist myself, I was curious what he was up to.
It seems like he is collecting youkai's blood.
For some kind of spell.
I see...
And that's why you couldn't leave it as it is.
You're still the same, Natsume.
Yes.
But, that is definitely a reason for concern.
Why don't we investigate a little?
Are you sure?
You're always helping me.
This time, let me help you.
Natori-san...
For free?
You'll do it for free, right?
Yeah...
That's great!
And so, Hiiragi took care of the winged-youkai.
Natori-san and I went out to investigate.
But, Matoba-san is quite young.
When you said that he's the leader,
I was expecting someone older and wiser.
Youkai are my boys.
Screw with me and you'll end up at the bottom of the river.
Though he is young, he looked ridiculous with his eyepatch, long hair, and parasol.
I'm sure he has his reasons.
Long hair means you can negociate it easily when you're making a contract with a youkai.
Same with an eyepatch... I'm sure there's a reason.
I'll find that out by tomorrow. For now, let's just call it a day.
Okay.
Let's go, Sensei.
It's not often I see the young Natori sighing.
Nanase-san?
What do you want?
Nothing much. I heard about your mistake.
You stole a job from us. That was uncharacteristic of you.
I didn't make any mistake.
I sealed the gateway where the youkai were appearing from.
And I chased away the youkai that remained.
Chased away?
You've gone soft.
I'm not as powerful as those from the Matoba clan.
There is only so much I can do.
Even your sarcasm is weak.
It's like you're trying to hide something.
You're the same as ever, Nanase-san.
What's there to hide from the great Matoba family.
Is that so?
Are you telling me you stole that job not because you wanted to keep us away from that town?
Why would I do that?
Yeah.
I have a photo shoot.
I've got to go.
Natsume Reiko's grandson is there, right?
I haven't met him in a while.
Where does he live?
That's private, isn't it?
Natori.
Our chief is currently on a job in that town.
Don't interfere.
Our boss is very short-tempered.
Lately, I have become so comfortable with them, I'm relying too much on them.
I didn't tell him about the Book of Friends, yet he helped me...
I really need to thank Natori-san.
I'll eat you!
A dream?
What's that?
Sensei?
This shred of paper, from the paper-mask youkai I destroyed. Apparently it was stuck on your clothes.
It may be a youkai, but it's a man-made one.
Man-made?
This puppet they control has a face made of paper that absorbs spiritual energy to form the body.
This here, probably absorbed some of our energy.
Mine especially is of the highest level.
It's a man-made youkai...
Is that why I felt the ill-intent from it?
Where's Natori-san?
He hasn't come back since last night.
He's been up all night?
Why would he go to such an extent for the youkai.
You're helping youkai too.
But Natori-san is...
He probably thinks he's responsible for the recent events.
Events?
What Matoba-san's been doing?
That's right.
Natsume, now's your chance to back out.
I can protect you from youkai, but it's different with humans.
Especially that Matoba fella, he's no good.
Sensei...
I'm back...
Oh, you're back.
Natori-san.
You didn't catch any sleep, right?
Better rest for a bit.
That was nothing.
Lack of sleep isn't gonna make me smile less radiantly.
Don't worry.
You're acting out right now, just like someone deprived of sleep!
Really?
He looks fine to me.
Judging from the locations where those incidents happened,
it seems like they're gradually moving eastward.
And this is where it all started.
I didn't know there was a village here.
Let's ask around for a bit.
It's really Natori-san!
We are your avid fans!
All right, thanks.
Over there!
Hurry up, slowpokes!
[ Sign: Maihane Udon ]
Udon, here I come.
Three plain udons.
Yes...
By the way, any unusual news from around here?
Unusual news like...
Like places where monsters were appearing...
or strange people you've never seen before loitering around?
Strange people...
Besides him, of course.
Well, there is this guy with long hair and an eyepatch staying at the inn.
Thank you.
That was fast.
I guess the cat is useful once in a while.
What do you mean "once in a while"?
But it's too easy.
Like a trap, isn't it?
Yeah.
But, it just feels...
Nevermind, let's check it out first.
Yato
Inn
Yes, we have a guest here that fits your description.
Who are you?
We're searching for our brother, who's run away from home.
So, please don't tell him we're here.
I see...
Oh, wait a second.
Yes, hello?
Yes.
A landslide?
In the end, Natori-san and I didn't go back because the roads were blocked.
Yes, we'll be staying here just for the night.
Yes.
I'm fine.
I'll be back tomorrow.
We stayed at the small inn where Matoba-san is very likely to be staying as well.
Natori-san is taking too long.
Matoba might have caught him already.
I can sense bad energy gathering here.
Where are you going?
This is Matoba we're talking about!
Your wimpy punch is useless against him!
But...
I'll go instead.
So before I return, don't open the door for anybody.
Understood.
Sensei, be careful.
What's wrong with this door?
I'm the one that's of no help, after all...
What was that just now?
A youkai?
Something came in!
What's your motive?
I'm sick and tired that you're always nearby.
If you ever get in our way again,
for Matoba sake, I'll take your blood for the ritual too!
Matoba-san...
Ritual?
Come with me.
You have strong spiritual energy.
I've no idea who the hell you are...
but to youkai who have only tasted inferior blood...
yours must be delicious.
Delicious?
What is she up to?
Storage
Room
Come, too bad for you, give me your blood.
Stop it!
She said she wanted blood with strong spiritual energy.
Sensei and Natori-san might be in danger!
We keep running into each other...
Your cat isn't with you today?
Get him.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Exorcist
This is bad, Natsume's gone!
I'm bleeding now! What are you going to do about it?
You have the nerve to say that when all you ever do is sit on people.
What?
You want me to attack you from up here?
Sorry to intrude. I borrowed Natsume for a short while.
Damn!