Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Midterm Exams
Final Day: English Grammar
Hey, Natsume, Ishimura.
What's with you, the exam is over, it's our time now!
Let's go somewhere.
Yeah, fishing maybe?
I like that.
What about you, Natsume?
Where do you want to go?
Let me see...
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
Count me in as well.
Sasada...
I've something great for you.
What's this?
My dad got these from his friends.
Let's all go together.
An art museum...
What's wrong?
Whoa, it's quite far away.
It doesn't matter, now that the exam is over.
It's summer again.
Young Days
I'm back.
Welcome home, Takashi-kun.
Ah, see this, it's for a class reunion.
Elementary school reunion.
Yours?
It was nostalgia.
But, I'm so old now!
Ah, I guess it's the same for everybody!
I miss being a kid.
Honestly, there's a little something that's been bugging me.
Will you hear me out, Takashi-kun?
Yes.
At that time, a bunch of us, good friends exchanged presents.
We all agreed that we would exchange something we made ourselves.
We were all so excited.
We gathered together, we sang together.
I received Kuriyama-san's handmade cookies.
And Kuriyama-san coincidentally got the pressed flower cards I made.
But she looked so disappointed, and said:
"I don't want this!"
"Touko-chan is insincere!"
"Give me back my cookies!"
I was so ashamed of myself.
If only I had said "I'm sorry"...
I'm sure nobody remembers about that incident.
But I...
Kuriyama-san moved away soon after.
I've always wanted to see her again...
Not to talk about what happened then,
but to see that she is still as happy as before.
Then, I'm sure I wouldn't be bothered by that incident.
I was kinda envious.
I don't have a childhood that I can reminisce on.
What the hell!
What's there to do in an art museum?
I didn't ask you to come.
[ Ramen: Japanese noodle. ]
Come to think of it, Sasada said something about a really good ramen place nearby.
Ramen?
Ramen. Ramen. Ramen...
You better not sneak into my bag again.
I'm going!
You said you weren't!
I'm going, I'm going, I'm going!
I'm not taking you.
Ra-ramen...
I'm going.
Stay here and watch the house!
I don't want to stay home!
I'm going!
That's my life now... nosier, livelier days...
Ramen!
I'm going!
It's so quiet...
Is it summer again?
I can hold my breath for ten minutes!
That's useless!
It's not useless!
It doesn't really matter if it's summer or not...
Do you know how much trouble it took me?
Can't even see me... they're really a bunch of stupid idiots.
Humans just breeze by, just like the seasons.
Was that a summer, too?
That person...
He who could see me.
The green is really pretty.
It sure is.
Here.
You'll get in trouble for this.
It's fine.
Nobody's watching.
What do you want the branch for?
I just feel like taking it.
You suck.
Such arrogance! Such rudeness!
Can't even sense my noble presence here...
Retarded inferior creatures!
Assholes! Scum bags!
What a crappy day.
Isn't there anything that would go my way?
Hey, the liar's coming.
You're right. He's a liar!
Get too close to him, you'll become a liar too!
It's contagious, contagious!
Get lost!
Shoo-shoo!
Already bullying their own kind at such a young age...
That's so ugly.
Get lost!
What?
I didn't do anything!
That rock probably fell from the sky.
That's the kind of lies you say, right?
Right?
Stupid kids.
Right, Natsume?
Come on, say something!
What's that?
Hairy, hairy, worms!
That was fun, that was fun!
Just now, he looked right at me...
No, nobody can see me.
It's impossible that there is a human who can see youkai!
It's impossible that there is a human who can see me...
You really can...
What an ill-mannered kid!
I won't let you off!
Since then, I followed him everyday.
I ambushed him.
I tried my best to scare him.
Wait, wait!
And he would run off.
Although it was just that...
it was kind of fun.
Now now, where's that kid today?
Hey, he's a transferred student, isn't he?
Yeah, I heard he's weird.
His lies are out of this world.
Lies?
He says he can see youkai, just to get attention.
He's an orphan, nobody wants him, that's why he keeps transferring.
That's why he's always by himself.
He's always alone...
Just because he can see us?
Mom!
Careful!
I made daddy something today!
Wow.
I startled you, I startled you, didn't I?
Why?
This is the first time he speaks to me.
Why are you sticking to me?
Are you that free?
Free?
Don't be stupid!
We just happen to take the same path.
I have lots and lots of things to do!
I'm not sticking to you!
I see.
Okay...
What's up with him?
Insolent kid!
Scum bag!
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Look at that! It's beautiful!
I used to live around here.
What's wrong, Natsume? You're spacing out.
What, are you hungry too?
No, I'm good.
Because I moved frequently from one relative to another,
I was hardly conscious of where I've been.
That was...
I'm back.
We're the ones in a bad spot.
Whatever it is, you'll be taking care of the kid from next week onwards.
That was the deal!
Jeez...
Why...
You're back.
That... well...
As arranged, you'll be staying at my brother's place starting next week.
You see... My kid is taking his exams this year...
And... Ahh, yes...
You can have this coat.
It just a little big, but it's okay, right?
Here.
Don't think badly of us...
for, you know, all these.
It smells kind of dusty.
He finally spoke to me for the first time...
I never intended to say any of that...
This is upsetting!
Why do I have to care what a human kid feels?
I'll just scare him again tomorrow.
That's right.
If I scare him, I might get him to talk to me again.
Where'd you get that coat from?
He's here! He's here!
My uncle gave it to me.
I see.
Okay... now!
Oww...
I'm sorry.
I'm all drenched!
How are you gonna makeup to me?
Oh, no! I went too far.
I'm sorry!
I was only...
Get lost.
Get lost!
What did I do?
Why do I have to...
I hate all of you!
From the next day on, he never came down that path again.
He would rather take the longer route to school.
My words will never reach him now.
And he will never see me again.
But still...
[ しかどめ幸福地蔵菩薩: The Shikadome Happiness Buddha ]
He's all by himself again today.
Oh, it's a kitty.
Come here.
You have a sweet smell.
He looked so kind...
It's so cozy...
I wish I could stay with him just like this forever...
How I wish to be you.
How I wish to be left alone.
How I wish to live by myself.
I'm a youkai, I don't understand humans.
But it's sad to be alone.
That, I know.
That, I understand.
A few days later, he was taken to a place far away.
Okay, let's hurry and get going.
Who's that woman?
Her lips and nails are all bright red.
And that man, his eyes are never still.
Okay, we will be leaving then.
We have kids of your age at home.
Relax, you'll get used to it in no time.
Right, Mom?
That's right.
And after that, I never saw him again.
So what if I'm alone?
It's much better to be alone.
Why do humans argue more the closer they get?
What pretty flowers.
Where?
Huh?
Anything wrong?
I don't know... something touched my hand.
No... that's scary!
Enough is enough.
Look who's talking?
How much longer are you gonna burden me with your mother?
Come on, don't say that.
What?
I'm sick of this.
Sick of this...
What an ugly, unreasonable face.
Bad, bad, detestable humans.
It's your mother, you take care of her.
I wish they'd all just disappear.
I hate them!
I resent them!
Those selfish, ugly humans...
Make them all disappear!
I heard you shouldn't step under that tree.
I'm not sure why,
but there is something scary about it.
Wait!
Oww...
Shut up.
Oww!
A cat!
I hate cats!
Go away!
Nothing matters anymore.
Nothing affects me anymore.
Time has stopped for me.
I wonder how he's doing?
That kid with the kind smile and a poignant wish...
Is he finally smiling now?
I'm glad.
You're still here.
I don't know how many seasons it's been...
but I've never forgotten...
I've always remembered...
It's been bothering me...
How it ended with us.
I'm glad you're doing well.
Back then, I vent my frustrations on other people.
But now, I think I can understand your kindness.
He must have met with some kind people,
people who can give him a smile like that.
Ahh, what a familiar smell.
I am Natsume Takashi.
Would you tell me your name?
Welcome back!
I'm back.
I'm back, too.
Welcome back.
So, you've seen her?
Yeah, what about you?
Did you have fun?
Yes.
I'm glad.
I have one, too...
What? All of a sudden? Going somewhere?
Umm, there's someone I wish to see.
An old friend.
Although I don't know if I can find her.
Go.
We'll head home.
That's right.
See you.
Bye!
Hey, hey!
Have a good time!
Bye!
Now, I understand...
If there's someone you wish to see,
then you're no longer alone.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
The Thing Lurking in the Storeroom
There are youkai who knew my grandpa here in this house?
Yeah, they all gathered here because they knew your grandpa.
Although grandpa was never able to see them up till the end...
There are also those who can see them, but didn't want to.