Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
7th Street Shop
Look at that, Sensei.
Yatsuhara looks like a sea of light.
Nothing great about that.
Let's just hurry home, and you let me have my dango, Natsume!
You do nothing but eat, Sensei.
What's that?
I like it!
It smells great!
Love this scent!
Ghost Kill
The big white pig is attacking!
What did you say? I'll eat you!
Stop it, Sensei.
Oh, it's Natsume-sama and the Pig Cat...
Pig cat, pig cat...
I mean, Madara-sama.
Oh, did you bring us snacks?
Thank you...
Not for you!
If you keep making this much noise,
be careful the monk will purify you again.
We haven't heard any chanting from that temple recently.
I wonder if the monk died?
He died, he died...
Did something happen to Tanuma's dad?
Ukihara Village
Tanuma is a dear friend, one of the few people
who knows I can see youkai.
Hey, Natsume, Nishimura.
Gym Class next?
Yeah.
Marathon.
Oh, Tanuma.
No, it's nothing.
See you later.
Yeah, see you.
He is also able to sense youkai's presence,
but he can only vaguely see them.
And so you left without asking him anything?
I didn't know how to ask him.
Why?
Didn't he know you can see youkai?
If his dad is ill, or something bad happened...
I don't think it's appropriate to talk about it with other people around.
And why is that?
Well...
It's my friend's family matters.
How deep should I probe and not be intrusive?
Why would I know!
Yeah, you're right.
When I was young,
I never had any friends with whom I can talk about my parents.
That's why I don't know how to get close with people.
I'm back.
Oh yeah, nobody's home.
My name...
Natsume-sama, of the Book of Friends.
You want your name back?
Sorry, I'm heading to school.
Can we do it later?
Tanuma!
What, it's about my dad?
It's because I've heard that the sutras chanting had stopped.
He's gone to the main temple to help out with a ceremony.
He won't be home for about a month.
It's like a business trip.
Happens from time to time.
I see. I'm glad to hear that.
You were worried for me?
Thanks.
Err, it's nothing.
So, you're living alone now?
That must be tough.
Not really.
It's nice and quiet.
Did something happen?
No, it's nothing.
Okay, here's where we part.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah.
It you...
Return my name...
I guess it'll be okay here.
That which shields me, reveal thy name.
Natsume!
What are you doing standing there?
I don't have her name...
A youkai?
You were giving back another name behind my back?
Yeah...
You fool!
If you keep returning their names willy-nilly,
by the time I lay my hands on the Book of Friends, it'd be empty!
[ Gyuudon: A dish of rice with beef. ]
Oh, the gyuudon blues!
Why did it turn out this way...
The priest is finally away, and here comes other scary fella?
When will peace come to Yatsuhara?
It's the white pig again!
It's Madara-sama.
What's with all the ruckus?
Well, you see, he seems to have revived.
Who?
You remember, that one youkai who came
[ Miasma: Bad air. ]
and started spreading a miasma everywhere?
Yes, yes...
Yeah, I guess I do, kind of.
Weak youkai fell sick when they come into contact.
It's giving everyone's a headache.
A headache, a headache...
It's rumored that he was defeated by Natsume Reiko, and his name taken.
Then he went to the mountain and got into a deep slumber.
Reiko?
That girl's always so cruel.
His miasma is spreading again.
Actually, you see, he's...
I'm sorry about yesterday,
Natsume-sama of the Book of Friends.
Is your name not in the Book of Friends?
Yes.
It wasn't my name that was in the book.
I was my brother's.
Brother?
[ Ukihara: Floating spring. ]
My brother is from the village of Ukihara.
The village of Ukihara...
The village of Ukihara
is the dream-like village that humans can't see, isn't it?
Why would anyone there want to come here?
Don't know.
It's said that he's been moving about all these years trying to find a way back.
The Ukihara village
is a place where flowers blossom all year round,
where the birds never cease chirping.
It doesn't normally interact with the outside world.
But occasionally, during big festivals, it connects to the outside world.
Drawn by the music and dance, my brother and I set foot into this world unknowingly.
My brother and I have been searching for an entrance back to the Ukihara village.
For years, and years...
Eventually my brother fell sick,
and started to give off a miasma.
I too, grew weak from the miasma.
Seeing this, my brother placed me in a hole of a holy tree,
and he went off on his own.
Soon after, with the help of the spiritual energy from the holy tree, I regained my health.
And I arrived here following the rumors of my brother.
But according to the youkai here,
ever since my brother's name was taken by Natsuma-same,
no one ever saw him again.
So that's why you came to me, because I have the Book of Friends.
But it wasn't me who took your brother's name, it was my grandmother.
I haven't seen him before...
so I can't call out to him.
I see.
Then, since I know his face, he should respond to my call, right?
I guess so.
Then...
Give me the Book of Friends!
Stop!
Natsume-dono.
Misuzu!
I felt the presence of a youkai here just now.
You saved me.
I just happened to come by.
Several lowly-ranked youkai have been devour at the riverside.
I was trying to find the culprit.
Oh hey, it's Misuzu!
Madara, it's not you, is it?
The one who's been eating the lowly-ranked youkai in my territory.
What?
Don't throw wild accusations at me, I'll get you!
Moreover, I'm a gourmet.
I wouldn't just go around eating wimps!
Could it be...
So, the youkai who is hiding in the mountain is...
Probably the brother of the youkai you met.
The place where he was spotted was near Tanuma's house, isn't it?
He's loitering in that area probably because the monk isn't around.
Tanuma...
Where? Where are you?
I will take you there... Natsume....
Natsume?
Hey!
What are you looking for?
If you do anything to Natsume, I'll make sure you regret it!
Rust?
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Map of the Yatsuhara Temple
An old map of the temple?
Tanuma went home early?
Yeah, he was here this morning,
but left early saying he has a bad headache.
A headache...
Don't tell me...
He must've been affected by that youkai's miasma.
What a weakling.
I'm worried about him. We better hurry.
Roger!
He's not home? Is he hospitalized?
Natsume, I'm picking up a youkai's scent.
This is...
Huh, this is the map of the temple?
This is what you see now, but in the past, the temple was much bigger.
[ Kagura: Japanese theatrical dance to appease the gods ]
Every year, the Kagura is held within the temple grounds.
Kagura?
The Kagura would sometimes open the door to the other world.
I see, the Kagara was held here.
That's located at the end of Yatsuhara.
Huh, Tanuma?
What's the matter?
Err... a brief...
Your dad isn't at home now, right?
It sucks when you're sick and all alone, right?
Sorry for the trouble, I didn't feel like staying at home.
Don't worry about it.
Natsume was pretty worried too when he heard that you were sick.
This way, right?
Hey, Nyanko-sensei?
Hey!
He's been hit by the miasma.
Just let him sleep by the side, he'd be fine.
Sensei, how are you holding up?
Don't treat me like I'm one of these wimps!
Let's hurry.
I've a bad feeling about this.
He's close, Natsume.
Yeah.
Wait!
Natsume?
Natsume... Reiko?
Reiko?
No, I'm...
I see.
Reiko is gone.
I know my blood's affecting the youkai around me.
It's regrettable.
But the entrance to Ukihara village
will only response to the blood of it's people.
That's why you hurt yourself...
But, there's no need to do this anymore.
And why is that?
Are you giving up already?
A youkai claiming to be your sister is looking for you.
No, that's impossible.
My sister died ages ago.
It's my fault.
I was drawn by the Kagura, and took her with me.
She couldn't get used to live here, and died soon after.
After then on, I wandered alone.
When I was just about to give up on returning to my village,
I met Reiko.
That's when she kicked your ass hard.
It was a meaningless battle.
I lost, and gave her my name.
But Reiko... She finally passed on, but still, she didn't summon me.
I retreated back to the mountain, found a cave, and slept there.
Before I knew it, a long time had passed.
When I awoke, the old abandoned temple had been rebuilt.
Tanuma and his father moved in.
Although I can't get close to it,
these few days I haven't sensed the monk's presence,
so I went in to take a look.
And there you found that old map?
I came here because rumors had it that the door once opened here.
This was probably the site where the Kagura was held.
The place must have been burnt down.
If the building was still here, it might work, but as it is...
But what about that female youkai?
I'm afraid that would be Sagume, a youkai banished from the Ukihara village.
She probably thinks that by following me, she may one day return to the village.
I see.
So that's why she was eyeing on the Book of Friends.
She was going to use you to open the door to the village.
Sagume was probably also the one Misuzu said was devouring the lowly-ranked youkai.
In that case,
we should return your name before she comes for the Book of Friends again.
For Reiko-san.
That which shields me, reveal thy name.
I return this to you, Kanawa.
Please take it.
Banished simply for breaking a flower stem? Unfair!
The blood from a criminal will not open the door.
I hate them.
I have no need for the Book of Friends, kid.
Because I already got his blood.
The trees that grew on the remains of the building are responding to his blood!
The door is about to open.
I can finally return home.
I wanted Reiko to see this scene.
His body is rusted.
What a bother.
Are you not going to say "Hello" to the person who was here before you?
You can see me?
The other youkai were talking about you.
Aren't you scared of me?
I'm strong.
What a fantastic village you came from.
Yes, it's a very beautiful place.
But you've given up?
On going home?
With my body like this,
Even if I managed to return, I wouldn't last long.
Now I merely wander around, looking for a resting place.
Hey, you want to have a match with me?
[
Scissors-Paper-Stone,
石头-剪刀-布,
じゃん-けん-ぽん
]
Rock, Paper, Scissors!
That hurt.
Great, I won.
Now you're my subordinate.
Come, write your name here.
Listen. If you find it, you have to inform me, okay?
The entrance to your village.
I want to see it too.
If there's really such a beautiful world.
Then will you come with me?
If you dislike the humans so much, then come with me to the village of Ukihara.
Why don't you come with me, Natsume, Reiko's grandson?
No. For me, this place is important, Kanawa.
I see.
You seem to have good human friends, too.
Natsume!
Tanuma? Where have you been?
I heard you collapsed. I was worried.
Sorry. Actually, I have some weird youkai in my house.
He's gone now.
Ponta got rid of it?
No, he went back home.
He wasn't dangerous?
He wasn't a bad youkai.
I see. I'm glad.
I wasn't sure if I should had discuss it with you.
I was afraid to drag you into this.
It would be better if I had told you earlier.
Tanuma...
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
False Friend
We all have secrets we don't want others to know about.
You're Natsume, right?
The one who lied about seeing youkai.
How did you know...
What an arrogant kid.
Eat him...
I remembered about you after I met her.