Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
The sky's so clear today.
[ Note: Tamagoyaki are made by rolling a few layers of eggs together, then cut into pieces. Usually sweet tasting. ]
Natsume... I'm taking the tamagoyaki!
Give it back, that's my protein intake!
Come on! Don't you find me pitiful, all I have is the melon bread?
Jeez...
No matter when I look at it, you can always tell that it's made with love.
^
Tamagoyaki
Say, how many times have you changed schools?
It must have been tough, but it's not showing on you.
Nishimura!
I would probably have turned into a weirdo.
Don't laugh! I'm serious.
Sorry, sorry.
You have a point.
In the past, I was worried that no one would take me in if they'd felt that I was a weirdo.
But nobody likes someone who's always too timid to talk either.
I understand now...
When having meals with them, don't be afraid to tell them honestly and directly that "it tastes great".
I'm back.
Welcome home, Takashi-kun.
Have you eaten?
Yes, it was good.
You didn't eat the parsley.
But parsley's for...
No... Come on, eat it, eat it.
All right.
A Place to Go Home To
Nyanko-sensei, Touko-san made this pudding.
He's out drinking again?
I'll just enjoy it myself.
I've found you.
Is she here for her name?
I've found you, Natsume.
What?
I've found you.
You're not getting away this time, Natsume.
I'm back.
Who are you?!
Hands off him!
Sure is fast at running away...
What's wrong Natsume? Natsume!
Get some rest tonight.
We'll see a doctor first thing tomorrow morning.
I'm going out to the supermarket pharmacy now.
It won't take long.
Kitty, look after Takashi-kun.
Jeez, you're such a pain!
How can you let that kind of youkai affect you?
Sensei?
Touko-san?
Shigeru-san?
Nyanko-sensei!
What are you looking for?
There's no one left in this house, Natsume.
I've eaten them all.
Don't move about like that, idiot.
Jeez...
Sensei...
Keep still!
I remembered that youkai.
You met her before?
Yes, that was before I met you...
I didn't know much about youkai back then...
Not that I am any expert now...
Damn, I don't want to fall asleep...
I'm going to have another dream...
Stop there, kid.
How can a human like you see me?
I'm going to eat you.
What should I do?
I can't go home like this.
Up here!
He can't see things that are higher up.
Where is he?
Where did he go?
You see us, yet you know nothing about us...
You saved me?
Not exactly.
I just wanted to see him unhappy.
Youkai are indeed evil...
Oh yeah, what's your name?
Forget it...
Anyway, you saved me.
Thank you.
I'm back.
Sorry I'm late...
Out buying groceries.
Watch the house.
She left the window open.
Hey, what are you doing?
You're not allowed in here!
Hey!
Keep still!
We're back.
Takashi-kun, sorry about this...
I went to pick–
Get out!
What's that Mom? Anything wrong?
Takashi-kun?
What's wrong?
Umm... It's nothing... I'm sorry.
He messed up the room?
Yeah. I know he's not a bad boy.
But this is all kind of scary.
He's such a small youkai, I should have just ignored him.
It's not like people can see him.
I heard that his parents had passed away, that's why he's a bit unstable.
But it's still kind of disturbing, isn't it -- when he screams out like that?
Nobody understands me...
Nobody...
I never learn...
I'm such an idiot.
It's so cold.
Natsume-kun?
Are you Natsume Takashi-kun?
Umm...
Sorry about this...
I heard that you live nearby, so I came over to see you.
How rude of me, I'm just so happy to see you.
My name is Fujiwara Touko.
I'm a distant relative of your father.
Where are you going?
Just taking a walk.
You shouldn't. It isn't safe to be out this late.
Go home.
Or is it because you don't want to?
No, it's nothing like that.
I see.
Okay, go home before you catch a cold.
See you.
I can sense the warmth in her voice...
But, is she really a human?
What if I'm the only one who could see her.
We meet again.
This is only the second time.
You're right...
You are?
I am Natsume.
Stupid fool.
You're inviting trouble when you give your name so easily to a youkai.
You're lonely, Natsume.
I like people who're lonely.
It's interesting to watch them.
Do you know how I can stop seeing youkai?
No, I don't.
I see. Okay.
See you.
Natsume
Yuujinchou
It was really fun!
Natsume-kun.
Fujiwara-san...
I apologize for being rather assertive the last time.
After some deliberations, I think it's best you know about what we have in mind.
If it's fine with you, would you like to come and live with us?
We live way out in the countryside.
It's just my husband, Shigeru-san, and myself.
Though it's an old house, it's spacious.
We don't have kids, so it's a little too big for us.
It's only recently that we learned about you...
We won't force you, of course...
You can decide for yourself.
But if you decide to come, I'm sure our house would be a lot more livelier.
Shigeru-san and I will pay you a visit soon.
In the meantime, think about it. Okay?
Should I go or not...
She said she wanted me there...
Thus far, nobody has taken me in willingly...
Think about it? That's a first...
But that's because they don't know me.
I don't want to see them disappointed or scared.
Natsume.
I've come to get you.
I'll stay by your side.
I told you, right? I like people like you.
A sorrowful heart is a delight to me.
It occurred to me that keeping a human as a pet might be fun.
What are you talking about?
Come over here, Natsume.
You're lonely, right?
Stop it!
I was careless. I shouldn't have talked to youkai...
She didn't follow me home, did she?
I can't go anywhere if this keeps up.
Your scarf, wear your scarf!
I'm good, Mom.
Just wear it. You don't want to catch a cold, right?
Alright then, get one for Takashi-kun too.
I'm off.
But...
Good, she's not here.
I should get rid of her before she finds out where I live. But how?
It's done.
Looks like it's going to rain tomorrow.
That cloud–
Hello!
Well, it's a scrawny fella we've never seen before.
The humans chased me here.
That's bad.
They're weak, but bold.
What did those puny humans use to drive away youkai?
How would I know?
Come to think of it, up ahead near the Fox Boulder...
... there's a hole that a monk had worked halfway on for sealing away youkai.
There are still many who find it interesting...
You have a human scent on you.
It is indeed a human-child.
How dare you tricked us?!
Natsume-kun?
Natsume.
I've got rid of those weaklings.
What were you trying to do, Natsume?
You really are interesting.
I've been observing you.
This is bad! She knows about where I live!
Come, Natsume.
Come with me.
You don't fit-in with the humans, right?
They drink and take it out on you.
They "forget" to give you food.
Even kids, they always bully you.
She has seen right though my heart!
Not true! They were good to me at the beginning!
No, they've always been good people.
It's me...
Good people?
That's strange.
Why did they dislike you then?
Shut up!
Who in the right mind would invite a weirdo into their lives!
Come along with me then.
Nobody's waiting for you to return, right?
You don't understand...
It is no trivial matter when a human child goes missing.
It will trouble them more...
What a pain.
Okay then, I can just eat them all up.
No!
Please, don't!
Please...
I'll let you go back to them today.
Bid them a proper farewell and then come back here.
Nobody's waiting for me...
Takashi-kun?
What are you doing here?
No reason...
Your hair's all messed up.
Oh...
I apologize for my parents.
They can be insensitive at times.
No...
Let's go back together.
Okay.
I have to think...
How do I leave quietly without hurting them? How...
Don't you find it odd?
A distant relative appearing out of the blue?
Distant relative?
Who knows what they'd say about us.
I think it's great.
To be honest, it's easier on me.
Didn't you say so yourself?
We're back.
Oh, welcome home.
Welcome home.
We had guests?
Yeah... I'll go get dinner ready.
They came...
Fujiwara-san...
She really came for me.
I want to go. I want to go with them.
I'm going. I'm not gonna run off.
I must also thank this family whose been caring for me.
Someone, someone please tell me!
What? A human child?
He's so noisy.
Arrogant brat. Let's make fun of him.
Hey, kid.
Tell me, where is the Fox Boulder?
How can I use the hole to seal youkai?
What's with this kid?
He's a human, but he's not afraid of us.
Run for it!
I'm pleading you!
I'm scared, but I'm determined to go.
Natsume, Natsume, come out here.
Natsume, come out here.
Come out now, Natsume!
You think a child like you can seal away a youkai?
I showed a little kindness and you're pushing your luck.
I'll teach you a lesson or two!
Curse... curse you...
I did it!
One week in the hospital, they say...
Why did he run into the mountains by himself?
Did he do that on purpose?
Mother...
I caused trouble for them again...
I can't go back there now, can I?
Look, he's asleep.
Keep your voice down, you'll wake him.
You're right.
Fujiwara-san?
See? You woke him up.
Shigeru-san, you were talking too...
Well...
Takashi-kun...
If you don't like it with us, you can leave at anytime.
But for now, you need a quiet place to rest your mind.
Our place is as quiet as it gets.
Come stay with us.
You shouldn't exert yourself!
I want to give it a try...
I want to stay with the both of you.
Can I?
Can I...
Get out of the way.
He's mine.
That's too bad. He's mine now.
Just give up and go home.
There isn't anything in him that would interest you now.
Then I'll give him sadness once more.
I will not be disrespected!
He has to pay!
The seal must have been broken by construction work or something...
I've got rid of that stupid youkai who was sealed away by a small kid.
Go back to sleep...
We don't want Touko to nag, right?
Thank you, Nyanko-sensei.
Are you going back? Nobody's waiting for you.
No, I have a home now.
I'm so glad you're well now.
Aren't you running late?
Oh my, Takashi-kun, don't forget your lunch-box!
Be careful.
Remember to eat it all. Bye.
Yeah!
I'm off!
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Natsume's Book of Play
We're holding a banquet for Natsume-sama today.
Wait, I'm still a minor!
Let's have some fun! Let's go, Natsume!
How about making fun of human kids?
We're the Natsume Gang! Again!
Woof, woof!
What is all of this?