Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Cake?
Yes, it's Shigeru-san's birthday today.
Takashi-kun, could you get it on the way home?
What kind of cake?
Let's see...
For birthday celebration, strawberry shortcakes should be a good choice.
Three slices.
Okay.
Buy four!
Cats aren't suppose to have a sweet diet.
I'm not a cat!
[ Maneki-Neko: Fortune cat. ]
I'm a Maneki-Neko who loves sweet stuff!
This is my quiet, yet lively routine...
False Friend
The patisserie learned his skills in France, it's really tasty.
There.
River
Supermarket
Cute
Forrest
Cute Forrest?
That's one heck of a name.
Hey, isn't it near Kitamoto's home.
Cute
Forrest
Is this the place?
It's just like what it's name suggests.
Didn't I say that it'd be awkward for a guy to go in there.
I can't do it.
It's too hard for me.
I didn't expect that coming from a person who prance around with his cat all day.
Go!
You want to give Shigeru-san a nice birthday cake, right?
You're right.
Okay.
Natsume.
You're Natsume Takashi, right?
I've finally found you.
Who is this?
You know him, Natsume?
That uniform isn't from any school around here.
Um...
You managed to find friends here.
Hey, what do you mean by that?!
My bad, I'm Shibata from Sakaki West High.
Natsume and I attended the same elementary school.
You remember, don't you?
No.
But I remember.
You were special.
Can I have a word with you for just a bit?
Natsume, let's go.
I don't mind just saying it here.
I'm sorry, Nishimura, Kitamoto.
See you later.
Hey, Natsume.
How much further are we going to walk?
You used to said weird stuff...
Saying that you could see things others couldn't.
Was that true?
Liar!
He's up to his tricks again.
We should stay away from him.
Liar!
You're not serious...
Your expression's all changed.
It's true then?
That was just a prank I played during childhood, don't take it so seriously.
I'm going home.
I'll come back again.
You don't want your friends to know about it now because it's the truth.
I'm not as good at lying as I used to be...
Oh, right.
Do you have money with you?
Hey, where exactly are we going?
Shut up. Be quiet, and come with me.
There are mosquitoes everywhere!
What are we doing here?
Shhh! She's here.
Over there.
What do you see?
A girl?
What kind of girl?
A long hair, normal high school student.
Really?
She is really a human?
Don't laugh!
You can tell them apart right? Is she human or not?
She looks very normal!
Why do you ask?
Shibata?
Murasaki?
What are you doing there?
Is he your friend?
Yeah, he's Natsume.
He's an old friend.
Liar.
Try to play along!
Such cordial relationship.
After that, for a brief moment...
That girl, Murasaki and Shibata talked, before she finally went home.
The two seemed close.
Shibata seemed to really like her.
Sorry for being so weird.
You really helped me, Natsume.
What is going on?
Are you suspecting that she's a youkai?
Yeah, I was being weird.
What's this? You must be thinking I'm an idiot, right?
No, I wasn't making fun of you.
Look, it's already this late...
If I don't hurry...
The cake!
What is it?
It's so pretty!
Will these cakes do?
Yes, thanks.
I've gone to just about every cake shop in the vicinity,
but they were all out of shortcakes.
Just by myself, I probably wouldn't have found it.
I found it, Natsume!
Fortunately, Shibata was there with me.
This is really good.
Takashi-kun bought it.
Thank you, Takashi.
Eating sweet and salty food together is kinda nice.
Natsume, go get me another one of these.
I'm too tired.
I'm done.
Can't open my eyes.
Where have you been?
You have an unearthly scent on you.
Unearthly?
No, she is just a girl.
Where am I?
It's that girl.
She seems to be eating something.
Shibata!
What are you doing here again?
That's all because of the stupid things you said.
I'm worried.
I think it was around here.
I'll go take a look.
I didn't notice it yesterday,
something about this park is really making me uneasy.
That sound...
You smell delicious.
You're really a youkai!
That's right.
It doesn't have to be him, I can eat you instead.
Ahhh! I'm being bitten by what seems to be a white pig.
Nyanko-sensei!
Oww.
Curse you, human!
If you reveal my identity to anyone,
No matter where you are, I'll come and eat you!
Don't be so sure!
He's my backup food ration!
She's a youkai from one of the flower trees around here.
She takes a human form,
deceives humans, and eventually eats them.
Then, Shibata... he is just being deceived.
Youkai who are too forward tend to make mistakes.
Your friend probably came to you because he sensed something wrong about her.
You saw that person? At the gate?
Yeah, he's probably waiting for someone.
He isn't from our school.
Shibata.
So it was really you.
What are you doing here?
That's the ugliest cat I've ever seen!
Get lost, ugly cat!
Shibata, this ugly cat is mine.
What made you come all the way here?
It's about the girl from before...
Yeah... I'm really sorry for making you go through the trouble.
I met her in the park.
The first time I saw her, I was all by myself.
And we started seeing each other after that.
But she wouldn't give me her address, phone number, or even the school she attended.
I thought she didn't like me.
But her gaze told me otherwise.
Umm, Shibata.
That girl...
Icy cold...
Whether it be just talking,
or holding hands enjoying the flowers or watching the sunset,
her hand is always icy cold.
And it's the same when we met.
What would you do if I was a youkai?
It's stupid, I know.
But it didn't feel right.
Then, I remembered you.
Shibata.
She's not a human.
Stay away from her.
What are you saying?
I got it wrong.
She is not a human.
Then, what is she?
Didn't you say that she was just a normal girl!
That's because...
She's...
Enough.
Shibata.
Liar.
You're still a liar.
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Liar!
I can't stop just because he called me a liar.
Pull yourself together.
I should do what I can now.
Don't worry.
She won't show up for a couple of days.
Jeez.
Can't you show more restrain?
I told you not to come in without asking.
No cake today?
No.
More importantly, that youkai...
When you said she won't appear, do you really mean it?
She's not a powerful youkai like me.
She's just a small fry.
It'll take her at least three days before she can take on a human form again.
Three days...
I have some time, then.
Natsume?
He left? Already?
Yeah, he left through the rear gate.
He ran away.
He's gone.
Thanks.
Are you sure?
I think he's worried about you.
It's better that you talk to him, don't you think?
You two are friends, right?
No, he's...
He's someone I used to bully and didn't take seriously.
What do you intend to do?
To keep watch on that youkai, so that she doesn't get to Shibata.
What a pain.
There's no reason for you to stick your neck out for a jerk like him.
He may be a jerk, but he's not a bad person.
I think.
Oh, fine.
Now you owe me another slice of cake and another dried squid!
This scent.
Let me go!
It's you again?
You came all the way here so that I can eat you?
I already told Shibata yesterday evening that you weren't human.
Even if you were to wait here, he won't come!
Give up on him!
You're lying.
I'm not lying!
Then, I guess he didn't believe you.
If he had believe you, you wouldn't be here.
That's because...
Because he didn't believe you, you wanted to do something yourself.
That's why you made your way here, right?
Too bad.
Hey, Natsume. Where are you?
Let me go!
I can end this right now by eating her.
Wait, Sensei.
Natsume.
Wait just a little more.
I need to figure out what to do, just a little more.
Shibata really cares about her.
Natsume, you're so naive!
See, she got away!
After her, quick!
She fell.
She's indeed weakened.
Weakened?
I didn't intervene initially because I knew she didn't have much time left.
Murasaki...
Murasaki.
A Yamafuji tree?
It's big.
She's awake.
You two...
Don't touch me!
I'll eat you, all of you lowly humans who touch me!
Will you get better, if you do?
I don't know.
It's better to try eat a human than to wait here and die.
But as I was sitting there, weaken and tired after taking a human form...
Shibata came to you?
He was an easy prey,
but I was so exhausted I couldn't even eat him.
I told him to come back in three days.
Three days later, that stupid human came back foolishly.
But he looked so cheerful...
and he talked on and on...
I couldn't even find the chance to eat him.
That's why, I said we should meet again...
again, and again.
No matter how many times we met...
he always made me happy.
I never could find the chance to eat him.
To be honest, Shibata came last night.
Murasaki!
Murasaki, where are you?
But I couldn't take on a human form.
Murasaki!
Murasaki...
What are you doing here at such a late hour?
What would you do if you met a youkai?
It's okay.
Hey, want to take a walk?
To that hill by the river?
I'd love to go.
But I'm not feeling well today.
Can we do it some other time?
Okay.
It's a promise, Murasaki.
Yes, a promise.
By then, Shibata already knew my identity.
Murasaki!
Let go of her, Natsume.
She'll eat you if you touch her.
That's what I planned initially too.
I guess not anymore.
He's Shibata's friend.
Shibata would hate me if I ate him.
Hang in there.
I'll get you a fish.
Wait...
Shibata!
Sorry, it's not that I don't believe you...
But, right now...
This is a letter from Murasaki.
Murasaki?
You met her?
Where is she?
Never mind that, just take this!
Would you mind passing this to Shibata?
I wrote him a letter.
If I were to meet him face to face, I might have regrets.
I wrote my goodbye and penned out my feelings.
Is it because I forcefully got you into this?
Because I called you a liar?
Because I didn't believe in what you said?
Is that why you gave me this nonsense?
Those characters...
Enough.
It's all my fault.
So, you don't have to...
It's fine that you don't believe me.
But please keep this letter safely!
Murasaki.
Where is Murasaki?
Shibata?
Murasaki wants to see me!
This way!
Murasaki.
You shouldn't have come.
Didn't I told you I'll be going away, and we won't see each other anymore?
But...
We made a promise, didn't we?
Take me there, Shibata, like you always do.
Yeah.
Shibata...
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I was so mean to you.
Yet, you kept helping me.
Thank you, Natsume.
And just like that, Murasaki has gone to a far away place...
It's icy cold.
What's so funny?
Don't tell this to other people.
Tell them what?
That I cried.
Yeah, I won't.
What kind of answer is that?
Like you're all important.
Ever since I was little, I've always wanted friends,
humans or youkai, all the same...
that sense of warmth that will light up my heart.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Young Days
I was always alone.
He always looked sad and lonely.
I didn't understand then...
how others felt, or my own feelings...
I feel like drinking some sake!