Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Natsume, look!
Lightning! Lightning!
Quiet please, I'm trying to do my homework.
Oh? You're sure you're not afraid?
I can't concentrate like this. Close the curtains–
That struck somewhere in the forest!
The Broken Mirror
This isn't where we usually take a stroll.
It's always by the school, right?
Where are you going, Nyanko-sensei?
I'm going to find the tree that was struck by lightning.
Lightning? From yesterday?
You're being too curious.
You ignorant fool!
Centuries old trees that were struck by lightning may produce excellent sake!
This is common knowledge among youkai.
Furthermore, it's a "chance" for free sake.
Over there! Let's go! Natsume!
Wait up, Nyanko-sensei!
Jeez, where did you go?
Sensei!
Voices? What is this?
It's up in the trees...
It's sparkling...
It's sparkling?
You're right.
Is that...
Could it be...
They're right. Something is sparkling up there.
Oww!
Damn, something got in my eye.
Natsume?
What are you doing here?
Tanuma?
And you?
It's a shortcut.
I see.
Also...
I somehow keep hearing voices around here since yesterday.
Voices?
A moment ago, the lower-ranked youkai did seemed to be fussing over something...
Natsume, you're really amazing.
But it doesn't feel that way.
It was frantic.
And it sounded like it was searching for something.
Searching for something?
Something is coming.
Nyanko-sensei?
No!
Natsume!
Tanuma!
Tanuma? Are you okay?
Y-Yeah...
What was that?
Just a gust of wind?
I'm grateful, Tanuma.
But don't use yourself to protect me!
It'd be bad if something happens to you!
Yes... but it'd be bad too if something happens to you.
Yeah.
Now, this is awkward...
It's hard to keep a distance when you finally found a friend you don't have to hide your secrets from.
Good stuff!
Simply heavenly.
[ Note: Tanuki is loosely translated as raccoon. ]
A raccoon youkai!
Who are you calling a raccoon?!
Oh, it's Natsume's cat, Nyanta-sensei!
If you're not going to learn my name, just call me "Sensei"!
Jeez, where have you been, Nyanko-sensei?
Drinking, of course.
You're dead drunk!
Only a monster won't get drunk after drinking!
What's a youkai talking about "monsters"?!
Youkai and monsters are different!
Okay, I'll head off first.
Okay.
Bye.
See you tomorrow.
Though my life is still intertwine with youkai,
having a friend to share it with, makes me happy.
It'd be great if Tanuma feels the same way too.
This headache...
What is it?
I don't like this.
Natsume-kun.
Good morning.
You look sleepy.
Taki, morning.
I'm glad to see you.
I have the pictures from the Culture Fair.
I was just about to go find you.
The Cultural Fair?
Here.
That's the wrong one!
Someone forced me to take that one.
This is the one.
You looked cute.
I looked tired.
Good picture, isn't it?
Thank you.
I have one for Tanuma-kun as well.
He's sleeping with his mouth open.
It was taken when he was resting backstage.
Can you pass it to him?
Sure, leave it to me.
Year 2
Class 1
Tanuma!
Natsume!
11th Oct Duty
Nakai, Kitamoto
Kitamoto.
Where's Tanuma?
He's sick today.
I heard he has a cold.
A cold?
Um, how is Kaname-kun?
You came to visit him? Thanks.
His fever has broken.
But it'd be terrible if it catches on to you.
He'll most likely be in school tomorrow.
Tanuma is usually easily affected by youkai.
Could this be related to yesterday's incident?
Possibly... But that's because he's weak.
It's not your fault.
But he was protecting me...
My "bodyguard" was drinking himself silly.
What?!
Blame yourself for getting separated from me, idiot!
What did you say, you fat cat?
Why do you care about that wimp?
Stop calling him a wimp!
Wimp! Wimp!
Tanuma! Morning.
Are you okay now?
Was it really just a cold?
Yeah, but I haven't fully recovered yet.
So we should keep a distance for the time being.
See you!
Sensei, what's the matter?
Oh, Natsume.
The mirror shattered all of a sudden.
An old mirror, I guess.
There are so many fragments.
I'll get–
I thought I saw somebody here just now.
Was it my imagination?
Natsume, is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
This has to stop...
I've been associating everything with the youkai lately.
I hope Tanuma will get over his cold soon.
– The Next Day –
How's your cold?
Sorry, not yet.
– The Day After That –
Tanuma!
Sorry, I have to go to the teacher's office right now.
Year 2
Class 1
– The Day After The Day After That –
Is Tanuma here?
15th Oct Duty
Tanaka, Hashimoto
Yup.
He was here a minute ago.
Tanuma?
Tanuma!
Why did he dig a hole?
What's happening? My right eye...
I found you.
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Where am I?
The school's backyard?
Why is there mud on my hands?
Natsume!
What's wrong?!
You all right?
Tanuma...
I'm okay, but my eye hurts.
Eye?
More importantly,
what were you hiding?
If there's something bugging you, tell me.
Alright.
Sorry, I didn't mean to avoid you.
I've been feeling lethargic since then...
But there's no sign that I'm possessed.
I didn't want to alert you for no reason.
It might just be a cold.
But, when I came around just now.
I was at the school's backyard, covered in mud.
That's the first time it happened.
I see...
So?
Your story?
Me...
Telling you certainly takes the load off my chest.
Keeping yourself bottled up feels terrible, right?
You're right.
The truth is, that day...
[ ikayaki: BBQ squid ]
You want some ikayaki?
Ikayaki, I want you.
I want you.
I'm so happy!
You're choking me! You crazy girl!
You're choking me!
Then all of a sudden, the pain.
But it's not painful now.
Also, there's a youkai with a hammer in the school's compound.
I don't know if they're related.
I see.
What's that?
Yeah, I heard that too.
It might be that youkai with the hammer.
You better not tell me to "go back first".
Okay, I won't.
In this room?
Step back.
What? Didn't I ask you to step back?
I did.
I'm just taller than you.
You saw him?
Yeah, vaguely.
He broke another mirror?
That fella, just what–
Natsume?
What's going on? What's that sparkling...
The pain stopped.
This fragment is from a bronze mirror?
Tanuma, this...
Give it back...
Give it back to me.
I've finally found my mirror.
Give it back!
Tanuma...
Wrong, it's the youkai possessing Tanuma!
Give it back!
Stop it!
Tanuma, sorry about that.
Not bad for a mere human.
Leave Tanuma now!
No, I can't do that.
Why not?
Because my mirror is broken.
I was struck by lightning while searching for a friend.
I wanted to search for the fragments, but I was recovering too slowly.
So I possessed this child.
Tanuma was digging holes because he's searching for the fragments?
I had a hard time getting that mirror.
I'm not giving it up so easily.
The mirror will hide itself in shinny objects.
And one of the fragments is hiding in your eye.
When it is near to the other fragments,
it will resonate, and you'll feel the pain.
Come, give me back the mirror...
Give me that eye!
Stop!
Tanuma!
No matter what, I'll be staying in this body for a while.
What did you say?
Tanuma-kun!
Don't worry, I won't possess him for too long.
But, if you want him back safely, you'll have to help me, kid.
With that fragment in your eye, you'll have no problem locating the rest.
Once you return the mirror to me, I will leave.
Bullshit!
Nyanko-sensei?
I've had enough of you troublesome pests.
Leave now!
Not yet...
I will never leave until I have the mirror.
Tanuma!
Even my light can't make her leave – quite a stubborn one.
Tanuma-kun!
Tanuma!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I heard most of it...
You'll leave once we collected all the fragments for you, right?
Yes, that's right.
That's the safest way.
You were driving her out a minute ago!
If I really wanted to, I can still drive her out.
But if I do that, Tanuma might get damaged mentally.
Are you fine with that?
That's right.
You just need to find all the mirror's fragments.
Tanuma?
I still feel like this body isn't my own.
Natsume, sorry about this. Would you help me find the mirror's fragments?
Of course. We'll do it together.
Thanks.
Can I help too?
That'd be great, Taki.
But how should we go about finding them?
That youkai said that when you're close to the fragments, you'll feel a pain.
If my right eye hurts, then one is nearby.
I first felt the pain in my eye at the school's backyard.
Therefore, one of the fragments must be there.
Let's check it out.
I'll get the scoops and shovels.
Yes, please.
This is where my eye started hurting.
Oww...
It's right here.
Here?
Should I start digging?
Are you okay?
Just wait, Natsume.
I'll find it right now.
What are they doing?
Who knows.
Practicing for a play?
There it is!
No, that's...
What? It's just a piece of glass?
Because it's a youkai's mirror, people can't normally see or touch it.
Then how do we find it?
Tanuma-kun?
There!
I knew it...
I can't see it.
The youkai told me it was under the glass.
The pain is gone too.
No doubt about it, this is it.
That's great.
Thank you.
I wonder if it would fit with the other piece.
They joined together!
Amazing...
What? What's going on?
Okay. Natsume, what's next?
Let's look around a little more.
This is going to take a while...
He says it's around there.
Oww...
Flowerbeds
Seedings
It's over there, there.
Here?
Okay.
They're still doing it?
Looks like it.
Let's continue tomorrow.
Yeah, that's right.
Maybe it's because of the youkai residing in me, I'm beginning to understand...
...how the youkai feels.
I see.
The mirror is very important to her.
It seems like her friend is sick and that mirror has the power to dispel sickness.
Something like that.
For a friend?
And she also warned me...
Warned you?
The mirror is very powerful.
There are other youkai looking for the fragments.
She wants us to be careful.
Other youkai looking for the fragments...
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
What the
Mirror Shows
Natsume, is this the world you see all the time?
Get out of Tanuma!
He's a dear friend.
I have friends too.
But why did he leave without a word.
I bet he has his reason?
Even so, I want to save him.