Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Yato Inn
Jeez. Why are you following me, kitty?
A much better view than usual.
Sir, cats aren't allowed in the inn.
No, take a closer look.
It's a stuffed animal.
See the big head?
So, have you found anything about Matoba?
No, but we better prepare ourselves.
He's the type who wouldn't think twice about using dangerous youkai to achieve his goals.
Yeah, there was that time he used Crow as bait.
He doesn't show mercy, no matter who the youkai is aligned to.
Is that why you left her behind?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about your youkai.
Not really.
I'm already regretting now why I didn't bring her–
The seal!
You broke it when you came out?
So that's why I was having a hard time...
See what you have done?
What are you gonna do if something entered?
Why do you use such a cheap seal that even a cat could break!
Nothing ever goes well when I'm with you!
Natsume?
Natsume!
Natsume...
Exorcist
I won't forgive you. I won't forgive you....
How dare you. How dare you!
You're awake?
Interesting, isn't it?
That strap of paper? Normal people can't see it.
Matoba-san...
The Natori family specializes in paper, ask him.
What exactly are you up to, doing all this...
I haven't done anything.
I merely instruct them to capture you.
I don't think you'll believe me, do you?
You can see for yourself...
I'm sorry they roughed you up...
They're still learning.
But, it's your fault you ran.
I just wanted to talk with you.
Why are you taking youkai blood?
What are you up to?
Youkai's blood can be used to lift seals bounding powerful youkai,
or for summoning them.
Essentially, it is used as a lure.
There's a powerful youkai resting here in this forest.
I'm after him.
Not using your own blood, but the blood of innocent youkai...
If you continue with this, I won't let you off!
Won't let me off...
Other than being able to see them, what else can you do?
Sorry about that.
With this on, my depth perception isn't very good.
Your eye...
I'm not blind, but I need this.
Else, it would get eaten.
There was once a man who offered his right eye as payment to a youkai who helped him.
In the end though, he went back on his word.
And so, for generations, that youkai has been seeking the right eye from the Matoba chiefs.
Though my eye is still intact, he left a deep scar on my face.
This is a rare opportunity, would you like to have a look at it?
May I have a moment?
Right away.
Watch him.
No matter what your reason is, please stop attacking innocent youkai.
If you persist, I'll stop you.
I need powerful youkai so that I can protect people.
Even if it means being hated, or having to make sacrifices, that's all inevitable.
He's different.
He's totally different from Natori-san, though they are both exorcists.
I'll be right back.
If you make noise, I'd make sure you can't make a sound.
If you run, I'd make sure you can't run.
Don't try anything funny.
If he knows about the Book of Friends...
With just one blow...
I thought he's only capable of seeing them...
Should we pursue?
No.
I'll handle this.
That was close.
Matoba-san's servants?
There's a powerful youkai in that forest.
I must protect the few friends I have left.
It is used as a lure.
I may still be able to stop him.
Natsume-sama, don't go into that forest!
What's wrong?
I'm sensing something ominous in the west.
The west?
That's where they went with my master.
What is this feeling?
Eyes...
If you've eye contact with him, you'd be devoured.
They'll all be devoured!
Where are you going?
To save him.
I can't get Natsume-sama involved in this.
To be involved or not, is Natsume's own decision.
My master and the fat cat are with him as well.
But...
How can you help in your current condition?
Rest here.
Natsume-sama...
Why haven't you call me, Natori...
I'd fly there immediately.
Matoba-sama, he has just checked out.
I see...
See? We're screwed!
You've always been an unreliable guy.
But starting today, you'd be known as Useless. Useless Natori!
Everyone, the Useless Natori Shuuichi exorcist is here!
What did you say, you tubby fat pig?
Follow this!
Sir, that is indeed a cat.
No...
Who was that?
I can't let Matoba-san get what he's after.
I must find this "powerful youkai", and stop him somehow.
Where are you?
I should be able to sense you.
Sorry!
It's coming from here.
He should be around here.
Oww...
A cave?
There's something inside!
What a noisy kid.
Are you here to disturb me?
Matoba-san's servant?
It's a pity, but you'll just have to be the sacrifice.
Time is running short.
Wait, I know this voice...
Before he comes...
That guy!
Sensei!
Scram!
Get back, Natsume!
Natori-san!
My light ray didn't work on her.
This is the voice...
The evil intent I felt is from that masked youkai...
The voice I heard in that dream...
You are a human?
Of course.
Oh, yeah... You're the witch who once served Matoba.
You know her?
Yeah, Matoba used her youkai as bait.
After that, she resigned and disappeared.
Her servant was used as bait?
I won't forgive you... Matoba.
I'll devour him.
I'll awaken the youkai to devour Matoba!
Natsume
Yuujinchou
He is our guy?
It doesn't look like he's woken up yet...
Look, Natsume.
The awakening circle has been drawn with him in the center.
Those pots for...
You idiot.
They contain the blood that's been collected, of course.
I found this youkai that the greedy Matoba would sure be interested in, then I spread the word out...
All to lure him here to this village to be devoured.
To avenge your lost servant?
It's regretful, but in our line of work, youkai are–
Tools at our disposal?
I didn't think of him that way.
He wasn't a tool.
Even so, this has gotten too far.
It doesn't matter that an exorcist such as you doesn't understand.
What's important is blood. I don't have enough blood.
I'm taking yours!
Do you think it's gonna be that easy?
This is so irritating.
Taste awful.
I'll wipe out all these paper dolls.
Sensei!
Natsume!
Oops, my bad.
There were so many youkai running about, I couldn't tell who is with whom.
I didn't mean to shoot that kid though.
Matoba!
It really took me a lot of trouble to find this place.
Whenever something happens, I rush to the scene, send my youkai out to investigate...
and have my servants searched the forest repeatedly, but still nothing.
All it took was to let you run loose for a couple of minutes and you lead me right to it.
Perhaps, you...
Little punk...
You arrogant kid, repent for your mistake!
Sensei!
Calm down, Sensei!
Don't move too much!
Your wounds will open!
Natsume!
I'm fine.
More importantly, Sensei...
Sensei!
Count yourself lucky, Matoba.
What? This is boring.
Sensei, you're bleeding.
Stop fussing over a drop of blood or two.
I'll just lick it clean.
Natsume, how's your wound?
It just scraped me.
The bleeding has stopped.
What's happening?
Sensei is without a doubt a youkai.
You idiot!
If my blood was running like that in my body, I'd be terrified too!
A chant?
Look, the blood in the pots!
This is bad.
The cat's blood is very powerful, he's woken up now.
Sensei...
Did he deliberately aim for Sensei right at the start so that he could test out on this youkai?
Get away, Natsume!
This is bad!
He's letting out a poisonous gas!
Hear me! I'm the person who collected the blood and drew the circle!
Devour that man for me!
Quick, over there! That man–
Natsume, run!
Right!
Are you okay?
You're still the same...
What do we do?
It'd be a disaster if he gets to the surface.
This is pathetic...
You're an exorcist, yet you develop feelings for a youkai...
Then you do something this foolish...
Look at you now.
Matoba...
That youkai is unsuitable.
I'm leaving.
Hey, you!
Don't bother with him, Natsume.
It's dangerous here, go outside.
Okay then.
Natori-san?
I'll try to seal it away.
Natsume, you take everybody outside.
That won't do. I'll help too.
What are you saying...
Two are better than one, right?
All right then.
Sensei, you'll stay here with her.
Sensei...
How is it?
Is that youkai any good?
No.
He doesn't understand me, a contract is not possible.
And he's too powerful to force into a submission with spells.
Not to mention the poisonous gas.
That's too bad.
Seeing that they are still not out here, I bet Natori went back in to seal the youkai.
Natori?
I teased him a little and he came running here?
What a child.
Let's go.
It's a waste to have our chief down here only to find an unsuitable youkai.
Not exactly...
Though we have no use for the youkai, I'm rather interested in that boy and his cat.
Okay, follow me.
He's fast!
Come on, just a bit more!
Natsume!
Guardian of the Earth, holder of the keys, hear me...
Spare no one who disturbs the tranquility...
He who's not human, take him.
Natsume!
Natsume...
Why waste time on a youkai that is useless to you, just destroy it.
Though I don't care for the youkai or that woman...
you interest me.
We will meet again.
We'll exchange pointers then.
The Matoba Exorcist...
I won't forgive you.
Matoba...
There's nothing you can do with that now.
Put the past behind you.
Forget it?
Can you?
He is Natsume?
Yes.
Natsume Takashi.
He is Natsume Reiko's grandson.
I see... her...
That just makes him all the more interesting.
The Natori Clan will take over from here.
All right.
Master.
I'm back, Hiragi.
Welcome back.
Are you mad?
I have no reason to be angry.
Because you're my master.
Do they not see...
the pain of a youkai who went around trying to protect her friends...
or the pain of a human who was so close to her youkai that she broke apart when he's gone...
How can they completely disregard other people just to achieve their own goals...
Natsume...
There's no need to weigh yourself down being bothered by them.
Some people are just like that.
That's all there is to it.
He's right.
I have Sensei by my side, and Natori-san, and Hiragi.
I'm...
different from them.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
The Fox Child's Watch
He's here!
Natsume's here again!
Seeing how strong I've become,
I wonder if he'd be happy for me.
Though the God of Stone said something I don't quite understand,
I want to help Natsume as much as I can!