Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
Got you!
Come back!
Catch us if you can!
Are you okay?
He's gotten so bold!
Mom, I've gotten stronger.
I'm fine even if I'm on my own.
I'm sure I'm ready to help Natsume now.
Natsume...
The Fox Child's Watch
Huh, I'm going on a trip with Shigeru-san?
Yeah.
You remember Yasui-san, from the Kariba Hot Springs?
You know, the place you got this teacup for me?
Yeah, near the summer resort.
In truth, I've been in contact with him since then.
He is having a pottery class, and wanted me over.
Touko-san's coming too?
I'm meeting some friends at the supermarket on that day.
You two just go and have fun.
Though it's said to be a class, it's really a chance for the kids from the neighborhood to get together.
If you're not up for it, I can turn it down.
No...
Do you have plans with your friends?
No, I'd love to go.
Okay, let's go together.
Yeah.
Sensei!
What's wrong?
Were you groaning just now?
You must have slept out of your mind, Natsume.
Does it still hurt?
A tiny wound like that? It'd be fine after I lick it a couple more times.
I was planning on having the middle-rank youkai take care of you while I'm at the hot springs.
What?
A hot spring?
Natsume, you're going to a hot spring without me?
See, you shouldn't be moving around yet.
The Kariba springs aren't going to cure a youkai's wounds, you know?
Hinoe! Nobody asked you!
I heard you were injured, so I came to see you.
Is that how you greet your visitor?
Let's see...
You were hit by a cursed arrow, huh?
It's going to take long to recover.
Seriously?
Sensei said it'd heal in no time.
That wasn't far from the truth either.
To us youkai, it's just a blink of an eye.
Even so, it's difficult even for a powerful youkai like Madara to regain all his energy.
It looks like he's lost a lot of blood.
I guess a trip is out of the question then.
I'll just have to apologize to Shigeru-san...
You should go.
I've heard that the herb, "oborosou" grows there.
Oborosou?
It's a youkai herb that normal people can't see.
It grows on trees that are centuries old.
Grind it up and apply to the wound. It does wonders on youkai.
Nah, I don't need that. Take me to the hot springs, Natsume.
Fine, fine.
To say the truth, I wanted to go too.
Madara-sama, we've come to visit you.
Visit... Visit...
I heard that the white pig was injured, so I've come to see for myself.
Hey, it's Hinoe-dono.
How about a drink!
I love to!
Come on, not here!
You guys are too noisy–
It would probably worsen his injuries if I left him here...
You didn't sleep well, Takashi?
Yeah, I was up packing all night.
Want some coffee?
Yes, please.
Thanks.
There's a restaurant on the way there that sells delicious takeouts.
We will have that for lunch.
Sure.
Is this what it feels like be on a trip with your own dad?
It's a bit embarrassing, but I feel safe.
But sitting across from him, I don't really know what to say.
Young people aren't interested in pottery, are they?
I feel bad making you come here for my hobby.
That's not true.
I like the teacup we got last year.
For a long time, I've liked the touch of pottery.
It looks cold, but feels warm... like the clay is still warm.
I understand that.
So, I've always thought of baking one myself...
Having a conversation like this with Shigeru-san is something new to me...
This is something humans wear on their wrists.
I see it!
You come here often to look at those trains used by the humans.
Who are you?
I'm none other than the rock you're stepping on.
I suppose you could say I'm the living form of the rock.
People used to call me the Stone God.
Stone God... You are a god?
The humans decided on their own to worship me, that's just it.
You come here to watch the trains often.
Are they that interesting?
No, I thought that Natsume might return, so I come here to check.
Although I'm disappointed everytime, I'm certain Natsume will come.
Natsume... A friend of yours?
Friend?
Yeah! Natsume's my friend!
You're wearing a watch.
A watch?
It's a device humans used to track time.
It wasn't moving a while ago!
Why are you wearing that? Do you wish to become human?
Become human?
No, I want to be a great fox, just like my mom!
Then, it's useless to you.
Because it measures human time.
Human time?
It's Natsume!
Natsume's here!
Wait!
Natsume came to see me again!
I'm not as weak as before, Natsume!
It's so windy here.
Yes.
Let's go.
It's been a year...
I wonder how he's doing.
Natsume...
That man...
He lives with Natsume.
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Fujiwara-san, welcome.
Good to see you.
Takashi-kun, am I right?
You came to get the teacups last year.
Yes. It's been a while.
Come in.
I'll take you to the studio.
Natsume, over here!
What's this?
He's carrying a human item!
The beast thinks he's human?
How dare him, he can't even do a proper transformation.
Give it back!
Pass!
Give it back to me!
Catch!
This won't be as easy as the last time!
Give it back!
Sorry, sorry! You can have it back!
That's why I said he's a beast...
Mom said never to go near that place.
This is where we'll be firing the pieces we make in pottery class tomorrow.
And it'd be ready the following day, for you all to take home.
I look forward to it.
You must all be tired by now.
There's a hot spring out back.
Enjoy yourselves.
Thank you.
If this goes on, I won't be able to get close to Natsume.
Let's change over.
You've grown up.
Compared to when you just moved in.
Everybody still says I'm frail, and makes fun of me.
You're much stronger now.
I can tell, since we live together.
What a nice hot spring...
What is Natsume doing at such a dangerous place?
Didn't he come here to see me?
Natsume
Yuujinchou
It stopped.
I see...
It's only alive when I'm moving.
Be sure not to trap any air in the clay.
Natsume!
Skinny brother, lift me up!
Me too! Me too!
You're so weak.
Why won't I get any bigger?
We're going to start burning.
Takashi-kun, can you help me with the kiln?
Sure!
Beast child, stop seeing the human.
Why?
If you don't, one party will always be left with the sad memories.
You know...
Every entity in this world has his own time and space.
And they're not always the same.
Humans have humans', youkai have youkai's...
And beasts, their own definition of time.
I don't understand.
Natsume and you don't share the same time.
You must hurry.
You must find a partner, have children, and teach them wisely, just like your mother.
That is how a beast should live his time.
In the same way, Natsume has his own time to live.
And that is very different than yours.
Does the Stone God lives in his own time too?
I live the time of a rock.
I was here long before there was humans or youkai.
And I'll stay here until time abruptly ends.
Here always?
The day I leave this place, is the day I disappear.
That's the meaning of my existence.
Don't you feel lonely?
To me, it wasn't really that long ago.
But it wasn't short either.
We close this up like this while it burns.
And the clay will harden into the form we gave it.
After that, we can start with the coloring.
Now, we'll take a break.
Takashi, is there anything you'd like to do?
Yasui-san said he's going to show me some of his pieces.
I'll take this chance to explore around for a bit.
I thought I would see him in no time.
Guess I was too naive.
He has his own life, I suppose.
I remember you...
Oh, it's Master Natsume.
It's been a while.
Oh, yeah.
Do you know what that little fox is up to?
Oh, that guy?
He's no good, Master.
He's grown into a little delinquent.
A delinquent?
We don't know what to do with him.
Just look at this scar!
You two weren't bullying him again, were you?
Of course not!
Is that so...
There's one other thing I want to know...
Mom, I don't understand.
I just wanted to be with Natsume.
Don't get so nervous.
Master Natsume is here, we wouldn't misbehave.
You met him?!
He wanted to see you.
Really?
Natsume...
But he is pretty busy.
He is looking for some kind of herb that is growing here.
Herb?
Yeah, it's called "oborosou". Seems like it grows on the ancient trees here.
Oborosou...
Takashi!
It's about time to apply the colors!
Coming!
If only I could do something for Natsume...
We'll bake them for another twelve hours, and they'll be done.
Good work, everyone.
What's wrong?
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
You can't be up there, Sensei. You should be resting.
A thunderstorm is coming...
It's nothing, he'll be just fine.
It's right there!
Natsume...
I'll give that to Natsume!
I'm almost there!
Hey!
Natsume...
Natsume!
Natsume! Natsume!
You got those for me, right?
Thank you.
Natsume, the Stone God saved me...
Look!
The day I leave this place, is the day I disappear.
That's the meaning of my existence.
The Stone God told me not to see you again.
Said that one of us would have sad memories.
But... but that's not true, Natsume!
The watch is broken now...
...but it was working before, Natsume.
I remembered it all... meeting the Stone God, what we talked about, and how he saved me...
So I'm sure Natsume and I will... will...
I don't know the whole story why he would want the fox child to forget about me...
But I think I can understand what the Stone God is trying to say.
Humans and youkai have very different lives...
He must have seen it more than anyone.
Natsume!
Goodbye!
Oh, Nyangoro's on it.
Yes.
Very well made.
Isn't that great? Nyangoro.
Although we only meet for a brief moment,
it doesn't matter, I will still cherish every moment.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Through the
Autumn Wind
I got acquainted with a youkai again.
The cultural festival must have a bunny girl cafe!
We can't have bunny girls!
What's wrong, Natsume?
The festival is gonna be fun!
Yeah, I'm looking forward to it too, very much.
Set up a kitty cafe where I'll be the center of attention!