Natsume
Yuujinchou
Somedays, feeling lost, I can't help but let out a sigh
kotae no nai hibi ni tameiki morasu tabi
It's like I couldn't even see the real me
honto no boku wa mo mienaku na chatta
Even when I listen hard, I couldn't hear your voice
mimi wo sumashite mo kikoenai kimi no koe
but I will continue walking today to chase after you
oikakete kyo mo aruki tsuzukeru
My feelings for you just keep building up into a cocoon
tsutae rarezu ni itta omoi toki o hete sanagi ni natte
and now they spread their wings and take off
hane hiroge yagate tobitatsu
I can't forget those moments, each one, each one
wasurenai taisetsuna hitotsu hitotsu
Just hope that my feelings will reach you, somehow, someday
todoku ka na kono omoi douka itsuka
Small things, that even I can do
chippokena kono boku ni dekiru koto
Little by little, you'll feel my thoughts for you
sukoshi zutsude mo tsutaete mitai nda
It just started raining all of a sudden.
Natsume, let's take shelter by that house.
This is a really big house.
Must have a rich history, right?
Yeah.
Truth be told, I don't like to be near places where I can sense youkai.
What's wrong, Natsume?
Just now, I heard a strange voice coming from inside.
A voice?
Tanuma, let's go.
Natsume?
This is bad, there's indeed youkai here...
Huh?
Natsume-kun?
Tanuma-kun?
Taki?
And Nyanko-sensei?
The Thing Lurking in the Storeroom
So this is Taki's house.
Your house's really big.
It's an old house, cleaning it is a hassle.
Oh yeah, why is Nyanko-sensei here?
It was raining, so I went out to take a look...
Fluffy! Fluffy!
Before I knew it, he was already in my arms.
I'm sorry.
Geez, when are you going to learn to control yourself?!
[ youkan: pudding ]
You think one piece of youkan will make it up to me?!
What I thought was a youkai's voice, turned out to be sensei's screaming.
Are you sure you want to help with the storeroom?
No problem.
We're grateful you sheltered us from the rain.
That's right.
Thank you. You're a great help.
Nyanko-sensei, are you sensing any youkai?
I'm picking up many lingering scents, probably because this is an old house.
Nothing particularly odd at the moment.
I see.
That's great.
Well then...
I've had my youkan, I'm leaving.
What's the matter?
Wooden doll! Wooden doll!
Sorry about that...
That wooden doll is for warding off evil.
I was scared of it too, when I was young.
For warding off evil, more like scaring thieves off...
[ Onmyouji: The Art of Yin and Yang ]
Taki's family used to be in the Onmyouji business, wasn't it?
That was a long time ago.
Although my grandfather couldn't see youkai, he researched them.
Youkai
Come Quick
When I was young,
he taught me lots of things, here in this storeroom.
But my mom and dad didn't like this place,
that's why I'm the only one who would come in here.
What's this?
[ kappa: river-boy ]
A kappa, huh?
What a strange person, to want to see youkai.
It's nothing great to be able to see youkai.
Natsume.
How long are you gonna take to open that window?
Sorry.
[ kimono: Japanese traditional garment ]
Scared me for a second... those kimonos...
I thought somebody was standing there.
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
Those are for warding off evil, too.
He was indeed a strange man.
All done!
Thank you, everyone!
I'm sorry you guys have to work so hard.
That was nothing.
[ yakisoba: fried noodles ]
How about some yakisoba, my treat, in return for your help.
Sounds great.
Huh?
Taki, did you put one of those kimonos away?
No.
It's just like before, only two.
Huh?
But those two are remarkably similar, aren't they?
Absolutely.
They're good friends, right?
Their voices sound the same too.
Taki, hmm...
What?
Nevermind... I'm going to the toilet.
I must have remembered it wrong.
That was nothing, I shouldn't alarm them.
Oww...
Oh my, he saw me.
He saw me! He saw me!
Wait!
Hey!
I've never seen you before, kid.
You can see youkai?
That's interesting.
Are you friends with the kimono youkai?
I merely drop in here every once in a while.
I came here often when Shin'ichiro was still alive.
Shin'ichiro?
You don't mean Taki's grandfather?
He couldn't see youkai.
That's right, he couldn't, right till the very end.
What exactly is that kimono youkai?
You took down the inverted drawing, didn't you?
Just like the inverted Buddha,
you shouldn't touch anything that is placed upside down.
That's called a reverse seal.
Shin'ichiro did it once with the information he collected.
He didn't know it, but it worked.
He sealed away a rather evil youkai.
An aged-old youkai of a human doll.
Under the seal, his body was torn apart and scattered all around this house.
His torso and left arm were sealed in the storeroom.
He's searching the house, trying to find the rest of his body.
If he reclaims his body, you'll be in a whole lot of trouble.
Coincidentally, his right leg is right under you.
Natsume?
Huh? This scent...
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Natsume?
Is there something under the house?
A kimono youkai, huh?
My grandfather sealed it?
Yes.
This is Shin'ichiro's granddaughter?
What's wrong, Natsume?
Is there something there?
Yeah. She's the youkai who told me about the kimono youkai.
A youkai? Right here?
She said your grandfather was talented, but was a pity he couldn't see youkai.
Grandfather...
Natsume?
Did you hear that?
Just now, something just crawled along the second floor.
Wait, Natsume.
On the surface, Natsume does appeared to be acting out.
Yeah.
But if you know the truth,
you'd understand that Natusme is right now trying to protect us and the house.
Where is he? Where is he?
There are still as many dark rooms in this house as before.
Stop talking from my shoulder.
You guys didn't play tricks on Shin'ichiro-san because he couldn't see you, did you?
You bet we did.
Come on.
He really couldn't see us at all.
Look at that window.
Ever since young, Shin'ichiro would sit there
with paintings of youkai and books about youkai.
Enjoying them, as though he was reading a novel.
Right there.
Just once, let me see them just once.
We were right there, but he never realized it. That was so much fun.
Ah, I miss that.
Natsume-kun?
It's open.
I'm going up.
Tanuma?
I'm fine.
But this feeling... there's certainly something here.
Over to the right.
Uh, this bad, he's here too.
Natsume!
Are you okay?
I shouldn't have pulled you out.
No, you saved us.
Thanks.
Oh my, it's been a while since I felt strange spiritual energy from the house.
So, the seal's been broken.
Damn, I thought Shin'ichiro was back, and was doing something weird again.
Idiot! Shin'ichiro died a long time ago.
Humans can't be brought back to life that easily.
Oh, is that so... So boring...
What?
But isn't Shin'ichiro right there?
No, that's his granddaughter.
That girl who wouldn't stop crying at his funeral.
Oh, you're right.
So boring...
Natsume-kun, those youkai over there, who are they?
They're youkai who knew your grandfather.
And they seemed to really liked him.
Oww... oww...
Don't just make things up!
He didn't even knew what we looked like!
Shin'ichiro was just our toy.
Kid, you can see us?
Oh, that's so rare.
He's so different from Shin'ichiro.
Well, human child, a word of advice for you on our acquaintance.
According to the youkai on the wall, the kimono youkai, "Kakrua"...
has already gotten back his legs and left arm.
His right arm is broken and shriveled.
All that's left now is his head.
And it's in the backyard?
Yes.
This way.
Tanuma...
I'm glad.
Huh?
I thought you would again tell me to "wait here" or "go home first", something along that line...
Having people who would listen to me, and still stay along with me...
Natsume-kun?
Natsume!
Where are you, Natsume?
Natsume-kun!
He's gone.
Don't tell me the youkai has taken him.
How are we going to find someone we can't see?
That's right.
I can use the circle.
The circle?
The circle that reveals the youkai inside of it?
Yes.
We can use that to seek help from the youkai Natsume was talking to.
Yin and Yang
&
The Five Elements
Yin and Yang
&
The Five Elements
Yin and Yang
&
The Five Elements
Yin and Yang
Got it.
I'm seen by a mere human...
And they seem to really like him.
Natsume, where are you?
What are you doing?
I should be asking you that, Ponta!
I came because it was getting late.
Where's Natsume?
Please help me, youkai.
Tell me where Natsume has gone!
Please!
Answer me!
Please, please!
Taki!
Ponta's here.
Let's go check the backyard.
Okay.
Why didn't you step into the circle?
We had no reason to.
It's no good to be involved with humans.
Hey, wake up.
Kid.
If you don't wake up, he is going to chop off your right arm.
Where am I?
The backyard.
Look.
He can't get to it with only one arm.
I see... that's great.
That's why he intends to absorb your immense spiritual energy, and make your arm his own.
That's my dessert... you're preying.
Nyanko-sensei!
What is with this house?
There's half-assed barriers everywhere.
What'd you say?
Shin'ichiro must've set these while he was learning.
That's why he was only half-assed talented.
Natsume-kun!
It's dangerous!
Stay away!
Stop wriggling about!
Nyanko-sensei!
My my... I can't stand it anymore.
Exactly.
Good, keep him still.
Sensei, wait!
What's going on?
Shin'ichiro isn't reading his books or drawing his weird pictures these days.
He seems to be ill.
It's so boring...
That's right!
That person "Doctor", with strings running to his ears, used that thing to treat Shin'ichiro.
We made one just like it!
Will this work?
If a human can do it, there is no reason we can't.
Get well soon, Shin'ichiro!
Humans are such frail creatures...
Get well soon.
Get well soon, Shin'ichiro.
We'll be so bored without you.
Don't you want to see us?
Get well soon.
Grandpa!
There are others crying...
crying loudly...
...along with a little Taki.
Natsume-kun!
Good, you're awake.
Tanuma, Taki.
Where's Kakura?
I got rid of him long ago.
Sensei...
Leaving soon?
Of course.
We'll never come back again.
We don't need these troubles.
The youkai on the wall helped us.
We weren't helping you...
Yeah.
It's because there's a lot of interesting items here.
Not because it's Shin'ichiro's house...
Thank you!
Thank you, for coming here to see my grandfather.
Farewell, Shin'ichiro's granddaughter.
Take care.
What's that smell?
Is it some kind of flower?
I know that smell.
While I was crying for my grandfather, there was also this flowery gentle scent.
They might not know this...
But they were calling out the name of a person who had never saw them.
Seeing them is equivalent to meeting them...
Would you tell me about it?
About the youkai you've met.
Endless meetings and partings...
Memories that I've long held secret...
But now that I decided to talk about it, it's so fascinating...
Words can't adequately describe them.
The warmth once lost is returning bit by bit...
nakushita nukumori wo hitotsu hitotsu narabete
together with pieces of your colorful smile
irotoridori no kimi no kakera wa waratta kao wo egaita
Still unsure how to create new memories,
omoide no tsukurikata mo marude umaku naranai mama ni
I powerlessly leave myself to the rapid flow of time
ashibaya ni sugiru toki no nagare ni tada mi wo makasete
Where should I go, when I'm at the end of a dark alley?
doko ni ikeba ii kono yami no sakide mata
How many times do I have to say goodbye?
nando sayonara ieba ii
It's glistering deep in my heart...
hoka ni kokoro no naka de hikatta
far away, the pieces of you
harukana kimi no kakera
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Natsume
Yuujinchou
That Which Is Not Human
It's you...
My name is Matoba.
Why are you taking youkai's blood, what are you up to?
I've a bad premonition.
It's best not to get involved with him.
Long time no see, Natsume.
I'm sorry I'm still an eye-candy.
The premonition was right!