There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Sensei!
Nyanko-sensei!
Geez, where'd he go?
He said there was some shortcut through Nanatsujiya,
but there isn't even anything that looks like a road.
The weather's nice.
Autumn Banquet
I told that darn Natsume to follow me,
and now he's gone.
All right.
I'll wait five seconds for him.
One, two,
three...
Oh, a cat?
Don't scare me.
Huh?
Isn't this Natsume's fat cat?
Was it Nyan Nyan-sensei?
Are you okay, Nyan Nyan-sensei?
Nyan Nyan...
That's a pretty embarrassing name.
Let's go with Ponta.
Hey, Ponta, wake up!
Come on, Ponta!
It's Nyanko-sensei!
Aren't you Tanuma?
You're pretty good for an idiot.
The...
The?
The cat talked.
D-Damn.
You haven't heard about me from Natsume yet?
So, you're a youkai, Ponta?
It's Nyanko-sensei!
You're not a youkai?
There's a big difference! I'm a very high being.
Don't compare me to those youkai.
This is my first time.
This is my first time talking to a youkai.
That's right, you can't see us properly.
So, that's why Natsume didn't tell you about me?
You wouldn't be much help anyway.
I see...
Maybe you're right.
What are you to Natsume?
His sensei!
Natsume is my follower.
Follower?
You're not treating him badly, are you?
What do you mean?
Any way you look at it, you're more like the follower.
Are you threatening him?
Damn fool! I won't let you say what you want!
Now that you've seen what I really am,
I'll have to destroy the evidence!
I'll swallow you who-
What are you doing, Sensei?
N-Natsume?
Why's that cat with you?
He's something like a bodyguard.
Natsume,
if you don't want to talk about it, it's okay.
No, that's not it.
It's pretty complex, so I'm not sure how to explain it all.
Ah, well, it's not like I wanted to hide it from you.
No, that's not it.
I actually was hiding it.
I wanted to talk with you normally.
That's why I didn't want to put you through anything miserable.
Are you in a miserable situation?
Look, Natsume! I caught a big one!
Look, look!
No, not really.
What was that?
Ah, it's a festival.
They're holding one tonight.
A fall festival?
All right, let's go take a look, Natsume.
They're still setting it up.
I don't care, let's go!
Hey, wait, Sensei!
The temple is on my way home, so I'll tag along.
Okay.
Oh, it's not open yet?
I told you they were still setting up.
I thought the street stands might've been open already.
Natsume-kun!
Sasada.
What's up? It hasn't begun yet.
Is someone you know here?
No, that's not it.
Are you helping out?
Yeah, I was asked to.
I know!
They're here, aren't they?
They're here? What is?
Don't play dumb.
I heard they gather where it's really lively.
You're still saying that?
Well, it is true.
There are a lot of them.
I'm right, aren't I? What kinds are there?
Jun-chan!
Sorry, but could you take this to the front of the shrine?
Okay!
You.
Please take that to the shrine.
Me?
Hurry up, I'm in the middle of a conversation.
She asked you though.
Don't talk back to the class rep.
We're in difference classes though.
I'll go then.
You can't go.
Jun-chan?
This person will be going!
Hey, hey!
Quickly!
Just wait a bit! I'll be right back!
Now's our chance.
Yeah.
I'm sure Natsume will come to the festival.
What's with you?
You came as a fox?
Hold it!
Stop!
You did it now, you rascally fox!
N-No, it wasn't me!
You know,
humans can't see us.
That's mean!
I just prepared those!
I won't let you go!
Ah, no, no! It wasn't me!
Stop struggling!
N-Natsume! Help me, Natsume!
Natsume?
Aren't you being a bit too rough?
Who are you?
This has nothing to do with you! Get lost!
Did you see the fox do it?
No, I didn't.
But he's the only one around here!
Looks like it was the wind.
Let go.
He can see us!
He's a monster!
Here's some barley tea.
Ah, thanks.
It's so empty here that it's almost surprising, huh?
Ah, no.
It's about time.
Look at the corner of the ceiling.
The ceiling?
It's pretty.
Right?
The pond's reflection, huh?
Look.
There isn't a pond in the backyard.
So, I think only we can see the water reflection on the ceiling.
What's wrong?
Ah, it's nothing.
Yeah, it's strange.
So, Tanuma can't see the pond.
What?
I forgot him.
He got away...
Natsume-kun's fat cat.
If he's here, then Natsume will come back.
All right!
Excuse me, do you have any rope? Oh, and as tough as possible.
No, Natsume, those aren't my whiskers.
It's my cheek.
Stop.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Thank you!
You're welcome.
So, you can understand me.
Yeah.
Do you know Natsume?
No.
I see. Natsume can understand me too.
Did you come to meet him?
Yeah! I'm sure he'll come.
I see, I hope you'll meet him.
Yeah! Well, thank you!
Bye!
Hiiragi.
Follow him.
Yes.
Forgive my tardiness.
How careless of me!
Calm down a bit.
Takashi-kun could've told us he'd be going straight to the festival.
He's not a child.
But, if he's in an accident...
You worry too much.
Nyangoro will come tell us if that happens.
Don't joke around, geez...
How long has it been since Takashi came here?
I'm sure he's gone through a lot of tough things,
but he's too considerate.
But with him going out on his own like this, I am put at ease.
Being too considerate of each other isn't being a family.
But...
We were a bit too early.
Yeah.
What? Someone dropped it?
I'll go return it!
A dropped item?
All right, I'll hold on to it.
Thank you.
Someone dropped something.
Okay.
Kitty! What's wrong? Did they catch you?
Did you do something bad?
All right, I'll save you!
It got away!
Could you help me for a bit?
Ah, okay.
Ponta's not here.
Yeah.
Ponta?
Ah, sorry. It's nothing.
How about we split up and look?
Sorry, but will you?
Yeah.
I don't see your pouch.
You can't remember where you dropped it?
Is what's inside so important?
Yeah, it's really important.
I see.
Let's search over there.
Where'd Sensei go?
Hey, Natsume! So you came!
Hey, did you see Nyan-
No, did you see my cat?
That fat cat?
Nope.
I see.
Did it run away?
Yeah.
See you.
Here you go.
Ah, thanks.
Where's my taiyaki, mister?
Huh? I just gave it to you.
I didn't get anything!
I did, just pay up.
I'm not going to pay for what I didn't get!
What'd you say?!
Ah, uh, no...
Ah, how much was it?
What's he doing?
Is that it?
Yeah.
Just what's inside it?
Medicine.
Medicine?
It's medicine that allows me to be human for a while.
I'll cause Natsume trouble if I'm in my animal form.
I see, so that's how it is.
All right, I'll go and...
Hey!
You came here because of the smell of food, didn't you, little fox?
You can't have it though!
Hey!
That's not it!
Stop!
Natsume!
Natsume-kun!
It sneaked in?
Yeah.
I see.
I'll let it go in the mountains then.
Yeah, thanks.
Wait, I'll go too!
Hey!
The pot's boiling.
Oh no!
That's strange, I'm sure I lowered the fire.
Thanks!
It's dangerous if you're in a crowd of people with that form.
I'm sorry, but...!
Well...
I brought it for you.
You're...
Thanks!
If you're here, Hiiragi, then Natori-san is here too?
Yes.
He's meeting someone now.
He asked you to watch him?
You're being careless talking to me in such a crowded area.
They'll find you creepy.
I don't mind,
because I can see you.
You're too kind.
Are you that little fox from before?
He's fine.
I'm finally free.
Damn that Natsume, he didn't even come to save me.
How cruel.
Welcome back,
fatty.
This area is pretty cold.
Yeah.
It's quiet though.
Hey.
You could see the pond in my backyard, right?
All I can see are the shadows on the ceiling.
Does Touko-san know you can see these things?
No.
You don't believe in them?
That's not it.
They're kind, so I'm sure they'll believe me if I tell them.
But, because they're kind,
I'm sure they'll feel bad because they've cared for me so much.
It may be selfish,
but I don't like it.
I want them to always be smiling.
It's started.
It's better than I thought.
I thought it would've been more shabby since it's the countryside.
Yeah.
What is it?
Nothing.
Sorry, I actually can't see it.
There's some big guy in the way.
A big guy? You mean a youkai?
Yeah.
I can tell that it's pretty though.
He's gazing at it so intently.
Let's walk for a bit.
There might be some place so you can see too.
Yeah, let's go.
It's so pretty!
I can see it well here.
I see, that's great.
What color are the shadow fish?
They're red.
Red...
I see.
So, this is where you are, you heartless bastard.
Nyanko-sensei!
I can't believe you left your precious bodyguard, you...!
There's another one!
I could hear the winter's footsteps approaching.
It's an autumn night,
but it's warm here.
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo