There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Hold on a minute, Natsume.
Could you write your name on this?
My name?
Are you going to do something at the closed-down school building?
We're doing a courage test.
Sasada.
If we don't gather a certain number of people, we can't get permission.
So, could you help us?
It sounds fun, doesn't it?
It was Sasada's idea.
Thanks.
Ah, sure.
What?
Nothing.
He's saying it's surprising.
Well, I didn't think our haughty class rep would be organizing a ghost hunt, either.
Did you say something?
I'll call you when everything has gone through.
Okay.
What is it?
So they really can't see it?
D-Damn.
L-Later!
Hey, Natsume!
Why's he in a rush so suddenly?
W-What was that, just now?
The Dew God's Small Shrine
He's not chasing after me?
Natsume-sama!
You're Natsume Reiko, aren't you?
No, Reiko is my grandmother.
She already passed aw–
Give me the Book of Friends!
If you don't, I'll gobble you up!
Stop it.
Nyanko-sensei...
Don't get in my way!
That is not something to be used by a low-level youkai like you.
Silence!
Also, I have a deal with him to receive the Book of Friends once he dies.
In other words, it's already been promised to me.
So, be good and get lost.
You...
should get lost!
Y-You're!
Get lost. You don't know who you're up against.
That settles that.
Thanks, Sensei.
You can thank me with Nanatsuji steamed buns.
So you took a liking to them.
Due to the Book of Friends, there are two types of youkai that come to me.
The first type is like the one just now, those who are after the Book of Friends
in order to control the youkai whose names are written in it.
And the other type is...
Excuse me.
The ones who come back to have their names returned from the Book of Friends.
Ah, I could eat those steamed buns forever!
Oh, you returned another name?
Yeah...
Geez, what a waste.
The Book of Friends is getting thinner and thinner.
When I return their names, I become very tired.
I wonder how many will be left once I inherit it?
Maybe I should just eat this kid right now?
I can hear you, you damned, cheating fortune cat.
Thanks for the meal.
Eat up, okay?
Okay.
Touko-san is cheerful and kind.
Shigeru-san doesn't talk much, but he's always gentle.
I don't ever want to cause these people trouble.
He's not eating.
The cat.
I'm causing them utter trouble!
Maybe it doesn't like leftovers?
Maybe this will do the trick.
Oh, it ate it.
Ah, you're right. It's quite the gourmand.
Geez...
Is that a tooth-mark?
Well, well. It has a special flavor.
What's wrong, Takashi-kun?
Ah, no, I kind of burned myself.
I'm glad they can't see them.
Natsume-dono, I'd like you to return my name.
Sure thing.
Oh? Now that I've had a good look, aren't you the old Dew God?
You know him?
Yeah. He's grown quite small, so I couldn't tell at first.
Oh, that voice!
Ah, I know! You're Madara, aren't you?
What's with your silly na–
Be quiet! I'll swallow you up!
All right. Let's begin, then.
One who would protect me, show your name.
So this is it.
Huh? It's stuck to the next one.
You're right, they're completely stuck together.
Looks like a grain of rice.
A grain of rice?
Reiko was a really sloppy gal.
She was probably playing with it while she was eating.
Come on...
Don't force it apart!
My skin feels all tingly!
I told you, didn't I, Natsume?
If their names get torn apart, so will their bodies.
If you burn it, they'll turn to ashes.
That's right.
Sorry, Dew God.
That scared me.
Well, that's how it is, so please give up.
What?
Takashi-kun! The bath is ready!
Okay!
How cruel!
Well, I can't return your name if I can't take them apart, can I?
Please do something about it, Natsume-dono.
Return my name! Please!
You're asking the impossible.
Natsume-dono!
The Dew God lives in the Seven Forests, right ahead.
Well, I brought it because you told me to,
but what is it used for?
It's a precaution. Just put it away.
Oh, thank you.
Ah, it's nothing.
Here you go.
Thank you for your kindness.
If it isn't bruised, please have it.
I can't eat it all by myself.
Thank you. I'll keep it, then.
The weather is great, isn't it?
Ah, I guess.
Excuse me, then.
I wish I could say more thoughtful things at times like this.
I hate being a poor speaker.
That old lady doesn't have much longer.
She didn't give off much of a delicious smell.
Don't be so rude.
This is the Dew God's place?
What's with the weird face?
The Dew God is a real god? And not just a name?
You came, Natsume-dono?
Damn, I was rude to him last night!
He'll curse me!
And Reiko-san, why'd you do something that'll get you cursed?
Oh? What's wrong?
He's in a panic because he believes you're a real god.
A-Ah, Dew God-sama!
No, no!
I'm called a god,
but I'm just a wanderer that settled in this small shrine.
A long time ago, there was a long drought in this area.
Distressed by the disaster, the young villagers prayed at this small shrine.
And on the following day, it happened to rain.
Ever since then, the villagers would worship the Dew God,
and would leave many offerings.
And before I realized it, I was overflowing with power,
and my form became just as grand.
Grand, huh?
The last time I met you, you were as tall as a human.
Now I barely come up to their feet.
And just as my body grew because of people's faith in me,
I have diminished in size like this due to the lack of it.
I see.
Should I offer you a peach, then?
I already have a peach.
Right here.
I see, it was her.
You met Hana-san?
Yeah.
So her name is Hana.
She is the sole person to come here and worship me now.
I see. Together, huh?
Yeah.
If I return the name stuck to yours, I won't have to force them apart.
However, one problem came up.
We don't know the other youkai.
In that case, I know him.
Really?
After losing to Reiko, I was really frustrated.
After hearing that the next youkai's name was taken,
I went to see him to gloat.
All right, it's done.
I may have forgotten his name, but he was like this.
Is this really him?
Yes, it's drawn quite well if I say so myself.
Did he have any hair?
He... didn't have any.
Not even one strand?
Not one strand.
He happens to live at Sannozuka.
He's also the god of shadows and moves by walking among them.
What? What is it?
H-Hey! Why are you laughing?
Are you making fun of my drawing?
San
You damned, accursed fools!
Natsume Yuujinchou
And so, our youkai search began at Sannozuka.
But after spending several days searching for him,
we were unable to find him.
San
Hey, you look sleepy.
Tired from all the searching?
Yeah.
That's right, Hana-san can't see him.
Even though he's within breath's reach.
Oh!
Hello.
Did you come to pray too?
Ah, yeah.
That's great.
It seemed like I was the only one coming recently.
I was thinking that the Dew God was lonely.
When did you start worshipping him?
Ever since I was a kid.
Promise you won't laugh, okay?
I think that I saw the Dew God once.
I was on my way back from girls' school.
The weather was just like today's, too.
I came to pray just as I always do, and when I raised my face,
I saw a leg behind the shrine.
I was surprised, but I pretended not to notice.
I then saw a person wearing an old man's mask, who was in quite a good mood.
"The weather is great today," he said.
I almost replied without thinking, "Yes, you're right."
But I felt that if a human saw him, the Dew God would disappear.
But even now, I think to myself that it would've been better if I had replied.
The Dew God is always alone, right?
I don't think I'd be able to handle being alone.
So, I thought I should at least talk to him.
He's always alone, right?
Alone...
Being alone is lonely.
Being alone is painful.
Being alone...
is painful...
It's painful...
It's heavy...
Don't sleepwalk!
You had a nightmare last night, didn't you?
You were heavy!
You had an opening in your mind.
Weak minds invite spirits.
If you don't want to lose your life,
you should never let your guard down.
Well, if you lose your life quickly,
I'll be able to get my hands on the Book of Friends fast and be happy.
The next time you sleepwalk, I'll pull out the fur on your tail.
You're a demon.
I don't want to be told that by a youkai.
I found him, Natsume-dono!
Are you sure?
Yeah, he really was on this mountain.
I called for him, but he ran away.
He couldn't have gone too far, though.
Sensei, let's split up!
Hold up.
What's wrong?
Something bad is coming.
Something bad?
I have come.
That was him!
He appeared from over there!
He looks nothing like your picture!
Don't be stupid, it was the spitting image of him!
The only thing that's the same is the character!
Natsume, use the mirror.
Reflect the sunlight and blind him!
I see!
Sensei!
I have come.
Nasume-dono!
I have come to get food.
I have come.
Hey.
How about fighting me?
If you beat me, I'll give you food.
Or you could eat me.
I'm Reiko.
What's your name?
I got it!
His name is...
I have come.
Natsume!
Susugi, Dew God, I return your names!
Are you listening, Dew God?
I am Reiko.
They won't always be bringing offerings, you know.
You didn't even get one peach today.
Ah, you're right.
People are cruel and only care for themselves.
You should find a better home while you have power.
Thank you, Reiko.
But once you are loved,
and once you have loved, you cannot forget it.
Natsume!
Is it okay for you to walk now?
[Note: "Susugi" - to wash.]
That Susugi youkai would walk along the shadows to go to the village,
and in exchange for receiving food scraps, he would wash that house's dishes.
Oh, so you looked it up.
These days, the city is bright even during the night,
so we might not see him anymore.
He has friends on the mountain.
I'm sure he's glad to have cut his ties with humans.
You think?
I hope that's true, then.
I brought you some peaches, Dew God.
Dew God?
I'm here, Natsume-dono.
You got smaller again.
Yeah.
You're glowing? What's wrong?
Well, Hana-san has left.
Hana-san had been sick for a long time,
and it took everything she had to come here recently.
She was the last human to have worshipped me.
So, once she dies, I will disappear.
I'll... I'll worship you!
Even if it's impossible, I'll come pray every day!
You can't.
You are my friend, Natsume-dono.
This is fine.
I can go with Hana-san.
I've always...
I've always done nothing but watch her.
But now...
Now, I feel like I'll be able to touch her.
She heard you.
She heard your voice, Dew God.
Thank you, Natsume-dono.
Humans have been such charming creatures in the past, and even now.
The weather is great today.
Yes, you're right.
What's wrong, Natsume?
Hey, what are you doing?! What a waste!
Don't say things that'll get you cursed.
There's nothing here!
Not today, but there may be something tomorrow.
What's important is a caring heart.
What are you doing, you stupid cat?
That's "fortune cat" to you, you idiot!
Meow!
What do you mean "Meow"?
Give me back the steamed buns!
Hey!
Hold it, you steamed bun thief!
They're mine!
I'm the one that bought them!
Hey, hold it!
No way!
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Mysterious Person at the Eight Fields
Hey, Natsume.
The youkai from the Eight Fields are
crying because some human got them.
Which means someone who can see youkai did it?
He seems kind of suspicious.
Who are you?
I'm Tanuma Kaname.