There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Why are you going through Reiko's belongings?
Looking for something?
No, not really.
Just looking.
Just looking?
Like always, I just don't get you.
You've got some on you.
Seeds.
On the sides of your mouth.
Two of them.
Don't worry about them, they're just there.
I don't get you.
When I return the names back to the youkai,
Reiko-san's memories become my own thoughts,
and flow into me.
And little by little, Reiko-san...
It's a book borrowed from the library.
It looks like she forgot to return it, though.
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
A ticket?
Heart-Colored Ticket
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Natsume!
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Moriguchi to Kiraganuma
Valid only on issued date
3rd Class, 40 yen
Listen, Natsume!
Who do you think is wrong?
This guy says that he eats the kitsune first in kitsune udon!
Can you believe that?
Of course you should eat it first!
What are you talking about?
The kitsune must be put at the bottom of the soup and eaten last!
Isn't that right, Natsume?
No! You should eat the kitsune before it absorbs the soup!
Right, Natsume?
W-Well, I think that either way is fine.
No!
The kitsune must be eaten later!
It should be first!
Well, before arguing any more, I don't think it should be called "kitsune."
That doesn't matter!
Sorry.
Later!
First!
Hey, stop it!
We're through!
Yeah, fine by me!
H-Hey!
What a silly fight.
Here. You dropped this, right?
This is an old ticket, right?
What's up with it?
Nothing really.
What does it have to do with you?
It seems to have some kind of history.
That's not it.
I picked it up on my way to school this morning.
You're terrible at telling lies.
I'm telling you, it's nothing.
I'll ask for all the details later.
Natsume-kun.
There's no point in running.
Ah, no, I wasn't running away.
Where are you going?
Where?
Home.
You're going to the station on that ticket, aren't you?
I'll go with you.
Where's the station, again?
I couldn't see it well earlier, so I forgot.
Is it close?
Why do you want to go so much, Sasada?
A-Ah, well...
That's right! After that test of courage the other day, I've wanted to see a real one up close!
See what?
See what? Isn't it obvious?
Hey, look, the bus is here.
Come on, let's get on.
Hey, you dropped something.
That.
What did I drop?
Nothing was dropped.
Look harder.
I am.
It's right there.
Where?
H-Hey, wait!
Wait!
It's gone...
And what are you saying that I droppe–
He's gone...
You're finally here. You're late, you know.
Nyanko-sensei.
This place isn't being used anymore.
Yeah.
They say that it was abandoned quite a while ago.
Quite a desolate place, huh?
Yeah.
I guess Kiriganuma is over there.
But still, why did Reiko–
A youkai...
How can he sleep in this heat?
R-Reiko...
It's Reiko! You finally came!
No, I'm...
Hey, you've got it wrong!
He's not Reiko!
You're not?
You really are Reiko!
No, I'm not Reiko!
Do something, Sensei!
It's pointless to say anything to him now.
He's not evil, so just play with him a bit.
W-What are you–
Reiko!
Sensei!
I see.
So Reiko died.
I'm glad you understand.
He's her grandson, after all.
There's nothing strange about them having the same smell.
You don't need to smell me.
So, furball, you said you were waiting for Reiko.
Did you have a promise with her or something?
Yeah, she said she'd go with me.
Together?
Where?
Kiriganuma.
Reiko-san was supposed to go with you to Kiriganuma?
Yeah, Kiriganuma.
But, why?
Well, Mikuri was all pouting,
and said, "I can't forgive you!"
And then Reiko said, "No," and "Later."
I guess it's impossible to have him explain.
He's probably in the Book of Friends.
If you return his name, I'm sure the thoughts will explain it all.
I see.
What's your name?
My name?
I'm Santo.
Santo.
One who would protect me, show your name.
So you had a fight.
Yeah.
Mikuri was the one who got angry, though.
And you like that youkai Mikuri, don't you?
I love Mikuri!
But Mikuri said that he hates me,
and that he doesn't want to see me again.
Did you do something bad?
So you don't remember?
Then why is Mikuri so angry with you?
I sort of understand why Mikuri is angry now.
What should I do, Reiko?
Where is he right now?
At Kiriganuma.
Kiriganuma?
The place by the next station?
Yeah.
All right.
I'll go with you, then.
Just leave it to me!
The sun is already setting today,
so let's meet here again tomorrow.
Thank you, Reiko!
That tickles!
Hey, Santo!
But she couldn't keep her promise.
I'm sure there was some reason why she couldn't come.
Do you plan on going?
He might not be waiting anymore.
We won't know unless we go.
I'm going.
I want to do what Reiko-san left behind.
The sun is already setting, though.
I'll come by after school tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Okay, we'll go right now.
You're an idiot, making promises without thinking things through.
There aren't any buses that pass by Kiriganuma.
How long do you think it'll take to walk there?
The sun will set by then for sure.
It looks like there's no point in persuading you.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Hey, Santo.
If Reiko couldn't come, couldn't you have gone by yourself?
Why did you wait all this time?
Because I made a promise!
I was an idiot to ask.
It's getting chilly.
The mountain winds are coming down.
Hey, Santo.
Hey!
Well, these kinds of people can be seen as charming or annoying.
Santo.
What are you going to say when you see Mikuri?
What? You haven't thought about it?
If you want to make up, you have to say something.
Say something?
Maybe it's better if they don't meet.
It might just be troublesome once he's back.
Well, we can't do that.
Santo.
Think of something to say before we get there.
Okay!
Here!
I don't want it!
This is...
An earthquake?
I sense malice.
Malice?
Santo!
Unforgivable! Unforgivable!
Natsume!
Sensei!
Grab on!
Sensei, what was that?
It was after Santo.
Why?
Mikuri seems to be possessed by the earth spirits.
By the earth spirits?
They feed off of anger and hatred.
Mikuri!
Did Mikuri hate Santo that much?
It'd be safer if we don't go and see him.
What do you want to do, Natsume?
Mikuri!
Let's go.
I don't care what happens, then.
Go, Nyanko-sensei!
Damn idiot!
It's cold.
It's almost like it's not even summer.
It's not the mountain winds.
It must be because of the malice.
Mikuri! Come on out!
Mikuri!
We need to talk!
Santo, what does Mikuri look like?
Um...
He's small.
Small?
How small?
Is he that small?
About that small?
This is no time to be joking around.
Something's here, Natsume!
Be careful!
Show yourself!
A catfish?
Mikuri...
That's Mikuri?
He's huge!
What do you want to do, Natsume?
Want to talk to him?
Who do you think I am?
Sensei!
You're Natsume Reiko, aren't you?
Thank you for coming.
Give me the Book of Friends.
I see, the Book of Friends is in there.
What are you doing?
This is Reiko's!
Hand it over, you fool!
Mikuri!
Mikuri! It's me! Santo!
I'm sorry! Please, come to your senses!
Come back, Mikuri! Please!
Santo...
Give me the Book of Friends!
No! I won't!
Give it!
He did it.
Are you okay, Natsume?
Yeah.
Here.
Thanks.
Where's Mikuri?
It's sad, but he disappeared along with the earth spirits to the bottom of the swamp.
Santo...
Geez, what's going on?
Santo! What are you doing?
Mikuri!
Hey, what are you doing, you idiot!? Let go!
Hey, stop!
Mikuri!
Stop!
This is creepy, so let go!
I said let go!
You had a fight because of Reiko?
Yeah, Natsume Reiko.
What do you mean by that?
His name.
He gave his precious name to Reiko.
That's why I got angry.
Don't you have any pride as an youkai, you big fool?
I didn't want to see your face again!
And then you just show up like it's nothing!
You useless fool!
Sorry!
Hey, you don't have to say it like that.
He's been worrying about it the entire time because he likes you.
That's why he's an idiot!
If you're going to apologize, then get lost!
You're always spacing out!
Sorry!
Hey, Mikuri.
Observe, Natsume.
Hey, are you listening, furball?
I'm talking to you!
I'm sorry!
They already made up a long time ago.
Mikuri, let's go back to the mountains!
I'd go back even if you didn't tell me to, idiot!
Thank you so much, Natsume!
Fool! Don't bow your head to a human!
But he returned my name.
Thank you!
I told you not to lower your head, you idiot!
What? Just going through it again?
Just putting it back to where it was.
You said Reiko couldn't keep her promise because she had some special reason, right?
You're giving her too much credit.
She just forgot.
That's the kind of person she was.
That can't be true.
Then what about that book?
It's there because she forgot to return it?
These are...
Ah, it looks like she forgot quite a few things.
She must have had some really special reasons.
Reiko-san...
Morning.
M-Morning.
Hey, have a look at that.
They made up.
What was up with yesterday, then?
I just don't get it.
Yeah.
It must be because they're friends.
That's right!
How was it yesterday?
Oh, right, I remember now.
Sorry, take this for a second.
Natsume-kun?
Sasada.
Do you eat the shrimp in tempura noodles first or last?
Which?
It doesn't matter which!
Friends, huh?
Yo.
Thanks for yesterday.
You looked troubled.
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Swallow at the Water Bottom
A village submerged by a dam shows itself.
The youkai that live there come to have their names returned.
Hey, all of you! Don't hang on to Natsume!
There's someone I want to see.
I'll be troubling you for a while.
Someone you want to see?