There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
It completely dried up.
It was a pretty dry season this year.
I guess we can't go fishing, then.
That's amazing.
Look, Natsume.
Ah, it's the village that was submerged because of the dam.
It's the village of Futaba.
There's someone there.
Look, by that house's window.
Come on, Natsume, there can't possibly be anyone there.
I-I guess you're right.
They can't see it?
Then it's a...
Natsume!
What's wrong, Natsume?
Hey, Natsume!
Are you all right?
The Swallow at the Water Bottom
A dream?
So you got dizzy?
What a weakling.
Shut up, Nyanko-sensei.
You...
What is it?
Hello? Anybody home?
There's a lot of you.
My name is Tarusaru.
I presume you're Natsume-dono?
That's right.
We've been asleep underwater along with the village,
so we came to have our names returned.
Underwater?
You mean that dammed-up village?
Yes. When it's filled with water, we can't go above ground as easily.
Now is our chance to move about, though,
and so we followed you.
Takashi-kun? Have you woken up?
Oh my, you didn't even turn on the light.
Touko-san.
Sorry for causing you trouble.
Don't worry about it.
The doctor said it was just a slight heatstroke.
Do you think you can eat dinner?
Yes, I'll be down soon.
There you have it.
Sorry, but could you come back later tonight?
Yes.
That was the last one.
I-I'm so tired...
Damned fool, returning it so easily.
The Book of Friends has gotten thinner again!
Thank you very much, Natsume-dono.
To demonstrate my thanks, I shall show you my magic mirror.
There is something possessing you.
I knew it! I thought you smelled strange.
Could it be from that time?
How dare it touch my property?
All right, I'll exorcise it.
Well done.
Damned bastard, I won't let go!
I won't let go of this child!
Forgive me.
I cannot leave the bottom of the dam by myself,
so I possessed you when you passed by.
There's someone I must meet!
Even if it's just a glance from a distance...
A human you must meet?
So it's not about the Book of Friends?
So, Natsume-sama, I will be troubling you for a while.
We refuse!
I'm not asking you.
Just shut up, you old fogey.
What?
In what way do I look like an old fogey?
You're a lowly youkai, and you're trying to act all strong!
And look at your belly! Don't doubt my fashion sense!
I don't want to hear that from someone with a weird mask on!
All right, I'll help you already.
So, you don't have any clues?
None, other than that he once lived in Futaba and that his name is Taniozaki.
Futaba village...
That village?
So, how many years ago was the village submerged?
Twenty years ago.
Eh? Taniozaki from Futaba?
You know him, Sasada?
No, not in the slightest.
I guess I have to prepare for a long battle.
My dad was from Futaba.
That was gross, Natsume-kun!
Ah, sorry.
Is what you said true, Kitamoto?
Yeah.
Most of the residents of Futaba moved here.
I'll ask my dad for you.
I don't really understand the feeling of wanting to see someone,
but you must be glad.
Yes.
Do you have any siblings, Natsume-sama?
No.
I see.
What about you? Do you have any?
Yes, four of them.
But everyone died because of me.
Natsume-sama, can I hold your hand?
You're so kind, Natsume-sama.
That's why you got possessed.
I don't want to hear you say that.
You have cold hands.
Yes.
No, that's not it.
I wanted to say that they're cold, and it feels good.
Natsume-sama, it's going to rain.
I can tell.
A bird that can predict rain?
I see. You used to be a swallow?
Yes.
I came to pick you up, Natsume!
What are you two doing? Are you kids?
Shut up.
Very long ago, I was once a young bird.
Our nest fell,
but then some humans found the nest and returned it to its place.
However, our parents came to hate us because we smelled like humans,
and so they left and abandoned us.
My siblings died one by one,
and I was left alone.
I was very sad...
And then...
I...
became a spirit.
But one day,
a human appeared and gave me food.
And he would come day after day...
He probably mistook me for a stray dog.
But the scent of humans he carried reminded me of the ones who had found us.
When the village was being submerged,
I was able to sleep peacefully thanks to him.
I see.
How silly.
Na-tsu-me.
Here.
It's Taniozaki's address, the one you talked about the other day.
Thanks, Kitamoto!
I can smell him.
He's close!
Why?
Why can I only see them?
She's so... She's so...
Why do I see them?
Natsume Yuujinchou
Thank you, Natsume-sama.
It was like a dream.
I have no more regrets.
I will go back to Futaba.
If you like him so much,
you don't have to go home.
There were actually times I thought about possessing you,
and telling him, "You damned, impertinent human!"
But I want to sleep in the same land as my siblings.
I see.
Natsume-sama.
Thank you very much, Natsume-sama.
You still have time until the village submerges again, right?
We found who she was looking for,
but I feel like her wish to meet him hasn't been granted.
Have I become attached to her?
It's him!
Hey!
Natsume-sama,
I'm a bit tired today.
Is it okay if I go rest?
Sure, good night.
She's probably getting weaker.
The swallows signaled that her time to remain in that form had lessened.
Why are you here again?
The Futaba Festival is tonight,
so I brought some sake.
The Futaba Festival?
Yes.
Futaba Village lies on the vague boundaries of darkness,
and youkai gather there once a year to hold a festival.
And so while the lake is dry, I thought I'd attend it, since it's been a while.
We'd drink, dance, gamble, and race!
[ Note: A yukata is a Japanese summer garment ]
And the winner will receive a yukata that will make them appear to be human for a night.
In the literal sense, I'm in a feverish mood for the festival!
What did you say just now?
A feverish mood!
No, the yukata that makes you appear to be human!
Oh? Are you interested in it?
Would you like to go, Natsume-dono?
Where are you going?
Nyanko-sensei.
To the Futaba Festival.
What'd you say?
You'll be eaten if you go to that festival!
You're Madara? Don't get in my way!
You were going to have Natsume as a snack with your sake, weren't you?
What's wrong with eating people?
You're a real fool to have become attached to them, Madara.
I'm the one who's going to eat him!
He promised me, fool!
I didn't promise that!
The story about the yukata wasn't a lie, right?
Could you take me, Sensei?
What'd you say?
You're going to do something troublesome again?
Why would you do it for her?
This won't benefit you at all, Natsume-dono. So, why?
Why?
Because I've become attached to her!
What's so wrong about doing something for a friend?
Damned fool! Damned, stupid fool!
This is why I hate kids!
Shut up!
There you go.
I have mixed my blood with the ink,
so no one will notice that you're a human.
Why are you doing all this?
Because it's interesting.
More interesting than eating you.
The one who touches the yukata first without using their power is the winner.
It's about to begin.
Take care.
So, you'll be staying behind in this village?
Even though it's going to be submerged?
Everyone has something that's hard to leave behind.
I see.
Thank you, Tarusaru.
He truly is similar to Natsume Reiko.
However, Reiko didn't talk as much.
It's begun.
He won't be able to win with his short arms and legs.
You got it. He's so stupid, I can't handle it.
Sensei!
Let's go, Natsume!
Where?
Where is he?
Will he come again today?
Tsubame.
Wake up, Tsubame.
Natsume-sama?
I'm happy you came back early.
It will rain later tonight.
Tsubame.
Taniozaki-san is at the neighborhood festival right now.
Wear this and go.
This yukata is...
Your powers are weak, Tsubame, so I'm not sure if you'll be able to talk to him,
but if you still want to, then go on.
Natsume-sama...
Tsubame, thank you for not hating people.
I love kind people!
I love warm people, too!
That's why I love people!
Natsume-sama...
Thank you, thank you!
I'm going now, Natsume-sama!
I'm going now!
And just as Tsubame said, it rained later that night.
I wonder if Tsubame returned to her village.
It's easy for those who are tied to the land to return to it.
She might even have gone to heaven.
I hope so.
Did you meet him?
Good night, Tsubame.
Sweet dreams.
Geez! I just can't keep up with you, Natsume.
But you'll stay with me until the end, right?
Does that mean I can eat you?
I wonder if you'll become attached to me one day.
What about you?
Who knows?
A girl wearing a flower-patterned yukata?
Yes.
At the neighborhood festival the other day.
Oh, that girl.
I met her, a quiet girl in a blue yukata.
I see, that's great.
I know, want to have a look?
I just got the photos from back then developed.
Here.
Yeah,
I love them too.
Kind people.
Warm people.
I love people who pursue things they're attracted to and want to live earnestly.
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The little Fox's Hat
Mom, I met someone really strong and cool today!
I wonder if he's alone as well?
If he is, I wish he could live in the forest with me.
All right, let's go to the city!
Let's go see, Natsume!