There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Try to act like a real cat, Sensei.
Geez, why do we have to go so far?
What are you talking about?
You've gotten fat recently, so I'm taking you on a walk.
Oh? Is it an earthquake?
It's gotten cooler, so my fur just sticks out more.
It's a grasshopper! A grasshopper!
The grasshopper's moving! The grasshopper!
Ah, geez...
Sorry, I was kind of dozing off.
Are you all right?
Y-Yes.
I see, that's good.
A tattoo?
Th-Thanks.
Natori-san! The break's over!
Okay, I'm coming!
Wasn't that Natori Shuuichi?
Natori Shuuichi? Who's that?
Come on, he's the actor who recently became popular.
Don't you know him?
That was surprising.
I thought Sensei disguised himself for a moment.
First you'll have an argument, and then...
Natori... Shuuichi...
Ayakashi Exorcism
A rope?
Is it tied to her?
She's a youkai, right?
Hey, your bandages are coming apart.
Want me to tie them back up for you?
You're just a human, so don't talk to me.
Idiot, don't just talk to them without giving it any thought, Natsume.
Yeah.
That's right.
Why am I calling out to them?
Liar!
Natsume-kun, why do you keep making up all these creepy lies?
Why can't I at least forget about what happened recently?
Huh? Where's Sensei?
Gone
drinking
Again?
What is that?
Let go!
This is...
Are you all right?
He saw me?
No, it's not like he could see that thing just now.
I'm all right. It was nothing, so you don't need to worry.
You...
You could see the thing just now?
I can see them too.
See them?
See what?
Let's see...
Probably the ones called youkai.
No way...
Just who are you?
Huh? You can't tell?
We met once this afternoon.
I'm Natori. Natori Shuuichi.
I tested you, and it seems you can see them.
And your power seems to be quite strong.
Sorry, I'm getting too excited.
I was just so happy.
You and I are the same.
Th-The same?
I'm going now.
Ah, wait, Takashi-kun!
You forgot your lunch.
Ah, shoot!
What's wrong? You seem out of it this morning.
No, it's nothing.
I'm going to go now.
And finally, the sisters brought the corpse that no one else would take to the gate.
You and I are the same.
The same?
He said he tested me. Was he teasing me or something?
Hey, Natsume.
You okay?
Tanuma... Yeah, I'm okay.
Get it together!
Damn it, how can I be so confused like this?
Hey, doesn't that person by the gate look like the actor Natori Shuuichi?
Ah, you're right, he kind of does.
It's Natori Shuuichi.
You know him?
Hey, don't make fun of me.
Even I watch some TV.
But, well, if I had to say, he's the type that I wouldn't like.
Walk further away from me.
Why?
I don't like standing out.
I'm sorry for being so fabulous.
I just want to have a talk.
So, could you come with me for a bit?
So, you're really human.
Your aura was kind of weird, so I thought you might have been a youkai.
What do you want?
Would you like to help me with my job?
Your job? Do you mean your TV one?
No, my side job.
I actually work as an exorcist too.
An exorcist?
I've been wanting an assistant.
I'm sure you'll learn a lot from it, so how about it?
No thanks.
How selfish.
Is it the money? Do you want money?
I'm leaving.
I'm just joking!
You're so quick-tempered.
Huh? Did that tattoo look like that?
The tattoo moved!
Ah, amazing!
You can see this too?
This birthmark moves all around my body.
Birthmark?
When I was young, I noticed that I had a birthmark around my ankle.
The next day, I thought it had disappeared,
but it had moved to my left arm.
It was pretty creepy.
After looking it up, I found out that it was a youkai.
I learned a lot while trying to find a way to get rid of it.
It was all self-study, though.
Does it have any effect on you?
Not really, so I just left it.
It actually eats your life-span or something...
This person has been fighting alone under all that uneasiness.
That's nothing to laugh about!
Master.
Who is this precocious little brat?
Ah, is something wrong?
I think he has anemia.
Sorry, but could you bring some water?
Yes!
Hey, hey, don't act on your own.
He's my precious friend.
I won't allow you to be rude to him.
You're the rude one.
Don't speak so friendly to my prey, brat.
Sensei!
What's that odd creature?
Sir, we can't have you bringing in a cat!
S-Sorry!
Natsume Yuujinchou
He's so funny, no matter how many times I look!
What is he?
A-Ah, he's my cat.
Cat?
No, I lied.
Nyanko-sensei isn't actually a cat.
Thanks. I see.
You've got a cute follower.
I'm not his follower! I'm his master, you greenhorn!
Bastard! What are you doing to my master, you fat cat?
What'd you say, frizzy?!
Hey, hold it.
Stop!
FAT
CAT
FRIZZY
Stop!
Allow me to introduce you.
On my right is Sasago, and on my left is Urihime.
They're youkai that serve me.
I have a job from a certain old family.
They have a "forbidden" cellar that supposedly curses you if you open it.
They needed money, so they called for a pawner.
The pawner opened the cellar with the key he kept and went in with the family head to have a look.
Ever since then, the pawner would have nightmares every night,
be in accidents, and have bad luck.
Is it the doing of a youkai?
That's what these two say after looking into it.
Ever since their ancestors locked away their valuables in order to save up,
a youkai began to live in the cellar and deny entrance to humans.
What a troublemaker.
They're always so irrational and such an annoyance.
I'm not so sure.
You can't say anything unless you know their circumstances.
You're a nice kid.
You're on the youkai's side?
That attitude is...
So you wear glasses, Natori-san.
These are fake.
It's easier to see youkai through glasses or mirrors instead of the naked eye.
It's like a bracelet.
That's the first time I've seen you smile.
I guess this birthmark is useful at times.
You're a nice kid.
You're just a nice kid.
So...
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
Sorry.
I'll be at the pawner's employer's house tomorrow.
I'll be waiting for you there.
I didn't say I'd help you yet.
Natsume.
Hand over the Book of Friends!
There's something in that thicket.
I have to get away or Natori-san will get involved.
I'll be going now.
I told you, you don't need to keep any secrets.
Hand it over!
Stop it already! He's wounded!
What are you saying?
He's after you.
It's okay now.
You're naive.
You cannot let them hurt people.
Is this what you do to exorcise youkai?
Hurting them is going too far!
You should understand, since youkai have made you suffer.
But I can't approve of this method!
If you have that kind of annoying mindset, it'll come right back to bite you.
Even so, this is a method I can approve.
Thank you for saving me.
Even though I finally met someone who can see the same things,
is it too hard to understand each other?
We both suffered through the same things too.
I could see the hate he had for youkai when I touched him for a moment.
Despite what he says, he must've gone through a lot with them.
Without anyone believing in him.
This rope...
Stop it, boy.
Ah, sorry.
Who put this rope on you?
You have his smell.
His?
It's been on my mind, so could you let me fix your bandages?
You can ignore me when I finish.
A...
A long time ago, a shaman tied this rope to me.
I used to be a mountain guardian,
but I was caught, tied to that pole, and ordered to protect this family and cellar.
So you were always here.
There was someone who opened the cellar recently.
If I don't fulfill my duty, this rope will constrict and my head will fall off.
Her nails...
I tried to run away once,
but I eventually gave up.
I gave up and just sat here alone in a daze...
For years and years...
Hey, what's wrong?
What a strange mask.
Your hands are bleeding.
It was a human child.
Like you, he could see me.
He tied this for me.
When the cellar opened, I thought it would've been okay to not fulfill my duty and to have my head fall off.
I had no regrets.
But fate is a funny thing.
That child has come back to this city as an exorcist.
I would be happy to be a service to that child.
Yin and Yang are so troublesome.
I can't even thank him for this single strip of cloth.
Hey, I thought you wouldn't come.
Rip up the paper there and cover up the characters on the ground.
Do you know the youkai you're exorcising today, Natori-san?
Yeah, it's an enslaved youkai with a rope around its neck.
It should be exorcised.
Natori-san doesn't remember her.
I have to stop her from coming here!
Where are you going?
I can't have you interfering.
Just stay still.
Natori-san!
It's coming.
Stop, Natori-san!
Stop, child.
You can't do anything, so stop.
Stop!
Hurry up and get out!
I can't stop the spell!
Sensei...
Hey, what's wrong?
What a strange mask.
Your hand is bleeding.
When I fell, my mom treated me this way.
My mom isn't around anymore, though.
She had a weak body.
The old men say I called forth bad luck because I can see weird things.
But if so, someone should've just gotten rid of me before that happened.
You talk a lot, child.
I'm not a child, I'm Shuuichi.
You know, human children do not have the power to call forth bad luck.
Really?
You're a nice child.
You're just a nice child.
Because I was so happy...
Just to meet you...
I didn't realize it.
It was that youkai.
The curse on her neck has been lifted.
I thought the chances would be 50/50.
If it was a helpless youkai that couldn't be freed from its curse,
I wanted to let them go in peace.
And if it had gone well, then perhaps the rope would've burned off and it'd be free.
I'm glad you saved her.
I'm sorry though, Natsume.
I didn't want to get you involved like this.
When I look at you, it reminds me of my old self,
and I thought I could teach you something.
I just wanted to talk.
Yeah, me too.
Well, I can't have someone reckless like you as my assistant.
Really? That's unfortunate.
You're not cute at all.
What about you? Why did you become so peevish?
You were such a pure child.
What'd you say?
Even if you call me naive, I can't approve of your methods.
That's fine too.
We don't need to have the same opinion on everything.
Understanding others is a difficult thing.
For everyone, you see.
If you're ever in trouble, you can call me anytime.
I want to be helpful to my friend too.
That youkai girl is finally free,
yet she was given the name Hiiragi and is going to serve Natori.
It seems to be her own will, though.
Maybe she's fallen for him.
Well, there are times when only they themselves know what makes them happy.
Yeah.
That's right.
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Asagi's Koto
Human child, please lend me your body for a while.
No way!
That's right, he's mine!
Since when was I yours, Sensei?
Please let me play the koto one more time.
Please, I don't have much time left.