There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Where is she?
Where did she go?
Where is she? Where is that woman?
Where is she? Where did she go?
Where did that woman go?
The Cat and The Book of Friends
If you want a part-time job, then you should work at the beach! At a beach house!
Ah, the beach, huh?
Maybe I'll meet someone.
That could happen! It'll happ–
Natsume?
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
Nothing.
Nothing?
You're all muddy.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Hey, is there a shrine nearby?
I think there's a shrine once you pass through those bushes there.
Thanks.
Hey, Natsume!
What's up with him?
Why's he in such a hurry?
What was that?
That was some crazy wind.
He's a strange guy, huh?
He hasn't talked much ever since he transferred.
He's kind of hard to talk to.
"What are you doing," huh?
I'm jealous that you can't see them.
Wait!
Ever since I was small, I would sometimes see strange things.
They were probably the ones called youkai.
They were never really friendly,
but ever since I moved here,
there have been some who randomly pick fights, and it's been quite problematic.
When that happens, and if I run away to a shrine–
I've got you.
I've finally got you, Reiko!
Reiko?
Now, return it.
Come now, return it!
Wait.
Just wait, it'll be a bother if your name is called.
Pull out her tongue so that she can't call your name.
Her tongue?
That hurts!
Ow!
Fool, she got away!
Cursed human!
Why does this always happen?
It's not like I want to see them.
Ah, Takashi-kun?
We only need three plates.
But...
We need one for our guest over there.
The child was saying some strange things again today.
He just wants attention. He's lonely.
You think so?
He's kind of creepy.
Look, right over there.
Where?
There's nothing there, Takashi-kun.
Something is  there! Look carefully!
Look, right over there!
It's right there! It's looking right at us.
It's there!
It's really there...
I'm sorry, I can't see it.
Don't tell me this is a...
It's been broken.
The barrier that sealed me has been broken!
Barrier?
Oh, no!
I-It's not working...
What should I do?
You're quite a precious human, to not bumble at the sight of me!
Say something.
I'm used to it.
Impudent brat.
Oh?
Aren't you Natsume Reiko?
I've got you, Reiko!
Reiko...
What? You're not?
Natsume Reiko was my grandmother's name.
Grandmother? What, you're her grandson?
I see. If I look carefully, you're a man.
You don't need to look carefully to discern that I'm a man.
Unlike humans, we do not particularly concern ourselves with gender.
You knew my grandmother?
Yes, she lived near here.
She was quite the beautiful human.
And just like you, she was able to see youkai.
However, the humans around her could not.
No one was able to understand Reiko.
She was always alone.
She was always, always alone.
Alone...
And so...
Reiko began to confront the youkai.
Do you know of the Book of Friends?
The Book of Friends?
Oh yeah, it was my grandmother's...
He vanished.
Oh, welcome back, Takashi-kun.
Touko-san, I'm home.
What's wrong? Your face is all pale.
Are you feeling sick?
Ah, no, I'm fine.
Your uniform is all muddy.
What happened?
No, I just fell.
Fell? Where?
Are you injured? Does it hurt anywhere?
I'm fine. Sorry for making you worry.
I'm really fine.
That's good, then.
If something happens, just tell me. You don't need to hold back.
Okay, thank you.
Being naughty is fine, but keep it to a minimum, okay?
Okay.
I can't tell Touko-san that I was being chased by youkai.
I don't want her to be creeped out.
Having lost my parents early, I moved from place to place among my relatives.
We weren't related by blood.
But I have been living with people who are somehow connected to me.
I began to live in this house last month.
My grandmother also lived on this land once.
She passed away, but like me, she had the power to see things that others couldn't.
And because of it, she was shunned by others.
I'm sure it's somewhere among the things I inherited...
Is this what that fortune cat was talking about?
What is this?
Hand that over.
That's not something you should have.
Hand it over...
The Book of Friends!
Takashi-kun! What was that sound just now?
S-Sorry, it was nothing!
Really?
I'm going shopping for a bit, so watch the house, okay?
Okay, take care!
Hurry up and let me out!
Ah, give me the Book of Friends too!
Ah, no, no, no! Let me out first!
Hand me the Book of Friends after that!
I guess I'll leave him alone for a bit.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Leave after you eat that.
You freeload here?
Shut up, you're just a cat.
What do you mean, "Cat"? How rude!
This fortune cat form is not my true form!
My true form is quite elegant!
You're not a cat, then?
That's what I'm telling you.
You are a cat.
N-N-No!
My body is just used to this form!
Well, whatever. Just eat that quickly and leave.
I don't want any trouble.
No, I won't leave.
I know you have the Book of Friends.
I also owe you for breaking the barrier.
I'll be your bodyguard from now on, so call me "Sensei."
Bodyguard?
Is this that dangerous?
What, you don't know anything?
Within the Book of Friends are the names of the youkai that Natsume Reiko defeated.
Names?
Reiko challenged the youkai she met, one after the other.
Since she was born with immense spiritual power, she was undefeated.
And those who lost
were made to write their names on paper as proof of their subordination.
The Book of Friends is composed of those who wrote their names.
So they're the names of youkai?
It is said that they cannot defy
the one who holds the contracts and calls their names.
Basically, if you have the Book of Friends,
you are able to control the youkai linked with the names in it.
See? Dangerous, isn't it?
A seed.
It's stuck beside your mouth.
I see. So that's why you want this, Nyanko-sensei.
Ah, you idiot! Don't treat it so carelessly!
It is said that if you damage the characters, you'll hurt the one who has the name as well!
Oh, really?
Then does that mean you're in this too?
Like heck I am!
I'm just telling you how delicate it is!
Really?
What's with those eyes?
Do you think I'd lose to someone like Reiko?
Weren't you sealed away, though?
A-A-Ah, well, there are some meaningful reasons for that.
No! More importantly,
the Book of Friends' power is much more immense than you imagine.
That's why the youkai with their names in it are desperately searching for Natsume Reiko.
You're in danger.
Hello?
C-Coming!
Sorry, the person living here is away now.
So, you are here.
You came back, Reiko.
Hand me the Book of Friends!
Hello?
You... Return it!
Ah, geez...
Nyanko-sensei!
Where are you planning to go?
Where?
Hide in that bush.
Damn...
It's not something a human can manage.
You understand well now, don't you?
So, give it to me!
No.
Why? You're just a human. Do you plan to supersede the youkai?
Of course not.
Then what? What other purpose is there besides that for you?
It doesn't concern you.
I planned to wait until you changed your mind, but forget that.
Hand over the Book of Friends!
N-No.
You're the one who's going to use it for bad things, aren't you?
Of course! It's such an interesting object.
You're terrible...
Hurry up and hand it over!
If you don't, I'll crush you!
This is...
The Book of Friends is...
It's an important inheritance from my grandmother.
It's true that she couldn't get along with other people.
There are barely any people that remember her.
She died young,
so as her only blood relative, I want to hold on to our link and do it.
I can't think of it as another person's problem.
Hey, I want to return them, so what should I do?
Return them?
The names. I want to give them back to the youkai.
Fool. Don't do it, it's a waste.
Plus, there are some evil ones in there.
No matter how many lives you might have, it won't be enough.
I'll be fine.
You're with me, Sensei.
I want to do what Reiko-san left undone.
If I die along the way, then you can have the Book of Friends.
Lend me your power, Sensei.
Natsume, can I really have the Book of Friends when you're gone?
Yeah, sure.
Very well, I will witness it myself.
Thank you.
Damn Reiko! I'll pull her tongue out!
You're...
You want the Book of Friends?
Once I have the Book of Friends, I'll be the master of this area!
Isn't that what you want too, Madara?
Don't lump me together with you, you vulgar bastard.
Cursed fool!
First, you imagine their form,
open the book, and then pray.
One who would protect me, show your name!
Get lost and never appear before me again!
Is this it?
What you need next is Reiko's saliva and breath.
As her blood relative, you can do it.
Tear out the contract and bite on it.
Put you hands together with force and concentrate.
And then, blow a whiff.
I'm lonely...
I'm hungry...
My steamed bun!
It's not that good.
What are you doing, you human?
Your spirit is filthy!
If you want some good steamed buns,
then I recommend the ones from Nanatsuji.
Nanatsuji?
I know, if you fight with me and you win,
I'll treat you to some food.
You can see me?
Yeah, I can see you.
Aren't you scared?
Not at all!
Because I'm strong!
Let's start now.
All right, it's my win!
Wasn't that a surprise attack?
A win is a win.
All right, now you're one of my followers.
Followers?
What?
What's with that injury on your cheek?
Someone threw a rock at me.
They said I was creepy.
Hey, you have a pretty name.
You're my follower now,
so when I call your name, you have to come flying to me.
What's your name?
It's Reiko.
Reiko...
See you later.
She won't call me today either?
It's lonely! A lot more than before!
Return it! Return my name!
No matter how long I wait, you never call my name!
Hishigaki...
Reiko...
Is it okay now?
Are you okay by yourself now?
I'm sure my grandmother wasn't alone.
Thank you, Hishigaki,
my dear grandmother's kind-hearted friend.
Did you see Reiko?
Yeah.
She was a mean person, wasn't she?
Do you think you can do it, Natsume?
I want to do it.
I see.
As usual, I can't come to like the youkai.
But...
Sensei, they say the steamed buns there are good.
What? Let's go eat them!
Hey, don't be so wild!
Whether good or bad, it was a meeting.
Huh? Can cats eat sweet things?
I told you, I'm not a cat!
Some steamed buns, please!
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo
Natsume Yuujinchou
Next
Time on
The Dew God's Small Shrine
What is your name?
I am the Dew God.
Hey, that lady is worshiping at your shrine.
I've always watched her and listened to her voice.
If only she could hear my voice.