There you go, making that face again,
mata sonna kao wo shite
biting onto your lips
kuchibiru kamishimete
You're hiding your weak side,
yowasa wo kakushiteru kedo
but deep in those eyes,
sono hitomi no oku
I can see you cowering
uzukumaru kimi ga
If you had a true heart,
hontou no kokoro nara
you would care, cry, call for someone and worry
omotte, naite, hito yonde, fuwande
Why are you holding onto the pain?
nande itai no mottenda?
Share some of it with me
boku ni sotto azukete yo
If you don't think it's possible right away,
sugu ja muri to omou no naraba
you can do it slowly, bit by bit
sukoshi zutsu de ii
We don't have wings,
tsubasa no nai bokura kitto
but I'm sure we're only finding times that we can't fly
tobenai toki mitsuketeru dake
I'll call for you to the limits of my voice
koe no kagiri kimi wo yobu yo
so that you won't get lost
mayowanai you ni
Soar up to the sky with your gentle heart,
fuwari kokoro maiagare
ride on that wind, and get it all at once
ano kaze ni nosete issei no sei
Natsume
Yuujinchou
Got you!
Nyanko's Book of Boredom
Damn, how could someone as graceful as myself have done that?
Kyaa!
"Kyaa?"
A white piglet fell!
What'd you say? This is why I hate inferior animals.
It's actually a kitty, now that I look carefully.
Are you okay, kitty?
Did you fall down like me?
I can't climb up there.
What should I do?
Who cares about that! How dare you call me a piglet?
How cute!
In the first place, this is just a temporary form.
My true form is much more grand!
Don't laugh at me! Damn human children.
I'm really glad, though.
You aren't injured at all.
No, no, I can't stay with her.
I have to climb out of here right away.
Wait, kitty! Don't go!
Don't leave me alone!
Geez, this is why I hate human children.
Kitty...
You sort of... smell strongly of sake.
I'm back!
I'm back, Touko-san.
Welcome back.
I'm going to go change.
Okay.
Is something wrong?
Yeah, you see...
I see.
The recession is just as bad.
The stocks are...
Sensei!
Touko-san said the shrimp in the fridge are gone.
Oh? Well, that's quite odd.
You ate them, didn't you?
What?
I told you so many times not to bother the other people in this house.
Fool! Are you doubting me?
Of course.
It's got nothing to do with me.
Besides, don't make such a big fuss over one or thirteen shrimp, you ignorant boy!
This is the CD I borrowed from Nishimura.
What are you going to do about it?
It's your fault for leaving it there, idio-
So it was you!
Get out!
I'm tired of being with you!
Natsume, you damn punked-out, baldy, white asparagus!
Takashi-kun, I heard a big sound!
Sorry, it was nothing!
Natsume, you damn punked-out, baldy, white asparagus!
Stupid Natsume.
Still, that fat cat is a real bother.
He comes here every night and drinks like crazy.
Drinks, drinks.
And it's not just sake! He eats boatloads!
Eats, eats.
He sings too.
Tone-deaf, tone-deaf.
He's a bad drunk, too.
That's right! He goes wild after he drinks.
Drunken frenzy, drunken frenzy.
So, what are we going to do?
It's true that Natsume-dono is this Eight Field's savior,
but we need to watch out for that big-eating, tone-deaf, drunken cat.
But, still! There's a limit to how much we can take!
Right, right.
All right, for the peace of the Eight Fields,
we'll make that big-eating, tone-deaf, drunken, old cat pay double!
Double, double!
For the peace of the Eight Fields, we'll make that big-eating, tone-deaf, drunken, old cat pay double!
Bravo!
Ma-Madara-sama!
That's right.
I'm a big eater,
a bad drunk,
tone-deaf,
and old!
I eat thirteen shrimps from the fridge,
and I'm bad with CDs!
Take this!
A, B, C, D?
[ Note: A, B sounds like ebi (shrimp) and C, D for CD ]
E, F, G...
Hey, you there, monk.
Who are you?
Exorcise the Eight Fields.
That place is a den for ungrateful youkai.
You should purify them so that they won't go wild.
Thoroughly and completely.
Hold it.
I'm back, dad.
Ah, welcome back.
I just felt something strange.
Hey, what should we do after this?
Go home, we've got homework.
Ah, that's right.
It's so hot.
Mareina.
It's expensive.
I bought it.
I haven't seen that uniform before.
Which school is it from?
Not sure.
Hey, wait.
Hey, which school are you from?
Oh, it's you two.
You're Natsume's classmates, right?
Oh, you're his friend.
Friend?
No, I'm his sensei.
Sensei?
We just broke up, though.
You two! Come with me for a bit.
How much do you have?
I used a lot at the arcade.
Hey.
Order another mixed pizza and a gratin.
You're still going to eat?
Aren't you eating a bit too much?
Don't worry, eating a lot is good for you.
No, the problem is that it's not good for our wallets.
What?
No, nothing.
By the way, what's an arcade?
A type of rice cracker?
Here's your hotdog.
Thanks, I'd like a pizza and gratin too.
Geez, what a waste of money.
Hey, you.
Sensei.
Hey, Sensei.
We kind of want to go home now.
Please, Sensei.
Damnit!
Go, go, go!
We sure caught a weird one.
Yes!
Natsume Yuujinchou
I haven't seen the cat today.
Do you know where he is, Takashi-kun?
Not sure.
I wonder if Nyankichi-kun is hungry?
Nyankichi?
Oh? That's strange.
Your cat.
He's always sitting imposingly on my seat.
Ah, sorry.
It's kind of lonely without Nyangoro around, though.
N-Nyangoro?
It's kind of surprising Nyanko-sensei got so close to them.
What are you doing there?
Just keep on regretting it, kid.
Like heck I'd go back to you now.
The cat... smiled?
Nishimura.
Here's the CD I borrowed.
Natsume.
Who was that?
Who?
The girl, man.
The girl?
Yeah, that's right.
The girl that ate everything on the menu from top to bottom.
She even made us go to the arcade with her.
She just wouldn't let us go home.
And thanks to her, my allowance for this month is completely gone.
Completely gone!
I don't know any girls like that.
She knew you, though.
She probably has the wrong person.
I don't have any female friends in the first place.
"Friend?"
"No, I'm his sensei."
Sensei?
That's what she said.
Tell me more about her.
Hey, you!
It's against school rules to go to the arcade on the way home from school.
But, well, it's kind of surprising.
So even you play games, Natsume-kun?
Well, it's healthier than going through the garbage in the mornings.
Onee-chan.
Oh, Tamiko-chan!
Hello.
Are you alone?
No, I'm with my mom.
I see.
She's from my neighbourhood.
Hello.
Going shopping?
Yeah, we're going to a picnic tomorrow, after all.
So your mom and dad both got time off!
That's great.
Yeah!
This girl's parents both work...
He's gone.
He ran away.
I'm back!
Maybe I'll go tease Natsume's friends again.
Who's there?
It's been a while.
It's me.
That voice... Enkou?
That's right!
What do you want?
Well, I heard that you cut ties with the human that holds the Book of Friends.
That has nothing to do with you.
Now that you're not related, you wouldn't mind me taking the Book of Friends, right?
Remember, you turned it down,
so don't come complaining to me later.
That's it.
I haven't... Wait!
What's the meaning of this, Madara?
I won't let you pass.
Don't play with me!
You're attached to it, Madara.
You've come to desire the Book of Friends now?
Or... don't tell me you've come to like humans?
Shut up!
Natsume, you idiot.
Anyway, I just can't stand other youkai stealing the Book of Friends.
[ Note: The cawing sound crows make sounds like "stupid" in Japanese ]
Don't call me stupid.
You eat a lot for such a small cat.
Stop, that tickles!
Wh-What?
Oh my, it's completely attached to you.
We'll be keeping it while my friend is on his business trip for 2-3 days.
Sorry, but look after it for me.
Sure.
Ah, look, it's like a ball of yarn.
Who cares about Natsume!
Who cares about the Book of Friends!
Treating me like an idiot...
Shut up!
This isn't some freak show!
Get lost!
All right, let's sing a song!
The stars are so beautiful!
Yeah, the ancient heavens!
I drank too much yesterday.
Ah, the water from these rocks...
My head's ringing...
Ah, shut up!
Ah, I'm pretty hungry.
Got you!
You're hungry, huh?
I know, I have some chocolate.
Here's half for you, kitty.
It's good, huh?
I was supposed to split it three ways with my mom and dad.
They said we couldn't go on a picnic again, so I went by myself.
And then I fell!
Oh yeah, how about you come live with me, kitty?
We can eat meals and snacks together!
I'm sure it's a lot more delicious than eating alone!
What is all this?
Don't hide. Come on out, Sensei.
Oh, you did all this?
It's raining!
Oh no! My mom said rabbits die if they get wet!
Will you die too kitty? Huh? Huh?
Ah, what should I do? The kitty is going to die!
Calm down, child. That won't happen.
I'm sorry, kitty.
You said you wanted to go home, but I stopped you!
I'm sorry! You even came to me, kitty!
But you're going to die!
It's gotten quiet now.
Humans are such fragile creatures.
I hate weaklings.
They're weak, yet they care for others.
They have no powers, yet they desperately try to protect others.
Just like her.
And him.
Sensei!
Nyanko-sensei!
Huh? I'm flying.
What a wonderful dream.
It's all warm and fuzzy.
Are you okay, missy?
Are you okay?
What's your name?
Sensei!
Nyanko-sensei! Where are you?
Geez...
Natsume!
Through the color-changing western sky
irozuku nishizora ni
pierces a single beam of sunlight
sashikomu hitosuji no hi
As the afternoon rain stops,
yuudachi no ameagari ni
I notice the scent of summer
kizuku natsu no nioi
and the concentrated, shining light
hishimeku hikari ga terasu
If I listen closely to the memories,
omoi ni mimi wo sumaseba
I can hear traces of my dear friends
kikoeshi tomo no omokage
The summer sky releases a scent
natsu yuuzora kaoritatsu
of fresh and vibrant days that have passed by
azayaka na sugisarishi hibi
We laughed together from the bottoms of our hearts
kokoro no mama waraiatta
at the memories of that summer
ano natsu no omoide yo
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Five Day Mark
Sensei touched my mark and he became small!
Yes, it's the effect of the curse you picked up.
You're Hinoe?
It's the five day mark curse.
You only have five days left to live, Natsume.
Five?!