Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
I met a mysterious boy named Kai who said he was being chased by something.
I wanted to protect Kai.
But it wasn't just a youkai that was after him.
It's best you don't get close to him.
He's a youkai.
He has enough power to pretend to be a normal human.
I came to exterminate him.
Exterminate?
Humans and Youkai
Natsume!
Kai...
Natsume, it's great that you're safe.
He wouldn't listen to me when I said he shouldn't go after you.
The kitty was with you,
and I said he'd be in danger if he went.
That's because I was worried about Natsume.
Thanks.
What's wrong, Takashi-kun?
Did something happen?
Ah, nothing.
Is Kai really a youkai?
Should he be exterminated?
What should I tell Taki?
Would it be better if I stopped seeing him?
Who'd have thought he was an youkai.
So what are you going to do?
Well, since it's you,
you'll probably get involved and there'll be trouble.
Shut up.
Shut up?
I'm worried about you!
This wouldn't have happened if you had noticed it earlier!
My sense of smell has gotten worse after sniffing your stench this whole time!
Stench?
Right! Stench!
Don't say that!
I'm going to buy a car soon.
It's cheap, but it has good mileage and it's durable.
I want to see the sea with you.
You'll want to let your special one ride it.
Yokota Vivace.
It's mean of you to laugh.
Natori-san!
But it looks like you made up thanks to it.
I thought you'd be suffering on your own.
Well, sorry for that.
Are you teasing me?
Yeah.
What a terrible person!
You're the devil!
I'll curse you if you say that again!
Hiiragi! When did you get here?
I won't allow you to be rude to my master.
It's okay, Hiiragi. Natsume's special.
Anyway, don't you have something to ask me?
Why do you have to exterminate him?
The area around that western house attracts youkai.
There is a well in that area where ogres that once rampaged the neighborhood are sealed.
And so, youkai are called there to free the ogres.
So Kai was called by the ogres?
Lesser youkai can't release the seal, but with his power, it is possible.
Where's the well?
I don't know.
So Kai came to that western house to...
To look for the well.
My master has taken a job to exterminate him.
Don't interfere, Natsume.
Who hired you?
Is it the Matoba's again?
I can't tell you.
It's my job.
We don't know if Kai can even release the seal!
You're going to exterminate him just because he might be able-
It'll be too late once something happens.
That's why I won't ask you to help me.
Just don't interfere.
He's my friend!
I can't just stand by and watch!
Natsume, how about you decide now?
What's more important to you? Humans or youkai?
Even if you don't bother with youkai anymore,
you have people who will be with you now, right?
He's a bothersome guy, isn't he?
If you're his bodyguard, don't let him stick his head into danger.
An insensitive human like you wouldn't understand our feelings.
Insensitive, huh?
He doesn't even understand my master's feelings.
Damn that ugly cat.
Couldn't you just refuse this job involving Natsume's neighborhood?
Maybe, but...
Natsume-kun?
Oh, Taki.
W-What's wrong?
You look more gloomy than usual.
Well, some things happened.
Kai isn't with you?
He said he never ate cookies before, so I baked some.
He's a strange kid.
I wonder if he's at home?
Taki, Kai is...
Kai isn't at home.
Oh, I see.
Anyway, there's something I'd like to ask of you.
There's supposed to be an old well around that western house,
could you find out where it is?
Sure, but do you need it soon?
As soon as possible.
I'll give that to Kai.
Ah, okay.
It might be in the old documents at my house.
I'll take a look at them.
Yeah, thanks.
Say hi to Kai for me.
Tell me what's going on after, okay?
Sorry, Taki.
He's not here.
Natsume?
Tanuma.
Have you seen Kai?
Oh, that kid from the other day?
I just saw him heading that way.
I see, thanks!
Hey! Want some help looking for him?
No, it's okay!
Natsume...
He doesn't know how to be a friend.
Nyan-Nyan-sensei.
He thinks he won't cause others any trouble if he takes it on by himself.
He's so thoughtless.
Kai must be looking for the well.
Natori-san!
No, it might be Kai.
Natori-san! Kai!
Is anyone here?
Kai?
Oh, it's just you, Sensei?
"Just you"?
I'm here to be your bodyguard!
Something smells good.
Over here?
Some bodyguard.
This room?
I can't move...
Natsume!
Are you okay, Natsume?
Kai, are you a youkai?
Do you hate youkai?
I like you.
That snobby man set up this trap.
Were you looking for the well?
Yeah.
I was thinking of saving my locked up friends.
Then I saw you coming in here.
I'm glad I came.
Thanks.
Still...
The exorcist who's after me put you in danger.
I won't forgive that annoying man.
His smell still lingers here.
If I follow it...
Hey, Kai, don't tell me...
I'll take care of him.
This is bad.
If he faces Natori head on, Natori will have no chance.
How about you decide now?
What's more important to you? Humans or youkai?
Natsume! Hey!
Natsume Yuujinchou
The trap!
He broke out of it.
He's got more power than I thought.
Hiiragi!
He's here...
You have youkai serve you?
Just how unpleasant can you get?
Get lost!
Kai! Don't make a mistake!
Running away is futile.
Stop, Hiiragi!
My duty is to protect you, master!
He'll catch up to us right away even if we run!
Found you!
There you are, monster!
Natori-san!
Natsume?
Thank goodness you're safe.
I'm sorry, I couldn't stop Kai.
He's after you.
You've got to run far away!
You're the one in danger.
Go back home now.
I'll talk with Kai again.
Talk and make him stop.
Natsume...
I can't choose between them!
Both you and Kai are important to me!
I know what Kai is.
He's one of the water gods that live in the mountains.
He would protect the source of the river, and wait for the people and their offerings.
But that custom would be forgotten by the people.
When he got lonely and listened carefully,
he heard the voices of the sealed ogres.
So he probably came down the mountain to break the seal and make more friends.
Lonely?
That's what he took advantage of.
But while he mingled with humans to look for the well,
that became fun,
and he eventually stopped listening to the ogres.
And then he met you and Taki.
Natsume, I'll withdraw from this job.
But I'll find the old well and renew the seal so that even the voices of the ogres won't be heard.
Natori-san!
Will you help me with that?
Yes.
There he is!
Natsume?
Why's he with the exorcist?
Kai.
Why?
Kai, there's something important I need to tell you.
So you're one of his friends too.
You tricked me.
No!
Listen to me, Kai!
If I was such a nuisance, you could've just told me to go back to the mountains!
I would've done that if you had wanted me to!
Enough.
I've had enough of humans.
Kai.
This is no time to be shocked!
What are we going to do, Natsume?
Natsume!
Sensei! Let's go!
Natsume...
When Kai was trapped in the coffin, he didn't cry because he was scared.
He cried because he was sad that he was something that must be exorcised and shouldn't be there.
A crybaby god all alone on the mountain.
And he finally found a place he wanted to be.
Kai...
Where did you go?
Let me talk to you!
That's...
Taki!
Where's the well?
You...
I see, you're a friend of the ogres trapped in the well too.
So that's why you came after me.
All right! Take me to the well!
Over there.
The old well is in a basin on the north side of the house.
I see, thanks.
Tanuma-kun found it.
We met on the way and I told him what was going on,
so he said he'd help.
You told me not to tell anyone, but...
Thanks.
Take care!
Don't be reckless!
So it was here?
Sorry, I'm late.
I'll let you out now.
Kai!
Natsume!
You shouldn't release the seal!
Listen to me!
Stay away!
I don't want to see you!
I've taken care of that obstacle, so let's go back to the mountains now.
You look delicious.
We're grateful to you for saving us.
So we'll eat you as thanks!
You're not getting away!
The Book of Friends...
I see.
You're Natsume Reiko's...
You did this to get back at me.
I...
I really don't like seeing Natsume troubled...
When I came to, Kai had disappeared.
So Kai was a youkai.
Sorry.
So he's alone again.
Natori-san said he lived on a mountain.
We should find out which mountain.
Natsume-kun...
Let's go see Kai.
Yeah!
Hey, that's your second one!
Yeah, don't break the rules!
*gobble gobble*... school lunch!
We can't tell what you're saying!
Didn't you read the guidebook?
On your own again?
What a troublesome guy.
Don't say that.
Still, I just can't get bored with you.
After Reiko died, I thought about taking the Book of Friends.
I didn't think there would be anyone to receive her belongings.
But this might be for the best.
Sensei...
Thanks for being by me.
Idiot! Don't say such creepy stuff.
I just finished making a new dish.
All right, I'll join them too.
Do you want to eat with us?
Can we really?
Eat! Eat!
It doesn't matter whether they're human or youkai.
What's important is whether they're precious to you.
You should accept them as they are and the feelings and joy that come with it, without any hesitation.
Takashi.
You took that down, right?
It's okay.
Touko-san...
What a nice sound.
Yeah.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no