Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
A bird's nest?
It was giving warmth to five eggs.
Four of them have hatched, so now there is only one left.
What, are you going to eat it?
I'm watching over it.
All you talk about is eating.
Is that a guest?
There's no one there.
land
I'm sure there was someone here just now.
What's this?
land
An Ayakashi must've written it.
You mean... this isn't actually written?
land
Yeah.
They're words that only we can see.
A Chick Hatches
Its parent isn't returning.
Takashi-kun, is something wrong?
N-No. It's nothing!
Really?
Don't do such dangerous things, okay?
Okay.
It's still warm.
What is this?!
Good morning, Sensei.
You're free, right?
Could you keep it warm for me?
What?
Your stupidity knows no bounds!
Eggs are practically dead once they're abandoned!
The chick might taste good if it hatches.
You've got a point.
I'm going out now.
line
The scribbled word has changed.
And so, on a simple whim,
Sensei and I tried to keep the egg warm.
Damn! I want to go drinking!
I'm back!
Damn it!
You're not hatching yet?
Hey, stop!
Looks like it got a bit bigger.
I wonder what kind of egg it is.
If the chick hatches,
what should I name it?
I'm leaving now.
coming
"Coming"...
"Three."
"Three"?
They're numbers?
land
"Land" was "six."
"Line" was "five."
line
Yesterday was "four,"
four
and today's is "three."
three
A countdown?
For what though?
Boy.
Just who are you to be able to see the words?
You wrote this?
Correct.
You belong to this household?
Yeah.
three
Then do you know of the egg in that nest?
My master desires the chick from it.
Desires it?
Of course...
...to eat it.
Its meat has a flavor like no other,
and its blood is said to grant eternal youth.
It has finally appeared in these lands,
and I had calculated the day that it would hatch,
but I could not find it in its rightful place.
Do not tell me that you have touched it with your vile hands and stolen it.
O-Of course not.
I trust that I can believe in you?
Yeah.
Boy, do not do anything funny.
three
Sensei!
Just now, there was a strange Youkai outside.
Sign: At my limit. Out drinking for a bit.
That gutless cat...
Will it be eaten once it's born?
This egg is alive.
It's trying to live.
Would you like to try living a bit more?
I'm back!
Oh, the heavens...
I'm leaving now.
two
one
That's it for today.
Stand.
Bow.
Natsume?
What's up with him these days?
one
S-Sensei! The egg!
What? A chick! A chick!
Got to give it a bath!
Towel, towel! Towel!
Natsume Yuujinchou
This is probably the chick of an Ayakashi called Tatsumi.
Tatsumi?
It's an Ayakashi that is similar to birds and dragons,
and they do not raise their own children.
That's why there aren't many of them.
They supposedly change into the first creature they see when they hatch.
Once you raise them for some time,
I hear they return to their true forms and leave.
So if it saw you first...
You're really lucky.
What do you mean by that?
Hey!
Natsume!
I'm talking to you!
All right, this should do it.
Ignoring me, huh?
I wonder how many days it'll take for it to grow.
Who knows?
I hear they grow quickly, but I don't know the details.
What do they eat?
Would milk work?
It might just be human flesh.
Ah, hey! You'll get a stomach ache.
How ungrateful!
I'm more of a parent than this matchstick here!
What do you mean by "matchstick"?
You're skinny as one, that's why you're a matchstick!
What's that, you stupid cat?!
Damn matchstick!
Was it too rash of me to take in another life on a whim?
Humans don't know anything about a dragon's child,
and dragons wouldn't know anything about a human child.
I should have known that, but...
Is it good?
Oh, yes!
It's really good.
Someone gave that to me, so I tried it out.
Could I have another one?
Ah, those are...
They didn't turn out well.
They're really good.
Don't tell me Sensei ate it.
Oh, you're here?
You want me to follow you?
What's that?
Is it a nest?
Tatsumi do not raise their own children,
that's why they change into the first creature they see.
They become affectionate with the first person they see.
Sorry.
I know you made it, but I can't go in with you.
A few days later, I had a dream.
A dream where I went inside the nest.
After quietly going in, I found something precious inside.
He's grown quite big.
He may not look like it, but he's a dragon.
You won't be able to be with him much longer.
Oh... yeah.
It leaves once it grows big.
I was thinking of giving him a name too.
I already gave him one.
It hatched from an egg, so his name's "Tama-chan."
Maybe he doesn't like that name.
You little shrimp! You're not getting away with it this time!
Little by little, Tama grew bigger.
And,
for some reason, weakened.
What's wrong, Tama?
He hasn't even touched his food.
I'll go change his milk.
Ah! A mouse!
You're...!
My name is Isozuki the Mouse.
I told you not to do anything funny, boy.
I will be taking the Tatsumi chick.
What vile creature do we have now?
You're really impudent to have entered my turf.
I trained my right hook on cattails, and it'll be more than enough for a lowly rat!
How rude!
What a strange creature.
Is it a pig?
A raccoon?
Bastard!
I'm going to eat you, you damn rat!
Hold it, boy!
Damn!
Where should I run?
Just what is wrong with him?
He's thinned out so much.
Why did he stop eating?
Could it be that you don't want to grow bigger?
You don't want to leave when you grow?
Tama...
You want to be together more?
I've found you, boy.
Sorry, but I'm not giving him to you!
If you won't hand him to me, then I'll just have to take him!
So, are you sure, boy?
You are a powerless human.
Tatsumi are nothing but trouble for the powerless.
Now, hand him over.
A single Ayakashi shouldn't matter to you.
T-Tama!
Stop struggling!
It's okay, Tama!
You don't have to leave.
It's okay for you to stay here.
You have to eat.
When the day that you leave comes, I'm sure it won't be the day we say our farewells.
So until then, it's okay for you to stay here.
Natsume!
Stop, Tama!
Let him go now!
Stop, Tama! He'll die!
Tama!
Stop, Natsume!
He's forgotten about us from the shock of his growth!
Let's go home, Tama.
Let's go.
Amazing, Tama!
You're just like a bird!
Listen to me, Tama.
I don't know my real parents either.
I've always been alone.
This may sound weird,
but I've never really felt lonely.
But...
I did feel very sad.
But when I came to this city and met different people,
I didn't feel as sad anymore.
I hope it's like that for you too.
I wonder, with you having known loneliness and struggling to be loved,
if I was able to lighten your heart, even for a bit.
I took a peek into the nest that Tama left behind.
Takashi-kun!
Yes?
The inside was empty, just as I thought,
but I had a feeling that I knew what was left behind at the bottom.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Promised Tree
What is your name?
My name is Kirinoha.
Um, my name...
Yeah, I'll give it back.
Huh?
Your name isn't in the Book of Friends.
Mine is in another place.
Let's go take a look.