Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
I would sometimes see strange things when I was young.
They were probably the ones called youkai.
Where the heck are you kicking it, idiot?
Ah, watch out, Natsume!
Natsume fell!
This is bad! That's someone's house!
You okay, Natsume?
Yeah, somehow.
Sorry, but could you get the ball?
Sure!
Ball... Where's the ball?
There it is.
That face... You're Natsume-sama, aren't you?
You own the Book of Friends, don't you?
Hold it!
Damn, she's chasing me!
What is this rope?
Don't tell me...
Wait, something like this happened before!
Give me the Book of Friends!
Let go!
Now, hand it over to me. Quickly!
Geez, it's so loud.
N-Nyanko-sensei!
Got yourself into a predicament with an youkai again?
I came with you because I was free and this is what happens?
S-Sensei... It hurts...
Butterfly! Butterfly!
Give it to me! Give me the Book of Friends!
I told you...
That it hurts!
What are you doing, Natsume?
What do you mean, you stupid cat?
I told you I'm not a cat!
This lucky cat form is just a temporary one.
You're my bodyguard, right?
Then you should...
Don't think that I'm just a simple bodyguard.
I'm waiting for your life to end so that I can get the Book of Friends.
Don't turn on me, you rice cake cat.
What?!
Just wait and see! I'll eat you like a piece of meat one day!
Geez...
Stolen Book of Friends
With no family, and after going from one relative to the other,
the ones who finally took me in were the kind Fujiwara couple.
Takashi-kun! Dinner!
Coming!
Ah, Takashi-kun! Nyankichi-kun isn't home yet?
He isn't coming to eat.
Maybe he's eating somewhere else.
I'm sure he'll come back when he's hungry.
Really? I hope so then.
Here.
Thank you.
Eat up.
This is good!
What is it?
They're lilies.
In order to not trouble them,
I have to keep the fact that I can see youkai an absolute secret.
He didn't come back to my room either?
Maybe I punched him too hard.
N-Nyanko-sensei...
Don't scare me.
Where'd you go?
You're pitch black!
Why?
What happened?
Hey!
Don't walk around with your dirty feet. Geez...
It's not coming off.
What did you do, Sensei?
How come you're not talking?
Are you sulking because I hit you earlier?
Come on, it was your fault.
I'm back!
Sensei!
Who's that black cat?!
Just as I thought, it's an youkai.
Oh, it wasn't you?
You can tell just by looking, you idiot!
There aren't many cats with such big faces.
So does that mean he's disguising himself as you?
I wonder what he's after?
Natsume, the Book of Friends is safe, right?
Yeah, it is.
It's right here.
Oh, no!
The Book of Friends!
Damn, where'd that black cat go?
We won't be able to find him in the dark since he's black.
We'll try again later.
But... the Book of Friends...
It's dangerous for a human like you to wander around at night.
Plus, the air seems to be different tonight.
Let me...
Let me look for him a little longer!
I was entrusted with the youkai's precious names!
Plea-
Calm down, Natsume.
I'm also irritated that it was taken,
but I didn't sense anything bad coming from that black cat.
That's why I let my guard down.
Besides, it would be bad if other youkai found out it was stolen because we made a fuss over it.
But...
What are those lights?
Oh, will-o-the-wisps?
Will-o-the-wisps?
There sure are a lot.
Where are they heading?
What's wrong?
I think... I smell a human.
S-Sensei... You're heavy...
Bear with it.
I'm camouflaging you with my smell.
Was it just my imagination?
I thought it smelled like a human, but it smells more like an animal.
S-Smells like an animal?
How dare he say that to someone as high level as...
Let it go.
Oh yeah, the lord often came back smelling like a human.
Ah, that's right. He played by disguising himself as a human.
The lord?
He often gave us gifts.
Yeah.
Nothing good comes from getting involved with those damned humans though.
You said it.
They're gone.
If it isn't Madara-sama.
It has been a while.
You're as beautiful as ever.
You...
Benio?
Is she your acquaintance?
Yeah.
Oh? A human?
Were you in the middle of your meal?
Please leave me some leftovers.
Where have I seen this face before?
Ah! Natsume Reiko!
You fool! You're too loud!
Oh? Natsume Reiko's grandson?
What was with the march of youkai earlier, Benio?
Everyone from this forest is gathering for a party.
Did you see a lovely black cat biting onto some paper around here?
Lovely?
Ah, I saw a big-headed, fat cat heading to the party grounds earlier.
Fat?!
That's him!
Could you take us there, Benio-san?
Are you insane?
You'll be eaten right away if they find out that you're human.
Then I'll go and disguise myself as a youkai.
Please!
I have a reason for why I must find that cat.
You really are similar to Reiko, with those brazen eyes of yours.
Is that what you like about him?
Are you stupid?
I'll eat you if you say any more stupid things.
It sounds interesting.
Very well, I'll take you there.
It'll be fine if you can successfully disguise yourself as an youkai.
But if you're revealed to be human, you'll be everyone's appetizer.
I don't mind.
Thank you.
Geez...
There you go deciding things on your own again.
Madara-sama turned into a midget!
How heartrending...
Is the sake this way?
We're not going to drink.
Anyway, you'll have to wear a mask or makeup, Natsume-sama.
We can't have you in your animal form either, Madara-sama.
Huh? Why?
Well, Natsume Reiko is famous.
There's a rumor going around about a young man looking like Reiko
who has an animal companion and the Book of Friends.
The Book of Friends...
Natsume Yuujinchou
Hey, how long do you plan to keep that kid?
I couldn't help it. Even my brother...
W-Welcome back, Takashi-kun.
Perfect timing! Reiko-san's belongings came.
Reiko-san...
She's your grandmother.
Hey, what is this? A scribble book?
I heard she was way out there, but I guess she was really out there.
It's okay to throw it out.
You won't gain anything by holding on to it.
The Book of Friends.
My grandmother, Reiko, was born with strong spiritual powers
and had the youkai she defeated write their names down as contracts so they would serve her.
Back then, I didn't know anything about the Book of Friends or Reiko-san.
What's wrong, Natsume?
No, it's nothing.
You'll be taking that form, Madara-sama?
Do you have a problem with it?
Not at all.
Well then, let us get going.
Okay.
Oh, Benio! You sure are late.
What were you doing?
How uncouth! I was putting on my makeup.
Oh? I haven't seen them before.
Ah, they're my companions.
Looks fun.
Let me join.
Sure thing. Drink! Drink!
You kind of smell like a human.
You're right.
Reminds me of the lord.
The lord did always smell like humans.
The lord?
He's the lord of this forest who favors humans.
When he disguised himself as a human and went down to the village,
he got caught by a fox trap.
Ever since he was saved by a hunter,
he would frequently go see him and tell everyone that he had made a human friend.
He had strong spiritual powers,
but he wasn't very smart.
He became friends with a human after all.
Yeah, I saw him have a duel with Natsume Reiko too.
Well, drink up!
Thank you.
Hey, has anyone seen a black cat...
Comrades!
Let us get down to our discussion!
I have found out where those hateful humans have sealed the lord!
Now is the time for our revenge!
He's our great savior, the one who gave power to us low level spirits so that we could live in this forest!
We will attack them tonight!
Do not fear the humans!
They're nothing if we all band together!
Attack? What's he talking about?
The lord attacked the humans' livestock,
so that's why they sealed him away!
But now we know he was sealed in a place with a tall, red bricked wall!
So then...
There's no need to attack the home owners though.
It's not needed,
but who knows what they'll do when they're all drunk.
What should we do?
Don't cause me any more trouble.
I can't stop this many so easily.
That's right, you should stop.
A human can't do anything either way.
You're right...
Fortunately, though, I can hear you.
Everyone else here too.
Even humans.
They all may be a source of strength for me.
You're different from Reiko.
There he is!
Hey, wait!
I don't understand this kid.
What part of him do you like?
I'm only interested in the Book of Friends.
Then you should just eat him and take it.
He'll be a way to pass time.
A human's life passes by in an instant.
So fast that it's scary.
I got him, Sensei!
He's pretty compliant.
Maybe this black cat did it on purpose.
On purpose?
It's like he led us here by stealing the Book of Friends.
What for?
I don't know.
You can find out, right, Benio?
Search him.
I'll try.
I believe a strong youkai was sealed in this form.
Sealed in that form, huh?
Was that popular back then?
His spirit reminds me of...
C-Could it be the lord?!
What?
The lord?
How heartrending! Damn those humans!
He's supposed to be sealed, yet he's moving around.
A house with a tall, red-bricked wall.
Could it be?
The rope I broke then was the barrier for this black cat?
Let's let everyone know, Benio-san!
No one will believe it's the lord because of the form he's in.
We have to break the seal and return him to his true form.
But how?
Oh yeah, didn't those low-levels say that he dueled with Reiko?
Yeah, that's what I heard.
That's it then!
He might not have enough power to break the seal since his name was taken.
Then we just have to give back his name?
The problem is his name though.
In his form, the Book of Friends will not find the name for us.
Benio-san, what's the lord's name?
Well, I only know him as "the lord."
Lord.
I'll return your name for sure,
so please help us stop everyone!
What are you all doing here?
It's about time we go.
Go attack people?
We don't need to!
The lord has returned right here!
You idiot! Stop!
Does anyone know the lord's name?
If I know his name...
You're human, aren't you?
A human?
They say there's a human.
Damn humans!
Let him go!
Shut up and stay back!
Madara-sama!
Listen hard!
There must be someone here!
Someone who knows the lord's name!
Riou-sama...
There!
Natsume!
Let him go!
Madara-sama!
Riou, I return your name.
Take it.
Lord!
It's the lord!
Riou-sama...
Lord...
I'm back, everyone.
Thank you, human.
Thanks to you, I was able to move again,
and so I went to see my precious friend.
However, he had already passed away.
A human's life sure is short.
I think I know what everyone meant when they called me a fool.
Why did you take the Book of Friends?
When I returned to the forest,
I heard them planning to attack the human house for my sake.
I had no power to stop them, so I brought you here to do something about it.
Forgive me, Natsume.
Humans sealed you away, right?
Yet you tried to stop them?
That's because I like humans.
That's why I won't go back down to human dwellings.
The bath felt great.
Farewell, human.
Farewell...
The black cat is gone.
He was really cute too.
What do you mean by that?
Just who do you think helped solve his prob-
Well then, Madara-sama's wounds aren't so bad,
so I guess I'll take my leave now.
I just can't come to like humans.
I was thinking of helping Madara-sama look for chances to eat you,
but I can't do that since you're our lord's savior.
Madara-sama, how about you come back with me?
No.
I'll be with him for now.
We'll meet when this instant passes.
Thanks, Nyanko-sensei.
It's so creepy when you're honest!
What's been troubling me lately are these small farewells that make me feel a bit lonely.
Brief meetings and farewells.
I want to treasure each and every moment.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Natsume Yuujinchou
Melting into Spring
Next
Time on
What's your name?
I am Gen.
Please help me, Natsume-sama.
You're the stone statue from Shibanohana?
There should have been two, so where's your partner?
Sui... She's...