Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Sensei! Sensei!
Natsume-kun is telling lies again!
There's no way a woman can be peeking in through the windows, right?
Yeah, this is the third floor after all.
Oh, a dream about the past?
Natsume.
I'm sorry.
It's rare for it to snow this much.
Didn't get enough sleep, Natsume?
Doing some "business" at night, aren't you, you pervert?
Are you worried about something?
I'm all right.
I'm happy everyday from the bottom of my heart.
You're exaggerating.
What a liar.
Later!
Yeah!
What are you doing, Nyanko-sensei?
Just what it looks like.
I'm teasing the dog.
This is just great!
If you do that, you'll sli-
Sensei!
Are you o-
You're a cat too!
Don't laugh, idiot!
I told you I'm not a cat!
My hip!
Melting into Spring
Which herb is the one for hip pains?
You don't even know that?
It's your fault too.
My fault?
Oh yeah, I don't think I've been here before.
This place is called Shibanohara,
and there used to be two forest guardian statues.
There's only one now though.
It's pretty.
There isn't even one footprint.
Stop, you...!
M-My hip cracked...
The day will end if I keep playing with this idiot!
Herbs! Herbs!
It's been a long time since I played in snow.
A youkai?
You can see me?
Perfect, I needed a body to possess!
Natsume! Are you okay?
Yeah, but...
Damn, I possessed this one?
Oh well, at least it's a body I can move in.
A-Are you sure?
You're quite the human if you're able to make a vessel out of snow that I can possess.
My name is Gen. I reside in that statue.
Please help me.
What?
Just until this body melts.
If my wish cannot be granted, then...
I'll curse you for three generations!
What a bad-
Can I eat this slushie, Natsume?
T-That wasn't what I meant.
I-I beg you!
I'll listen to your problem then.
Exterminate an evil spirit?
Yes.
Far west of here lies a tree called the "Sealed Evil Tree."
The seal seems to have been broken and the evil spirit has been released.
It releases a dark energy that kills plants and brings chaos to the mind.
It cannot be left alone.
I will...
I will seal it with my own hands.
What is this sensation?
Don't you have any friends, Gen?
There used to be another statue, right?
It was fun back then.
We would always protect the forest together.
We would watch the rain, lightning, moon, and flowers together.
But she...
Sui was smashed to bits.
I am alone in Shibanohara now.
Alone...
Gen-sama, is it boring here?
I'm not bored one bit.
Because... we'll always...
Gen's dream flowed into me.
That must've been Sui.
She was smashed by the evil spirit.
Hey, Gen.
You'll melt if you cry too much.
We can't leave the evil spirit alone, right, Gen?
There are many things I want to protect here too.
Takashi-kun! Breakfast!
Coming!
The Sealed Evil Tree?
In Shinrin Park?
Was there something like that there?
Oh, that tree was recently cut down for road expansion.
Are you serious?
That's pretty scary.
There's a rumor that the plants there were dying because of an evil spirit.
What do you think, Natsume-kun?
Well...
Are you sure it isn't because of acid rain?
Welcome back, Natsume-sama.
Who are you?
Gen?
I've gotten used to my snow rabbit vessel,
so I can become something close to my original form.
So I'm cleaning the yard for practice and to thank you.
I see. Thank you.
Cleaning is quite enjoyable.
You should keep it at a minimum or you'll melt.
Forget him.
You'll be free once he melts.
Peel this for me.
I promised him that I'd help, right?
You're still being naive?
So sweet! This is so sweet!
You two get along well.
How does it look that way?
Like with the mandarin and your snowball fight.
Nyanko-sensei!
Natsume!
That was...!
I'm embarrassed now because of you!
How can someone as high level as me be playing in the snow?
How are you high level?
You two really do get along well.
It reminds me of Sui...
Gen, the Sealed Evil Tree was cut down,
but I found out where it was.
Do you want to go?
Yes.
I hated selfish humans that only prayed for their own sake.
Sui was like that too.
In the past, the humans said that
if you see a three-colored rainbow, your wish will come true.
Sui said that it was ridiculous and laughed.
But ever since that day, whenever she saw a rainbow,
she would say that it wasn't a three-colored one, as if disappointed.
She also wondered if their wishes had come true.
Even so, Sui...
Gen, was the one who smashed Sui...
The truth is...
Hey, Natsume!
What is this?
Over there! Follow the trail!
I can feel something from that rundown house.
Gen!
The air's stagnant.
Don't breathe in too much! Your body won't be able to take it.
Damn humans!
Unforgivable! I won't forgive you!
Gen, it's dangerous! Get away from it!
Natsume-sama, this is Sui!
Sui became an evil spirit!
That's why, with my own hands...
Sui, let's go back together.
Gen!
I can't believe that was Sui...
What's going on, Gen?
Natsume Yuujinchou
Sui and I were built as a pair.
We resided in the statues in Shibanohara, purified the forest and expelled evil spirits.
But one time, the humans cried because they could not harvest their crops.
They begged that we fertilize the earth.
However, we were purification gods,
so we could not enrich the earth.
We asked youkai that passed by to see if there was another way,
but nothing came from it.
Time passed, and Sui and I began to send our lights of life towards the village.
Even so, we could not enrich the earth.
Finally, the humans blamed us for their poor harvest.
Stop!
Please stop!
Sui pleaded to the humans.
"I loved you."
"I prayed for your happiness."
Even so, our voices could not reach them.
Gen-sama!
Why?
I sacrificed myself for them...
Prayed for their happiness...
Protected them...
Cursed humans...
I hate you!
After becoming an evil spirit and attacking the village,
she was sealed away by the humans and that was it for her.
I couldn't protect her.
Not from the humans, or from the hate in her heart.
That's why, at the very least, I would finish Sui, who was reduced to an evil spirit, with my own hands...
With my own hands...
Gen...
Gen.
Ah, I'm sorry.
That snow rabbit was so cute, I put it in the refrigerator.
It was warm today.
It was kind of sad since it was alone, so I made another one.
It turned out terrible though.
Not at all.
That night, Gen slept closely to the small snow rabbit.
But that simple, small snow rabbit melted in the morning and disappeared.
Unusually, it continued to rain.
And beyond there was where I believed that Sui was hiding herself.
S-Sui?
Gen?
S-Sto...
Stop!
I'm back.
Where'd you go, Sensei?
Gen is...!
Don't get close to him, Natsume!
He's becoming an evil spirit.
He was alone for too long and his hatred and sadness must have grown.
He seems to be fighting back somehow.
No way...
G-Give me paper...
I've heard of the Book of Friends.
Natsume-sama, please take my name!
Do you understand what you're getting into, Gen?
If you write down your name, that paper will become your very own life!
So...!
Set it on fire!
If I become evil, then...!
No... I've had enough...
I don't want to be alone.
Get it together, Gen!
You're not alone!
Sui's with you and so are we!
I said I'd help you! I said I'd do something about it!
I can't do anything.
All I can do is protect the forest.
No, I can't even do that.
I'm trash that can't protect anything!
You're not trash!
You swept the yard and protected me from Sui!
You may hate humans, Gen, but I like you.
Plus,
I'm sure Sui, who tried to wish on rainbows, did too.
Boss!
Boss Natsume!
We saw a strange shadow in the northern forest!
We're here to tell you.
So please give us cookies!
He's gotten a lot lighter than before.
If he melts, he'll stay alone.
Natsume-sama!
Sui!
Gen!
Wait!
Let go, Natsume!
Her body is really hot because of the evil!
No! If I let her run again...
Gen-sama...
This feeling...
This is Sui's memory.
Gen-sama, a three-colored rainbow didn't appear.
I wonder if it'll rain again soon.
No, Sui, the rain's cold.
I'm fine with it.
It's not cold.
It's because...
It's because you're here.
It's cold...
Let go, Natsume!
Your body won't be able to take it!
Don't you understand?
Gen doesn't have much power left.
Even if you let them meet, he may die!
Let go! You'll die!
If you won't let go...
Sensei! Stop!
Gen!
I was cold too, Sui.
I was cold.
So, let's go back.
Let's go back together.
Once your heart heals, we'll wait for rainbows together again.
I was happy too, Sui.
Because...
You were by my side.
Gen-sama...
Farewell, Natsume-sama.
Farewell...
I wonder if they were able to go back.
I'm sure they're fine.
Unlike a wimp like you, youkai aren't as weak as you may think.
You're right.
But I'm not as strong with farewells as you may think, Sensei.
That's why I want to treasure things that I believe are important.
I never understand the things you say.
By the way, where are you going now?
Shibanohara.
I thought I'd plant some flower seeds.
I can't show them a rainbow, but I'll plant them flowers.
Humans like flowers.
I'm sure youkai do too.
Because flowers...
Tell you that spring is here.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Youkai Extermination Amid The Steamy Road
I'll be going to a hot spring with Natori-san.
I won a pair of lodging tickets, you see.
Why with me?
You're the only friend who can see the same scenery that I do.
Oh, I'm going too, Natsume!
Eggs, eggs! Hotspring eggs!