Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
I'm Taki Tooru from Class 5.
I can see youkai only when they're inside these circles.
One day, Taki was cursed by a youkai,
simply because she saw it.
Anyone whose name she speaks is placed under it as well, and will be eaten.
In order to lift the curse, I began to search for the youkai with Taki.
That Which You Must Not Call
Natsume!
I know you're hiding!
Where are you?
Natsume!
Natsume?!
Natsume?
Now for the next one...
Kitty?
What's wrong? Why are you in a rush?
That bag...
Natsume-kun is gone!
Damn you, Natsume. Where did you go?
Natsume!
You can hear me?
You can see me, can't you?
Who are you?
Where am I?
You're the youkai Taki's looking for, aren't you?
You forced her into that impossible game!
All she did was see you!
Why did you curse her just for that?
I despise humans.
I can't get enough of seeing that little girl tremble in fear,
which is why I put off eating her for a while.
But I do not like you.
You can see me on your own.
I sense a strange power about you.
I'm going to keep you here so you don't spoil my fun.
I'll eat you slowly later.
This game is absurd!
Nature itself is absurd.
Humans are the only ones who whine about it.
I have no obligation to follow the rules.
Stop!
I will eat you!
I will come to eat you!
Natsume!
Natsume-dono!
It doesn't look like he's over here!
Where is he?
Sensei!
Natsume?
Watch out!
I'm glad you guys are okay.
I'm far from okay!
I've got bumps everywhere now!
Natsume-kun, your neck is all red. Are you all right?
It just got rubbed a bit.
I'm fine.
You were cursed, weren't you?
Idiot.
Even when I warn you, you keep doing whatever you want and this always, always, always happens!
Learn already, you idiot!
Where did you go in the first place?
A cave back there.
Think about the people who have to look for you!
We searched everywhere for you, you know!
Taki, I met that youkai.
I'm sorry...
Taki, it's okay.
You don't need to worry about how you got me involved.
I think about it sometimes, but you don't need to worry when it comes to me.
What's wrong?
My vision's been kind of blurry for a while.
I can't see well.
The colors of your eyes seem to be darker.
I hear Mustache.
Is he nearby, Sensei?
Right in front of you!
He's sitting right next to me.
Oh no...
I can't see him.
Damn...
I bet it's because that youkai licked my eyes.
His poison may have paralyzed your eyes, making you unable to see me since I'm a youkai.
Well, it should only last a little while.
But for it to happen now...
I'm so sorry I got you mixed up in this.
It's fine.
It's really not your fault.
Idiot!
How are you going to catch him if you can't even see him?
Geez, now we've got twice as many useless people!
Twice!
Geez, what are we going to do?!
Should I have just stayed and fought instead of running away?
That didn't help.
Your silly face just looks even sillier.
Like I said, why do you keep falling for these things!
Sit down!
I'm going to lecture you until morning!
Sit, sit!
Why?
I can see your silly face.
Have you forgotten?
Since this body is just a vessel,
even humans can see it.
Including you, as you are now.
So, if you switched to your original form, I wouldn't be able to see you?
Should we test it out?
Sensei!
Nyanko-sensei?
I can't see him.
Are you there, Sensei?
Sensei...
Well, Natsume?
Can you see me this morning?
Sensei?
No.
I still can't see you.
Mustache!
Mustache?
You should've told me he was there, Sensei.
You couldn't see him that close up? You're a dunce.
I guess I can only see youkai now if they're reflected in a mirror or glass.
That aside, this morning the character on my chest changed to "2."
Taki might've said somebody's name unconsciously, like in her sleep or something.
So talking in her sleep even counts?
That's strict.
What's wrong?
Sensei... look.
[ Sign: Nyanko-sensei, 1 ]
When we were looking for you, I told Taki about myself,
and she accidentally said my name.
I thought I'd be fine since it's not my real name, but...
I guess I was wrong.
Sensei...
I don't care what happens to you,
but this leaves me with no choice.
Let's finish this game, Natsume.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Good morning, Taki.
Good morning... How are your eyes?
Sorry, they haven't healed yet.
I see...
You look pale.
Couldn't sleep?
You didn't spend the whole night walking around drawing circles, did you?
Don't worry.
I've decided to help you myself.
I... I want to hold him!
But now's not the time.
It's all my fault they got involved.
It'd be so wrong of me!
But...
What? Is this girl making eyes at me?
I want to cuddle him, rub my cheek against his, smell him, and take a nap with him!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Hold it in... Hold it in...!
And her spirit is unnatural....
He's just too adorable.
But...
I have to control myself!
Impressive, little lady.
Huh?
They became friends without me knowing.
I've heard rumors of an youkai that lives around here.
Apparently, a discarded broken mirror collected evil energy inside of itself and became a youkai.
It said it hated humans.
I've heard that these types of youkai gain pleasure from
causing youkai and humans to suffer and watching them afterwards.
What should we do?
Didn't I say not to worry?
An evil-sealing mirror!
Incredible!
What's happening to me?
Sensei suddenly looks reliable!
It must be because it got my eyes!
I got this from one of my drinking buddies as a favor.
How does it work?
A human just has to hold it and recite the sealing chant
while the youkai's eyes are reflected in the mirror.
So it'll be impossible unless we can see him?
Exactly.
We just have to lure him into one of my circles, right?
Then...
Use me as bait!
Taki!
I'm not sure about you, but Natsume would be a good choice.
His powers are strong, and he smells delicious.
Delicious?
So, does it look like I taste bad?
He probably realized that you're the Natsume with the Book of Friends when he touched you.
The Book of Friends is very attractive to bored youkai.
If Natsume wanders around here, I'm sure it'll draw him out.
You're special, after all.
Special?
What's the Book of Friends?
Sorry, I can't tell you the details.
It's a bit complicated.
Except, it's the one thing my grandmother left me.
Then it's a treasure to you, isn't it?
Yeah, that's right.
Sensei!
So you came to be eaten?
What's wrong?
He's close.
Don't touch me!
I've changed my mind.
The Book of Friends sounds more fun than any game.
Where?
Where is he?
I'm done with the girl.
Now...
Taki!
Natsume-kun!
It's him...
Wait there, Natsume-kun!
No, Taki!
It's dangerous!
Don't go!
Run, run!
Run as much as you want!
Wait! Stop!
Dammit...
This way!
I'm over here, youkai!
Taki, no!
Run!
Come here!
If you let me go, you'll regret it!
I know how to seal you!
Taki!
Why you little brat...
Don't get ahead of yourself.
I'll torture you to death.
You can't hide anymore.
So what if you can see me? You're a powerless little girl.
You said you would let me go if I caught you!
I have no intention of keeping my promise.
I can't... breathe...
Taki!
What will you do, friend?
Nothing will change whether you can see me or not.
Stop it!
Let her go!
Taki, I'm coming!
I'm coming for you now!
Reach!
Come on...
Come on!
Sensei?
O, being of shadow!
Find the light within quiet slumber!
Natsume-kun!
Taki... are you okay?
Yeah.
I see...
I'm glad.
Natsume-kun!
It's all right.
He'll be fine with some rest.
Oh... thank goodness...
The youkai's poison kept me in bed for a while, but I then realized that I could see them again.
Sensei's face, as he watched over me in his youkai form,
looked funny to me for some reason.
But I decided not to tell him.
When I couldn't see, I had thought just for a bit, that what I felt was loneliness.
But I won't tell him that either.
Morning, Natsume-kun.
Are you feeling better?
Yeah.
You look well too.
I'm glad you weren't hurt.
I can't...
I can't thank you enough.
Taki?
I might not be able to do much, but...
If you're ever in trouble, please let me know.
I'd like to help you.
You...
You called the Book of Friends a treasure.
That's more than enough.
You're the first person to say good things about my memories of my grandmother.
It made me happy.
Thank you, Taki.
You can just call me Natsume.
Good morning, Natsume!
Mustache!
Is Mustache here?
Yeah, he is...
Why is he here?
And why is this little bodyguard here?
Want to fight?
Let's go!
You mustached slug!
My days continue to be filled with noise.
Hey, is Mustache talking?
Yeah, he is.
They're arguing.
About what?
That manner of speech is incorrect!
It's a communicational mistake!
You obviously understand it!
Don't copy me!
I'm not!
That's what you call copying!
But, perhaps I'm the one straining to listen and understand the voices and words.
We'll be late. Let's go, Taki!
I'm mad! Mad!
Wait up!
Nishimura Attack!
That hurt!
Morning, Natsume!
Morning!
That's what you get!
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Eternal Feelings
I met a mermaid.
Looks like the hostess of the inn knows it too.
Keiichi-san was weak,
and I was so young.
"How frivolous I am," I thought to myself.
I could not understand the meaning of eternal life.