Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Sorry for dragging you along, Takashi-kun.
No, this is nothing.
Ever since I came here, it feels like I have only been the one receiving.
Will I be able to become someone who can do things for others?
What is it?
I just remembered I have something to do.
Sorry!
Takashi-kun?
It's hurt.
Hiiragi...
It got away.
Meeting of Sorcerers
It's a temperamental one.
It's been eating the youkai in this area.
It's been eating livestock recently too.
I had Hiiragi search for it so I could eliminate it, and so we happened to meet you two.
That bird youkai...
It was looking at me as if pleading for help.
Your powers are strong, so it may have sensed that and wanted your help.
Natsume, do you want to work on this job together?
You have power.
There are those who rely on it too.
Can you ignore them?
There's a meeting of sorcerers tomorrow evening.
Sorcerers?
There are a lot of youkai in this area,
so sometimes, sorcerers come together.
But only people who can feel or see them though.
Come if you're interested.
A meeting...
If I go,
will there be people like me?
Maybe if I'm with them,
I might be able to find something I can do.
I'll be back tomorrow afternoon,
but I'll be with Natori-san, so you don't need to worry.
After, tell me how the movie is, okay?
Okay.
Are we at the drinking hall yet?
It's a meeting.
Welcome, sir.
The entrance is this way.
I see.
People who can't see youkai won't be able to get there.
This area is pretty strange.
The Great Youkai used to rule these lands,
but it seems that most of them were hunted by humans.
Hunted?
Oh? Young man, what are you doing in this forest?
Are you heading to the meeting?
We are too!
Come! It's this way. Come with us.
Come on, it's this way.
Don't touch it.
If you're going to eat him, that cat on his shoulder won't keep quiet about it.
Young master Natori!
We didn't mean to try to eat him!
The underlings always try to cause mischief, so it's troubling.
Natori-san.
You just got out of that problem.
Hey, Hiiragi.
You're going to the meeting too?
Strip.
Take off your clothes now.
Sorry! I just...
W-Well then, show me your arm.
This charm is usually written on the heart.
If you're attacked, your left arm will probably remain.
Thanks.
Earless Houichi had his ear eaten,
but your entire body will be eaten.
It won't be.
You're with me.
Let's go.
Okay.
Are they all really...
So you can see almost all of the youkai.
I can't tell the difference between the humans and the youkai.
It's hard for me to believe even when I can see them,
so it's probably natural that people who can't think of me as being weird.
That's how people are.
That's she why hated them and youkai.
I wonder if there is someone here who shares the same pain as me?
Who's that kid? I haven't seen him before.
Is that Reiko-san? Natsume Reiko.
Was that a youkai's voice? Or a person's?
Natsume.
Do you want to put on a mask?
Everyone wants information, but there are those who don't want their identity known as well.
So it's okay to put on a fake mask.
Shouldn't you hide it too?
There are things you want to hide but can't.
Like my fabulousness.
Wouldn't they just think that you looked like Natori Shuuichi?
Nope.
Well, the Natori family have always been exorcists,
so we're famous even if we hide it.
Still, thank you for coming.
I want to find something I can do.
I see.
That mark is as creepy as ever.
Sensei!
I'm used to it now.
But, you know, this thing never goes on my left leg.
And that gives me a bad feeling.
Natori.
You said you'd bring a new acquaintance, so I've come to see him.
Nanase-san!
Is Matoba-san here too?
The chief went to have a look around the building,
and said he saw something interesting, so he already left.
Something interesting, huh?
Natori-san?
Ah, this is Nanase-san.
There is someone named Matoba who is a very powerful exorcist,
and she's something like his secretary.
Nanase-san, this is my friend Natsume-kun.
And this is Hiiragi, my new servant.
Natsume...
Do you happen to know Reiko? Natsume Reiko?
Do you know my grandmother?
Grandmother? You're her grandson?
No, I'm sorry. I don't actually know her well.
But she would sometimes come up in conversations between youkai.
They said she was very beautiful and very powerful.
I see.
Is she still well?
No, she died young.
Died? How?
I don't know the details.
Didn't you ever want to know?
I didn't think I could ask.
This whole time, not from anyone.
I see. Forgive me.
There wasn't anyone who has asked about my grandmother like this.
You don't have to fight by yourself anymore though.
Can I...
Can I really trust people now?
I heard, Natori. You're still chasing that youkai?
Yes.
There's money on the line too.
It's strong.
Even if it can't be eliminated, I'm sure it can be sealed.
Think of it as a farewell gift.
It's a pot for sealing evil.
Thank you.
Don't take too long.
Natsume Yuujinchou
I just can't like the Matoba family.
Is this meeting run by Matoba-san?
No, there are other sorcerer groups besides the Matoba family.
This is like a general meeting for all the groups.
I see.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm just surprised by everything.
So...
Your grandma could see youkai too.
Yeah.
Oh right, I haven't told Natori-san about my grandmother or the Book of Friends yet.
Should I tell him about the Book of Friends?
It's the one from yesterday.
A lot of people have had their servants eaten by it.
That's probably why there's prize money.
It may be natural for large things to eat small things,
but he pleaded to me for help.
Isn't there anything I can do?
Natori-san.
Can't you use the paper doll that you used to find me to look for it?
No. I don't know it's name, so it's probably impossible.
Wait...
Usually, you would write their name here,
but this place is full of energy,
and with all your power, it might just take off without a name.
I'm counting on you.
Place your hand over the magic circle.
Close your eyes, and imagine its face in your mind.
While doing so, order the paper doll to search for it.
Go!
Ah! It broke the glass!
Sorry, I forgot to open the window.
Still, it's hard to believe you did it successfully on your first try.
We won't be able to chase after it at that speed.
Did it fail?
No, it's inside this building.
It's attracted to humans with strong powers.
It may have come to eat them.
Hey! Wait!
I'll go on ahead.
Wait for me!
Where is it? Where did it go?
I have to protect them.
The people who share the same pain as me.
I have to!
Even I should be able to do that!
Oh, Natori! What is it?
Is that your new acquaintance?
Natsume.
Quiet.
Run!
Hiiragi!
What's going on?!
There it is...
Stop!
Hey! Are you okay?
Yeah.
How's Hiiragi?
She's okay. Her wounds are shallow.
Sensei!
Fine, I'll chase him, you idiot.
What a huge servant.
Just who is that child?
I can't believe he exorcised it with one punch.
Don't chase it! You'll be eaten!
All right, the magic circle is complete.
Just do what I told you.
Yes.
Here it comes.
Okay, let's do it.
Calm down.
Come forth. I seek your hands.
Seize it, defender of darkness!
The lid!
Oh, right!
It's over...
I didn't think we'd get him right away.
You idiots! What would you do if I got sucked in too?!
Thanks, Natsume.
You were a huge help.
I'm happy that even I was able to help.
Don't demean yourself.
You're very powerful.
Natsume, I don't know why you're in such a rush,
but humans do not become stronger if they're reckless.
You must know yourself first.
Know myself...
Okay. Thank you.
Ah, well done!
Nanase-san!
I'm sorry, but I'll be taking this.
What's going on?
We've been wanting a strong servant,
so we've had our eyes on this youkai for a while.
We used a crow we didn't need anymore as bait, but it got away.
We were thinking of giving up.
Crow? That crow?
You used a youkai... your bird servant as bait?!
Boy, that kindness will cost you your life.
You must not let youkai into your heart.
They are evil, unlike humans.
We used a monster meant for extermination for the sake of the people so that no harm may come to them.
What is wrong with that?
Come to the mansion another day.
We'll reward you then.
I thought if I met people who could see youkai, that we would understand our pains and suffering.
And I thought it would be wonderful, but...
But people who are like me are dangerous to me!
That's right, maybe they shouldn't know about the Book of Friends...
That woman probably won't be able to use it.
The seal you wrote on that pot won't be released so easily.
Come on, let's go back.
Yeah.
Thanks, I was saved thanks to you.
Forgive my blunders earlier.
You did well.
I'm just glad you're okay.
We get 50/50 on that reward!
Sensei!
I know.
See you again.
Yeah.
All right, on to the next job.
I'm sorry that I can't let you rest.
Is it a job request from the Matoba family?
No, not exactly, but it's another tough one.
Let's go.
Ah, yeah.
I've been running away from youkai, and probably people too.
I should learn about them.
About myself and Reiko.
And I want to become strong.
At least enough to protect those close to me and those I meet.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Boy from the Empty House
I met a young boy named Kai.
He was being chased by someone dangerous.
There you go, sticking your nose into something dangerous again.
Look at you, you're hurt!
All because Natsume saved me...
I have to protect him from now on!