Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Come on, just go!
What's going on?
We just need you to come.
So where are we going?
Just come!
Yeah, just come.
All right, here we are.
Here?
I've been waiting for you, Natsume-kun.
Sorry, we couldn't refuse our class rep's order.
Well then, come on in!
So that's how it is?
Right, so let's go in.
The Boy From The Empty House
They say there are mysterious sounds every night,
and that you can hear strange voices.
Can you feel anything?
No, it's not like I can sense them.
No matter how many times you deny it,
I still believe that you have a special power!
You may not like it,
but I think it's a wonderful power.
I think you should be proud of it.
By the way, where are Nishimura and Kitamoto?
They probably went home.
Went home?
We can forget about the people who don't believe.
I see!
This place does look like it would have ghosts.
You...
Taki?
This looks interesting.
I'll join you two.
Okay, Sasada-san, let's go look over there.
You look over there, Natsume-kun.
W-Wait!
Come on, let's go!
I want to go with Natsume...
That Taki girl is pretty attentive.
Sensei?
Come on, let's get away from here.
It's better if we don't stay here too long.
What do you mean?
Is there really something here?
Yeah.
Come, before it senses us...
Hey, where are you going?
Taki and Sasada are in danger then.
I'll go call them back.
Geez, what a guy.
Open up!
Was that a kid's voice?
Wait! It might not be a person!
Ah geez!
A coffin?
Open up!
Let me out!
Open!
He's inside?
Hold on, I'll open it up now.
Wait, Natsume!
Are you okay?
That was a great uppercut.
Why was that kid inside of it?
He didn't smell like a youkai.
Was he playing hide and seek or something?
The lid must have gotten locked, and he couldn't get out.
Is something wrong?
We heard some voices.
Ah, no, it's nothing.
What about you?
Unfortunately, nothing.
There he is! Kitty!
I wanted to see you!
No way, she's got bad taste.
Ah, your nose...
Kai?
Ishio Kai?
The guy in class 3.
You know, the one saying he's being chased by something weird.
Oh, him?
He said it might be a ghost or something.
He probably said it because his parents come home late.
Is he being bullied?
No way, he's got a lot of friends for some reason.
Later!
Bye, bye.
Yeah, thanks!
Nyanko-sensei!
Is it you?
You locked me inside the box, didn't you?
No, it wasn't me.
It wasn't me!
I just came to give you back something you dropped.
Is he the one?
The one chasing you?
Get lost!
Hey, stop!
Look!
He even brought a really ugly cat!
How lame!
Ugly?
Get lost, sprout!
Chopping board!
Hackberry!
Girly boy!
Get lost!
We should leave for now, Natsume.
It went on his shoulder!
Wow...
He's running!
Don't come back again!
Yeah!
He wasn't much.
That was easy!
Hey, you okay, Kai?
Geez...
I don't think I like kids.
[ Signs: sprout, chopping board, hackberry, girly boy ]
I think I took more damage than when I meet youkai.
What a depressing guy.
Ah, damn. I forgot to give it to him.
The name tag?
Hey, Sensei, could you give it to him?
I'll give you 200 yen.
What?
You'll only give 200 yen to someone as high level as me?!
Give me the paper! Give me 10,000 yen!
He's being chased by a ghost.
Can he see youkai too?
Tanuma.
Hey.
A kid that can see youkai?
He didn't seem like he was being bullied though.
I was glad.
Natsume...
I'll eat that kid...
I'll eat him if he breaks the promise.
Is something there?
It ran.
Was it a youkai?
Who's the kid it mentioned?
Natsume-kun?
Ah, Taki.
What are you doing here?
Ah, just now...
Oh right, this is the first time you've met Tanuma.
She's from class 5-
Let's talk about that later and get away from this place first.
This place was mentioned in a book at my house.
It supposedly attracts youkai.
Attracts youkai?
Hey, you're bleeding!
When did I get this?
Must've been that thing.
The youkai will gather because of the scent of blood.
Come on, let's go!
You too!
Y-Yeah.
Your ancestors were onmyouji?
So that's why?
Yeah.
Okay, that should do.
Thanks.
Must be a fierce youkai.
Yeah.
You must not let youkai into your heart.
They are evil, unlike humans.
Can that Kai kid really see youkai?
I'm not sure.
But if that's the case...
You want to protect him?
You're kind.
No, that's not it.
When I think I can't leave someone alone, I just act.
It might just be arrogance.
Natsume-kun...
In the end, I think I was just looking for trouble.
I would use to blame it on youkai though.
Natsume Yuujinchou
Kai!
A youkai?
L-Lost property?
Nice, Nyanko-sensei!
I'll pay you when we get home.
Ah, I can't hold it in!
You again?
She's got bad taste...
Kai.
You followed me?
It really isn't you?
The one who chased after me and locked me up in that box.
Yeah, it's not me.
I see...
Sorry about earlier.
Well...
About calling you a sprout, chopping board, and girly boy...
Ah, w-well, i-it's okay...
It's not funny!
Right.
Well, I apologized, so...
Wait.
Shouldn't you report the guy chasing after you to the police?
It's okay!
There's no point in telling them anyway.
It's not pointless.
I apologized already, so just leave me alone!
Hey, are you hurt?
What's it to you?
Don't be so stubborn!
It'll be too late if something bad happens!
Natsume-kun...
Sorry for yelling...
Doesn't look like it's broken.
I'm sure the pain will go away in a while.
Get on.
No.
I made a kid cry.
How can I tell him I'm worried?
I'd be more open if it was a youkai.
I didn't want to cause you trouble.
When I saw you, your hand was hurt.
Since you helped me, I thought you might've been attacked by the thing chasing me.
So I thought I had to protect you this time.
So that's why you followed me?
Thanks.
L-Later.
His family hasn't come home yet.
So he's alone.
That's the first time someone's told me that they had to protect me.
Hold on a minute. What am I then?
Ah, I forgot.
You're my bodyguard.
Don't forget! It's nothing to laugh at!
Lowly little thing.
If it's following me, then it's not after Kai?
Is it after Kai?
I'm not sure, but it said it'd eat a kid.
There are many youkai that eat kids.
You're thinking too much.
It's just nonsense.
It may be lowly, but it got me earlier.
What?
Without me knowing?
It's nothing though.
You idiot!
I'd be overjoyed to see you eaten and to get the Book of Friends for myself,
but I don't want that lowly thing to hurt my stuff!
It's really vexing! Do you understand, Natsume?
Do you understand how vexing it is?
Right.
Vexing!
So if Kai can't see youkai, and if a youkai isn't after him,
then who locked Kai in that coffin?
Natsume-kun!
What are you looking at?
No, nothing.
Huh? That kid...
How cute.
Is he waiting for someone?
Kai?
I want to protect him.
Ever since, I'd spend time together with Kai almost everyday after school.
Taki taught me.
Kai?
Now we all match.
Kai.
What, Natsume?
Could you tell me about it now?
About the box?
Yeah.
It's okay if you don't want to.
Not too long ago, I felt that someone was looking at me.
And then there was someone by the telephone pole.
I thought it was just some weirdo, so I didn't worry about it much.
No, you should worry about that.
That day, he was chasing me,
so I ran to that house.
I went into that box to hide and...
You couldn't get out?
It got locked.
Locked?
There wasn't a lock then...
Watch out!
What? What's going on?
Taki can't see it.
But...
You can see it?
So you can see it too?
Taki! There's a youkai in front of you!
I'm going to take Kai and run!
Don't follow us!
Natsume-kun!
Don't come!
That's right!
You okay?
Is it still there?
I don't know.
This place...
Damn, it lured us here!
Run away, Kai!
Natsume!
Nyanko-sensei!
Let go! Let me go!
It got away!
I let him go.
It was getting obstinate about eating you,
and I'm a gourmet, you see.
I drained a lot of its power, so it won't come back to attack anymore.
How'd you know I was here?
Taki came by looking worried and told me.
Just when are you going to learn?
Taki did?
I see.
Thanks, Sensei.
You saved me.
Not the nose! It tickles!
Wow...
Amazing!
The youkai obeys you.
He's not.
He helped us.
Natsume-kun! Kai-kun!
Taki!
Thank goodness you're safe!
Yeah, thanks to Sensei.
Kitty!
H-Hey, that's enough!
Thanks!
Kai could see the youkai.
So the one following him was that one?
What's this feeling?
It doesn't feel like it's over.
Natsume!
He locked Kai in the coffin!
N-Natori-san?
Geez, I tried not to get you involved this time,
but you came barging in yourself.
So you locked him in the coffin?
I didn't lock him.
I sealed him.
It's best if you don't get close to him.
What do you mean?
What's going on?
Natsume...
He's...
a youkai.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Humans
and Youkai
Kai is a youkai?
I came to exterminate him.
What are you saying he did?
Did he do something to deserve extermination?
Natsume, how about you decide now?
What's more important to you? People or youkai?