Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Oh no, oh no...
They're tiny.
Oh no, we can't pass through now.
Oh no, we can't proceed now.
They could just go around it.
Oh! There's a road now!
We're saved!
Let's go! Let's go!
They really are tiny.
That shrine's about the size of an urn for ashes.
Now, we must quickly deliver this to where our lord's body is located.
We must deliver!
Youkai Extermination Amid The Steamy Road
What's that?
There's paper in the doorway.
Paper dolls?
You're back, Natsume?
Nyanko-sensei.
Where'd you go?
On patrol.
I'm looking for youkai who would lure and eat you.
What's that?
I'm not sure. They were in between the doorway.
Hey!
Natsume! Natsume!
W-What's going on?
It's pulling me so hard!
Oh? Natsume-kun?
Natori-san?
It's been a while.
I placed a spell on the paper dolls and put them in the doorway
to inform me when you returned.
You're pretty slow minded.
You got caught in it?
You did this?
Natori-san exorcises youkai as a side job.
Well, no sense in talking out here.
But to the public...
Hey, look at him.
No way! Don't tell me...
Natori Shuuichi...
Why don't we go have a cup of tea?
He's Natori Shuuichi, a popular actor.
The truth is, it's kind of annoying.
Will you be free during the upcoming holidays?
No.
Do you like hot springs?
Who knows?
Would you like to go to a hot spring inn with me?
I won a pair of tickets for the hot springs from a cologne that I bought.
Cologne?
Why are you asking me anyway?
Why not invite a girl instead?
My agency doesn't let me.
He's a shady guy as always.
Do you want me to eat him, Natsume?
You must have some male friends.
No, you're the only friend I have who can see the same scenery that I do.
I've never gone on a vacation before.
Oh yeah, the inn allows pets too.
What?!
Let's go, Natsume!
Eggs! Eggs! Hot spring eggs!
Natsume!
I'll talk to your guardians for you.
Oh, a vacation?
That's wonderful!
I'll take good care of Natsume-kun.
My, what beautiful flowers.
I guess I don't have to worry if you have such a responsible friend.
Really?
I'll come for him tomorrow.
Takashi-kun is always reserved, so it kind of makes me happy.
Go and have fun, okay?
I-I'll buy some souvenirs.
And so began our two day, one night hot springs trip for two and one pet.
It's pretty deep in the mountains, huh?
It's perfect for traveling incognito.
It's not much of a secret with all the trains and buses that we rode on.
I'm hungry, so get going, you slowpokes.
Are you tired?
Yeah.
I'm glad it's a clear day though.
Yeah, you're right.
Thank you for coming all this way.
I'm going to go make a call.
I forgot to tell my manager about our trip.
I'll take you to your room.
Ah, okay.
I'm tired, but this feels great.
It's nice to get out once in a while.
The closet?
What was that sound?
Sorry for the wait, Natsume.
No one seems to be here now, so let's go to the hot springs.
Yeah.
Let's go, sensei.
Huh? He's gone.
This is heavenly.
Hey, why is the cat the first one in the hot spring?
I told you I'm not a cat!
Then what are you? A cat pig?!
W-What do you mean by cat pig?!
For someone as noble as myself, what do you think I am?
A cat.
What?!
Hey, hey, don't fight.
Don't dirty the water, sensei.
I'm made out of clay, so that won't happen.
Does it feel good?
Yeah.
That's great.
Others can't see Natori-san's newt-shaped mark.
I don't know if I should look at it.
I don't like youkai, but Natori-san...
He probably hates them.
What's wrong, Natsume?
Spent too much time in the bath?
What are you, a school girl?
Teenagers are sensitive, you know.
Plus, anybody would be scared if things show up out of nowhere.
Hiiragi, I told you not to scare Natsume.
I'm sorry, I forgot how weak he is.
Hiiragi is one of the youkai that Natori-san employs.
I'm sorry.
You'll catch a cold if you don't dry off.
You don't need to worry about her, Natsume.
Youkai don't catch colds.
Oh, I see.
That's good.
You didn't drink milk because you wanted beer?
Beer is great.
We could've enjoyed having some together if you were older.
Oh yeah...
What's wrong?
T-There's something hanging from the ceiling over there...
It's gone.
Did you see something?
Ah, no.
I guess it was my imagination.
I'll take a look around the inn.
It gets cold after a bath, so you can go wait in the room.
Ah, but...
It's okay. I'll be back right away.
Let's go, Hiiragi.
Yes.
I guess I shouldn't have said anything.
He invited me here for a vacation.
Natsume, you should keep an eye on the Book of Friends.
Yeah, it's right here.
Now that I think about it, I haven't told Natori-san about it yet.
Don't.
He'll take it.
He may seem the type, but he wouldn't do that.
Maybe, but I know how you are.
"He's probably nice to me because he's after the book,"
is probably what you'd start thinking.
Well, that would be a problem.
You're so negative.
Is there a rat in this closet or something?
Nothing's in it.
There's a pot.
A pot?
In the closet?
Yeah, it has a lid too.
Look, there's a piece of paper with some writing on the lid.
Kind of gives off a bad feeling.
Oh yeah, it was right about here.
The place where you saw a person's body hanging.
A head would fit perfectly into this pot.
Let's pretend we didn't see it.
Aren't you going to open it?
What a bore.
Who knows? There might be some delicious pickled leeks in it.
Your lures won't work on me.
What's this I hear about pickled leeks?
Natori-san.
I'm back.
Did something happen?
No.
I see.
All right, let's have dinner then.
I'll order some sashimi for the cat too.
Really?!
There is something I'm curious about though.
So far, though, all I've heard were sounds and there's no real harm.
You brought me along on a fun trip,
so I didn't want to tell you and ruin it.
You're right.
Let's try to forget about youkai, just for today.
Yeah.
Okay, let's eat!
Natsume Yuujinchou
I'm tired.
And sleepy.
Are things going well with your current guardians?
Yes.
They're very kind to me.
I see.
Yeah.
But if you get tired of telling lies,
you can come to me.
Lies?
We may be able to get along without lying.
Liar...
When I was small, I would always be called a liar because I could see youkai.
I've been dreaming of those times a lot lately.
I wasn't lying either.
I wasn't...
Liar.
Are you okay?
You were having a nightmare.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
How embarrassing.
I can't believe I cried because of a dream.
"Liar," huh?
The pot's lid came off?
Sensei! Natori-san!
The pot opened.
Pot?
The one with the leeks?
It probably doesn't have leeks.
It would sometimes make sounds,
but the lid just came off now.
In the closet?
You could tell the lid opened without even looking?
I felt a bad presence flow out.
All right.
So it was here.
It's empty.
Or what was inside got away.
I'll go have a look downstairs.
Let's go, sensei!
Roger!
That pot had quite a powerful seal on it,
so I didn't think there was anything to worry about.
But it broke the seal itself, so it must be really strong.
Plus, that seal is still new.
New?
Well, let's go.
Yeah.
It's bleeding.
Ah, it really is a powerful one.
Can I eat it, Natsume?
Natsume?
The owner of the Book of Friends?!
I beg you! Please return my name!
My name is Sumie.
I have lived on this land for a long time,
but humans came and said I was a hindrance.
So they sealed me in a pot.
I hate humans.
Please return my name.
I will no longer have to dwell with humans anymore.
If you return my name, I will leave, and disappear into the mountains.
Please!
Do you promise not to trouble the people of this inn?
If you won't, I can command you to leave using the power of the Book of Friends.
I will leave even if you do not command me, Natsume-sama.
I see.
I'm sorry to have taken your name for so long.
Natsume-
I have nothing to fear now.
Unlike Reiko, you're soft.
At the very least, I'll swallow you in one bite so that it won't hurt.
Natsume!
Natori-san!
They got away?
No matter. It's been a while since I've had a meal.
I won't let them escape this inn.
Over here!
Let's go to the room at the end of the hall.
Damn it! I was too naive!
I want to understand youkai, so why do I...
Hey, Natori boy, why don't you spill it?
What are you planning?
You shouldn't underestimate me.
Planning?
Hiiragi?
What's with this room?
I prepared it after our bath.
There's a youkai that wants to harm humans at the back of this inn.
Another exorcist had sealed it, but...
Another exorcist?
However, the youkai took refuge in this inn before he could completely seal it.
That's why I came here.
So...!
So you lied and invited Natsume, even though you know he hates exorcising youkai,
to help you seal it.
That's right. I'm sorry.
Deceiving people has become a habit of mine.
If I knew you'd enjoy it so much, then I should've explained it all.
I'm sorry, Natsume.
It's okay. There are things I haven't told you either.
So it seems.
Natori-san and I have gotten used to lying without even knowing it.
I'll help you.
This happened because I was too naive.
Thank you.
We'll seal the youkai with a barrier around the entire room.
Go outside, Hiiragi.
You too, sensei.
How boring!
I'll eat you.
He's in this room?
I'll eat you!
I'll eat all of you damn humans!
I can't move!
Just kidding.
She slipped out!
Natori-san!
I will not allow you to harm Natsume-dono!
Who is this youkai?
I've been looking for you, Natsume-dono.
Have you forgotten?
You built a bridge for me.
Three eyes?
The youkai from back then?
I shall purify her.
Since when did you know that huge youkai?
I just helped him a bit.
I guess there are honorable youkai too.
There you go getting involved with them thoughtlessly again.
Because...
Because I can see them.
They cry, get in trouble,
betray, and repay favors.
My master...
My master simply came to see if the youkai had been sealed.
It was a rare chance, so he probably wanted to talk to you too.
Yeah, there's a lot of things I want to talk about too.
There are so many things I want to say to Natori-san and the Fujiwara couple,
but the words just won't come out.
I'm scared of them knowing.
I'm used to being scared,
but one day, I'll tell them.
To the people who I want to show my true self to.
Sorry for the wait.
Sorry for getting you involved again.
No, it was really fun.
Will you come by when you visit again?
Yeah, of course.
Come on, let's go home.
Yeah.
And so my first hot springs trip ended.
Feeling a bit uneasy, I headed home,
carrying many fun memories and things to talk about.
Where should I start first?
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
A Chick Hatches
There was an egg left in a bird's nest in the yard.
Take care of it, sensei. You're free, right?
What? You want me to keep it warm?
Ah, it got bigger!
I-It hatched!
I'll be taking that Tatsumi chick, boy.