Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora ni egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
Natsume Yuujinchou
Your fingertips were slightly dyedan adult's color
Your fingertips were slightly dyed an adult's color
sukoshi dake otona no iro ni somaru yubisaki
Natsume Yuujinchou
Embarrassed, you hid them
terakusa sou ni sotto kakushite
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
hoozuetsuita kimi mitsumeteru shisen no saki ni
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
chiisana tsubomi ga yura yura
Hey, even now we're always lost,
nee bokura nante ima mo mayoi bakari de
and I remember the words I said that day
ano hi okutta kotoba imasara omoidasu
"I'd paint the future with the color of you"
kimi iro ni mirai somete
Face forward and run
hashiridase mae muite
I painted the lights in the sky
kajikamu te de sora egaita
with these numb hands to brighten your future
kimi no mirai ni shukufuku no akari tomosu
Cut through it with your hands
kirihirake sono te de
Can you hear my voice?
kikoeteru kai kono koe ga?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
sunao ni waraeru koto dakishimete hashiridase
What? It's snowboarding, I tell you! Snowboarding!
What are you talking about?
Riding on a train and gazing at snow-covered mountains is the best!
The sky's so high.
You sound like an old man.
What about you, Natsume?
Sorry, what?
Are you okay?
You don't look too well.
Do you have a fever or something?
I'm okay.
I guess I haven't been getting enough sleep.
Really? Be careful then.
What is it?
Over there.
Is something there?
What's with him?
How scary!
If those two couldn't see him, then...
He's a youkai?
The Promised Tree
This jelly from Nanatsuji is pretty good.
I should've tried it sooner.
Slides right down the throat.
So how was it?
A little over 37 degrees.
You should rest then.
I took some medicine.
I should be fine if I don't do much.
I don't want to worry Touko-san.
Geez, how long will it take for you to realize?
Realize what?
Nothing.
By the way, someone has been peeping at us the entire time.
Peeping?
I saw him earlier.
He's clumsy.
I'll ask you once more.
Why are you following me?
Is it the Book of Friends?
Maybe he doesn't understand human words?
That's not possible.
We won't know what you want if you stay quiet.
Say something!
O-Okay. I'm sorry.
So?
Don't you remember me?
I'm not Reiko-san.
You're not?
She died a long time ago.
Looks like he's gone stiff due to shock.
What a troublesome kid.
I see.
So you're Natsume Reiko-san's grandchild?
Yeah.
He's an introvert, but he's got some power.
You didn't need to add introvert.
That's great.
All right, I'll return your name now.
One who protects me,
show your name.
What's going on?
His page doesn't exist.
Then he didn't form a contract?
Excuse me...
No, the Book of Friends reacted to him.
He does have a contract.
Was it lost then?
Excuse me...
Knowing Reiko, that's a possibility.
Excuse me, I don't think mine is there.
It's probably in another place.
Another place?
Tell us that earlier!
She tied it on a tree branch?
Yes.
She said she'd give it back after 50 years.
Why'd Reiko-san do that?
That's just like her.
Still, you actually waited for 50 years.
You're really stupid and gullible.
I'm sorry, Nyanko-sensei-san.
Don't call me that, it gives me the creeps!
You don't need to add san.
I'm sorry.
Call me Great-sensei.
Natsume?
Didn't you think of doing something about it?
Reiko-san said that if I took it back too early,
the seas would rage and the world would be destroyed.
Basically, she played a prank on you.
Well, seeing how he is, I kind of understand Reiko's feelings.
I'm sorry.
So, where's the tree your contract was tied to?
Well, it should be around here.
Should be?
I get worried if I see it, so I've stayed away.
Does that mean...
Like I said, I've stayed away for 50 years.
50 years...
You left it alone for 50 years?
I'm sorry.
After 50 years,
the tree would have grown.
The branch it's on must be pretty high up now.
I'm not going to look for it.
But I need it!
Still, just how many trees are there in this forest?
But...
Just give up, then.
You're okay, so that means the contract is okay too.
It'll be safe even if you leave it alone from now on.
So just give up.
All right, I'll give up.
That's good!
Okay, let's go back and eat jelly!
So you're going to give up?
Well...
Let's look for it a bit more.
You may remember a hint after searching for a bit.
Okay?
Natsume-san...
Geez, just how good of a person are you?
I'm not going to help.
Tanuma?
Ah, are you looking for something?
Sorry.
It's okay.
Maybe it is impossible.
Kirinoha, we just started looking for it.
If only I could see them too.
He's a pretty good looking boy.
I see.
I'm glad it wasn't a girl.
It would've upset me.
Oh right, speaking of girls...
Hey, you two!
Look around the place more!
We're already doing what you asked us to!
But there's no point in searching the same place!
Then you shouldn't be searching the same place either!
I thought the more the better.
Stop staying in one place and spread out! Class rep's orders!
Maybe they're too annoying?
No, thanks though.
It probably doesn't even occur to them that they're looking for something that belongs to a youkai.
Sasada!
You found it?!
I found a beehive!
Be serious and look for it!
What is it?
Well, everyone is...
Does it surprise you that they're helping?
I had heard that humans acted coldly amongst themselves.
From who?
Natsume Reiko-san.
Oh, there you are!
Hinoe?
I've heard it all.
This ugly little thing asked me to help out.
What?!
These idiots are doing idiotic things,
so I just told you to be an idiot with them.
Thanks.
Don't thank me so sincerely!
Gives me the creeps!
So!
You're the one that Reiko cast a curse on?
Rather than a curse...
You practically were cursed!
Don't tease him so much.
I'll let you look around this area.
Huh?
Natsume?
What's wrong, Natsume?
Natsume!
We'll be leaving now.
Sorry for making you worry.
Well, we didn't see that he was feeling sick.
Thanks.
His condition has improved though,
and he drank medicine, so he should be fine if he rests.
I'm going to have him take school off tomorrow though.
Okay, I'll let the teacher know.
He should've told us.
Yeah.
Natsume Yuujinchou
That's what you get for pushing yourself, you idiot.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault.
I made you all look for something you'll never find.
Natsume-san shouldn't have suggested that we look for it.
Try saying it once more.
Who do you think Natsume is doing all this for?
Well for me...
That's not what I mean.
I'm telling you to try to understand Natsume's feelings a bit.
Don't say things that'll make his efforts look meaningless.
Say it again and this won't be all you'll get.
He's not good at getting along with others around him,
yet when the time comes, he pushes himself.
He's just like Reiko.
What a boring day.
Excuse me.
Um, I seem to be lost.
Could you tell me how to get out of the forest?
A human?
I can't believe she can see me.
This'll be fun.
Come, I'll show you the way.
Thanks, you're a real help.
If it was a boy, I'd push him into a swamp,
but this girl is quite beautiful.
I'll leave her deep in the forest and make her cry.
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Why's a girl like you in this forest anyway?
Well, I beat up these three boys,
and then I thought I'd hide in the forest until things cooled down.
Three boys?
I don't want to cause trouble for the family I'm staying with.
Dealing with people is very troublesome. I hate them.
So you like ghosts and youkai?
I hate scary things.
I thought so.
There aren't any humans that like youkai.
Aren't we near the exit yet?
We've got a long way to go.
By the way, you're dressed pretty well for being in the forest.
Are you possibly...
S-She's playing with me?
How impudent!
I should just eat her now, and then...!
That's right, I'm a...!
Ah, watch out.
Go away!
Why are they attacking you?
They're always after my hairpin!
I told you it's important to me!
They got it...
Is it that important?
What's she doing?
What are you doing?
Don't be reckless!
Why'd she do that?
I found it!
Hey!
You're a youkai, right?
If you want this back, lead me out of this forest.
Okay?
What a mean, mean, mean, mean girl...
I fall for her everytime I think of it.
I asked her so many times why she fell for her, and I still don't know the reason.
An ugly cat wouldn't understand.
Who's an ugly cat?!
Reiko-san did that?
Oh, you were awake?
She dove into the lake to get the hairpin?
Yeah, reckless, wasn't she?
By the way, Kirinoha, you said that Reiko threatened that if you were to take the paper she tied,
the seas would rage and the world would be destroyed, right?
Yes.
Why would she mention the sea when you live in the forest?
Probably because I said I wanted to see the sea.
The sea?
Yes.
Ever since I was born, I've only known the forest.
But I heard about it from a migrating bird,
and it said that the sea was wonderful.
So what did Reiko say?
"You should just go if you want to see it."
It's a bit far, but you could've went to see one.
I can't leave the forest.
Why?
Those born in the forest shouldn't leave.
I'd understand if there was a barrier up,
but I've never heard before that those born in a forest shouldn't leave.
A-Anyway, I can't.
So you don't know what a sea is?
Well, Reiko-san told me.
She did?
Yes.
It's blue, and infinitely vast.
There would always be waves, and the moonlight and sunlight would sparkle.
A long necked dinosaur lives in it.
There's an island that is its hideout,
and if you're lucky, you can see a UFO taking off..
It sounds so amazing.
It certainly is amazing, from the middle part onwards.
I can just imagine Reiko's face while she made all that up.
So she did trick me.
So then she got your name and put it on a branch.
Still, she didn't take the names of youkai who did the things she told them to.
She really must've wanted to play a prank on him.
How mean...
You think so?
Do you think she was mean?
Let's look for it again once my fever subsides.
I'm sure we'll find out what Reiko's motives were once we find the paper with your name.
Natsume-san...
That's good.
Your fever has gone down.
I don't want you to push yourself, Takashi-kun.
Okay. I'm sorry I made you worry.
I'll be going shopping, so make sure you rest.
Okay.
Are you going out?
Take care.
Hinoe found it?
Yes!
She also told us to take you all to the forest.
Don't go.
I see.
All right, let's go, Kirinoha.
Like I said!
Touko told you to rest!
The contract's up there.
Thanks.
I don't care what happens!
Kirinoha, you climb up and get it.
M-Me?
I can't climb a tree this big.
If you want to have your contract ruined, you can just ask the boorish Hinoe here.
What'd you say?!
Try saying that again, Madara!
You ugly, fat cat!
Go on.
You don't have to say it again!
Hey, stop blowing smoke at me.
Keep on going.
There it is! I found it!
You found it?
Wow, it's sparkling.
That's...!
The sea.
I see!
I can see the sea!
50 years is nothing to an youkai.
Reiko knew that and made this promise.
Reiko wasn't much of a romanticist...
Ow.
Reiko-san...
Reiko...
Thank you.
Kirinoha, I return your name.
Take it.
It's kind of sad that nothing remains.
Something does remain though.
The things you see, the things you feel...
Those will never disappear.
You'll never forget them...
I'm back!
I-It's Touko-san!
How are you feeling, Takashi-kun?
...along with many meetings.
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I want you to listen a little longer
mou sukoshi dake kiiteite hoshii
Hey, just a little longer
ne mou sukoshi dake
I just want to be selfish a little longer
mou sukoshi dake wagamama ii desuka
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed to disappear
te ni ireta totan ni kieteshimai sou
So could you say something?
kotoba wo kuremasenka?
With just you here,
anata ga iru sore dake demo
the world changed
sekai ga kawatteshimau
Look at the monotonous scenery,
monotone no keshiki ga hora
it looks so vivid
azayaka ni utsuru
We were walking with our hands held,
itsunomanika hanareteita
and before we knew it, we were separated
te wo tsunaide aruiteku
"I wonder we're a good match?"
umaku wa aeseteiru ka na?
was what I asked the sky
ano sora ni kiite miru no
Next
Time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
The Girl's Circle
I found a strange circle in Nohara.
It's a circle to communicate with aliens.
Ah, you there!
Natsume-kun?
Oh no, I just said your name!
Oh, you're...
I'm Taki Tooru from Class 5!